<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2108-03-14

                     CAMPBELL EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

VALDEZ,HARLAN,JR.   845-41-54-4                VISIT DATE: 03/14/08

The patient was seen and examined in the emergency department.  The 

patient was seen by the Emergency Medicine resident.  I have 

discussed the management with the resident.  I have also seen the 

patient primarily and reviewed the medical record.  This is a brief 

addendum to the medical record.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Briefly, this is a 45-year-old 

male who complains of several days of nausea, vomiting, and left 

lower quadrant discomfort.  He also describes intermittent chest 

pain, which he has had for a number of months without significant 

change.  He was sent in from his primary care doctor today with 

this pain and was also noted to have some EKG changes.  The patient 

has no chest pain at the time of evaluation in the emergency 

department and no shortness of breath.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As indicated and otherwise negative.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As indicated in the chart.

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  As indicated in the chart.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On physical examination, the patient is very 

well-appearing, a smiling, very pleasant gentleman in no acute 

distress.  The blood pressure is 119/90, the pulse 82, and the 

temperature 97.9 degrees.  Normocephalic and atraumatic.  The chest 

is clear to auscultation.  The heart has a regular rate and rhythm. 

The abdomen is soft.  He has left lower quadrant tenderness.  He 

also, of note on cardiovascular examination, has a soft murmur 

which he says he has had since childhood.  The extremities are 

normal.  The neurologic examination is non-focal. 

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  This is a gentleman with abdominal 

pain who will receive a CAT scan to rule out diverticulitis.  He 

has also had some non-specific ST changes on his EKG.  He is 

pain-free at this time.  He does not describe a classic exertional 

pattern for his chest pain, but given that he is a diabetic and 

with EKG changes, he will also be admitted for rule out MI.  A CT 

is pending at the time of this dictation.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  As above.  The 

patient's condition is currently stable. 

___________________________________                    CK498/89095 

JAY CARROLL, M.D.  JC72                                 D:03/14/08 

                                                       T:03/14/08 

Dictated by:  JAY CARROLL, M.D.  JC72 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2108-03-14" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="57" text="CAMPBELL" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="83" end="100" text="VALDEZ,HARLAN,JR." TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="103" end="114" text="845-41-54-4" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="142" end="150" text="03/14/08" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="509" end="511" text="45" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<ID id="P6" start="2337" end="2348" text="CK498/89095" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="2351" end="2362" text="JAY CARROLL" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="2370" end="2374" text="JC72" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2409" end="2417" text="03/14/08" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2477" end="2485" text="03/14/08" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2502" end="2513" text="JAY CARROLL" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2521" end="2525" text="JC72" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>