<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2120-09-19

Personal Data and Overall Health	

Patient is a 81 yr. old male who presents to Dr. Yager for multiple tooth extractions on 10/01/20.



History of Present Illness	

The patient complains of a hx. of tooth abscesses.



Past Surgical History	

Prior surgery includes:  

1.) excision l. neck mass for post l. neck lipoma 6/27/16- under local, no complications

2.) bowel surgery 15 yrs ago- g.a.- no complications

3.) hernia repair- 20 yrs ago- GA. no complications

4.) appendectomy-40 yrs ago- GA- no complications

5.) hemorroids- 2062-per patient done under spinal- had severe post spinal headache.



Family History	

There in no family history of adverse reactions to general anesthesia.



Past Medical History	

Current medical problems include:  

1.) HTN

2.) DMx20yrs- per patient glucose levels run 125-150 range

3.) hx. of tooth abscesses

4.) hypercholesterolemia







Social History	

Smoking: no

Alcohol use: no history of excessive use

Substance abuse: none



Review of Systems	

Medications:

insulin- 5 R/25N in am, 15 R in evening

hctz-25mg qd

captopril 25mg 2x/day

lipitor 10mgqd

zyrtec prn

ecasa

vit e

Allergies: shellfish



Cardiovascular: history of hypertension, no MI; denies CP, DOE, syncope, ankle edema

Respiratory: no history of asthma or chronic lung disease; denies unusual shortness of breath

Neurological: no history of neurological problems

Gastrointestinal: no history of PUD; denies reflux

Hepatobiliary: no history of liver disease; denies jaundice or hepatitis

Renal/Genitourinary: no history of renal failure; denies hematuria, dysuria, obstructive uropathy

Musculoskeletal: denies pain or limitation of movement

Endocrine/metabolic: history of diabetes last 20 yrs, hypercholesterolemia

Heme/Onc:  no history of bleeding, blood diseases; no history of malignancy, chemotherapy, or radiation therapy

Psychiatric: no significant psychiatric problems





Exam	

SaO2: 98% RA

Ht:6'1"

Wt:209

BP:180/74

P:79



HEEN&T:  good range of motion, no masses, neck veins flat, no bruits

Airway:  Mallampatti Class I or II

Teeth:  in good repair

Lungs:  clear bilaterally

Heart:  regular rhythm, no murmurs, S1=S2, no gallop





Assessment	

ASA Physical Status:  II

Well prepared for surgery; no unusual concerns related to medical problems.



Plan	

Proposed Anesthetic: general anesthesia

Monitors:  standard

Pain Management:  IVPCA

Autologous blood:  none

Premedication:  none

Usual Medications:  take on day of surgery

Medications to be held on day of surgery:  lipitor

Diabetic medications:  counseled to old am insulin regimen

NSAIDS:  avoid for 3 days before surgery

Aspirin:  avoid for 7 days before surgery

NPO: after midnight 



External Labs	

Not available



Attending Anesthesiologist Reassessment Note	

I have reviewed this preanesthetic assessment and concur with the assessment and recommended plan with the following exceptions:











______________________________                              







Yeomans, Vertis K., M.D.



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2120-09-19" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P1" start="76" end="78" text="81" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="112" end="117" text="Yager" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="152" end="160" text="10/01/20" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="349" end="356" text="6/27/16" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="563" end="567" text="2062" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="3030" end="3048" text="Yeomans, Vertis K." TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>