<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2149-03-19





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

BELLFLOWER DOCTORS HOSPITAL



Reason for visit   67 yo man with DM, supine HTN, orthostatic hypotension, hyperlipidemia, +FH presents with NSTEMI. Patient was in his USOH (extremely limited physical activity 2/2 severe orthostatic hypotension and osteoarthritis) until AM of admission. He had c/o some increased night sweats x 2 weeks s cough and increased constipation. He also c/o worsening "lockjaw" p eating which he attributes to poor denture fitting. He awoke 3/18 AM with sl fatigue, FS 190. He went to his preop cataract appt at FCH and c/o diaphoresis. His FS was 43, BP 122/50, HR 90. EKG revealed STD V2-V3 + pseudonorm T V4-V6-> left with baseline TWI V3-V6. His CK and troponin were positive. He was treated with ASA, BB, ACE, and heparin. He has been sx free since FCH.



Problem List (reviewed)



Tuberculosis MAJOR 

Diabetes mellitus MAJOR 

Radiculopathy MAJOR 

Hypercholesterolemia MAJOR 

Coronary artery disease MAJOR 

Orthostatic hypotension MAJOR 

Shoulder pain MAJOR 

Diabetic retinopathy MAJOR 

Arthritis MAJOR 

Depression MAJOR 

Renal insufficiency MAJOR 

Fatigue MAJOR 

Low back pain MAJOR 

Shortness of breath MAJOR 

Seborrheic dermatitis 

Tinea pedis 

Gastroesophageal reflux disease 

Smoking status: former smoker 

Constipation 

Health maintenance 



Major Problems

Coronary artery disease

History of CAD w/ positive ETT 3/37 (nothing on PCIS); since then had neg adeno-MIBI in 2145, 2147, 8/48 (but only 9680 PDP). Pt on asa, mevacor with hi chol (last fasting 7/48 chol 214, LDL 128). TTE 4/48: EF 59%, LVH, mild MR, no SWMA. Cards = Mildred Gustafson. 

A/P: Cath pending. Cont ASA. Would recheck fasting cholesterol and change to lipitor 80 qd for maximal risk factor management. Limited in use of BB, ACE with orthostatic hypotension. 

Orthostatic hypotension

Fairly severe orthostasis, likely secondary to autonomic dysfunction from diabetes.  Continues to c/o dizziness + nausea with prolonged standing. On fludrocortisone 1x/d, midodrine 10 TID, occ wearing TED stockings. 

A/P: Encourage H2O intake. Needs TED stockings. Continue fludrocortisone 0.1 mg/d, may need to decrease midodrine.

Renal insufficiency

Patient has a h/o DM and CRI. Baseline Cr ranges from 2-3, but went as low as 1.4 in the hospital with hydration. Est CrCl around 28. Ulytes c/w renal disease. Nephrologist Dr. Nesmith. He tries he drinks 6 8 oz glasses of water qd but sometimes doesn't drink as much as that. 

A/P: Encourage hydration, IVF + mucomyst o/n pre cath.



Active Medications



lovastatin 40 mg po qd

Ecotrin 1 qd

omeprazole 20mg po qd

Colace 100mg PO BID

free text medications insulin 75/25 SC 22 u qam, 26 u qsupper

Proamatine 5 po qd

Ultram 37.5 mg po bid prn

fludrocortisone 0.1 mg po qd 2 tabs po qd

Celexa 40mg po qd

Atrovent nasal spray 1-2 spray NAS QD

Buspar 10 mg po qd

vitamin d 800 iu po qd

calcium carbonate 1250mg po tid

Fosamax 70mg po q Week on empty stomach with 6-8 oz. water, remain upright >30min

Miralax 17g po qd 17gm (1tbsp qd prn) as directed

aspirin 325 mg po qd

One touch strips As directed<br />#100<br />RF 6

Syringes B-D ultra fine pen ndl 29gX1/2 use as directed #100   ref:5

Nonmedical therapy One touch test stips (qty 100, RF 5) - 01/02/42



Advance directives   Full code



Review of systems   Negative unless noted above.



Physical examination

Temperature 98.7  

Pulse 80  

Blood pressure 160/80  lying

Respiratory rate 12  

Foot exam   decreased sensation B feet.

General appearance   Tall, thin male, NAD.

Skin   Chronic venous stasis change B shins, skin discoloration, psoriasis.

Heent   NC/AT, PERRL, EOMI, O/P clear without erythema or exudates. No evidence of jaw click or pain with jaw motion on exam.

Neck   JVP 7cm; carotids brisk, 2+ bilaterally without bruits, no goiter.

Chest   CTA B w/o c/w/r.

Abdomen   NT/ND, no HSM. Normal bowel sounds.

Rectal exam   Guiac neg in the EW.

Extrem   No clubbing, cyanosis, edema. Not wearing TEDS.

Musc skel   Glenoid cyst L shoulder. B hands c interosseus muscle wasting. C/o joint pain B wrists and PIPs, L shoulder and L MCPs. Sens grossly intact B hand. Decreased stength 2/2 pain B hands, R =L. Nl strength B UE, slightly limited by pain.

Neuro   A&O x3, CN 2-12 grossly intact. Reflexes 2+ and symmetric x 4 extremities. Toes B downgoing. Gait WNL, but requires cane 2/2 lh. Neuropathy B feet.



Assessment and plan   1. CAD: NSTEMI, on ASA, heparin, statin. 2b3a to start, cath pending in AM. Would recheck fasting cholesterol and change to lipitor 80 qd for maximal risk factor management. Be VERY CAUTIOUS in use of BB, ACE with orthostatic hypotension (he has supine HTN but is extremely orthostatic when he stands up).

- cards consult appreciated

- bedrest x 24h

- increase BB; hold ACE with pending cath.

- pls repeat TTE as per cards

- fasting chol pending; inc lipitor to 80 qd.



2. BP: orthostatic hypotension/supine hypertension

- d/c midodrine, florinef

- BP control with BB (he will NOT be able to go home on this), IV TNG + nitropaste as needed.



3. CRI: DM + chronic prerenal. Continue hydration with IVF o/n.

- mucomyst, hold ACE.



4. DM: on  Insulin 75/25, 28 qA, 26qP. Continue QID FS, adjust as needed. Pls resend HbA1c and get a nutrition consult. I am concerned that he is on too much regular insulin causing his nightsweats and his low glc at FCH yesterday. He may need to change back to NPH and regular (was difficult in the past 2/2 poor vision and arthritis).



5. constipation: pls increase bowel regimen (currently on miralax + colace).



6. PT consult please. He will likely need rehab.



Thanks for the excellent care! I will continue to follow with you.



Lauren Lopes

93756



Selected recent labs   chem 7: 140/4.0/107/25.7/32/1.9/101 -> cr 1.6. 

c/m/p: 9.9/3.6/1.8

CBC: 9.1> 33.4< 187; PTT 75 on heparin

CK peak 1172 -> 917

Trop T 2.11

7/48 chol: 214/65/128



EKG 3/19: NSR. HR 73. TWI V3-V6, TWI 2, 3, F.

CXR: neg



Signed electronically by   Lauren  Lopes MD  on  Mar 19, 2149     



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2149-03-19" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="62" end="89" text="BELLFLOWER DOCTORS HOSPITAL" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P2" start="112" end="114" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="529" end="533" text="3/18" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="600" end="603" text="FCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="842" end="845" text="FCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="1435" end="1439" text="3/37" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="1492" end="1496" text="2145" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="1498" end="1502" text="2147" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1504" end="1508" text="8/48" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1576" end="1580" text="7/48" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1605" end="1609" text="4/48" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="1650" end="1667" text="Mildred Gustafson" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2413" end="2420" text="Nesmith" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="3299" end="3307" text="01/02/42" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P15" start="5423" end="5426" text="FCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="5748" end="5760" text="Lauren Lopes" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P17" start="5762" end="5767" text="93756" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="5937" end="5941" text="7/48" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="5966" end="5970" text="3/19" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="6048" end="6061" text="Lauren  Lopes" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="6070" end="6082" text="Mar 19, 2149" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>