<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2095-05-15

EDVISIT^75659490^ROOT, PERCY^05/15/95^JUSTUS, ELLIS

I saw this patient with Dr. Queen Pickett.  I confirm that I have

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed the

evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient. 

Please see the resident's note for further details.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Syncopal event.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 70-year-old male

with a history of atrial fibrillation for which he is on

Coumadin, congestive heart failure, coronary artery disease,

hypertension, and prior transient ischemic attack, who had a

syncopal episode yesterday.  As per report, the patient felt

lightheaded and passed out while he was shaving.  The patient

passed out while using in the bathroom.  The patient was actually

caught by son before he actually hit the floor.  The patient did

not strike his head.  There was no loss of consciousness.  The

patient then awoke once he was supine.  The patient later felt

normal.  The patient states that he did have some antecedent

diaphoresis and shortness of breath and possible chest

palpitations.  The patient states that he felt like something was

jumping inside his body.  The patient does complain of some

fatigue and malaise.  The patient denies having any lower

extremity swelling or pain.  The patient denies having any chest

pain at this time.  The patient did have an adenosine MIBI in

March 2095, which showed some areas of reversible ischemia over

the distribution of the left circumflex artery.  The patient's

transthoracic echocardiogram from March 2095 did show some LVH as

well as for an ejection fraction of 50% with some global

hypokinesis.  The patient was seen by his primary care physician,

specifically, Dr. Ross.  The patient was instructed to come to

the Emergency Department for further evaluation and admission.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient's vital signs revealed the

following:  The patient's temperature was 99 degrees Fahrenheit. 

Heart rate 63 beats per minute, respiratory rate 18 breaths per

minute, blood pressure is 151/18, and oxygen saturation was

interpreted as normal.  General:  Mild-to-moderate discomfort

noted, daughter at bedside, pleasant.  HEENT:  The patient's head

is normocephalic and atraumatic, no scalp hematomas.  Mucous

membranes were somewhat dry.  Posterior oropharynx was clear. 

Neck:  Supple, no JVD.  Respiratory:  Clear to auscultation

bilaterally.  No focal rhonchi, rales, or wheezes. 

Cardiovascular:  Irregularly irregular, distant heart sounds, no

definite murmurs, rubs, or gallops were appreciated.  GI: 

Abdomen:  Soft, no rebound or guarding, no focal tenderness to

palpation, no palpable pulsatile mass appreciated.  Rectal exam

deferred.  GU exam deferred.  Skin:  Warm and dry, no rash or

lesions were noted.  Back:  No costovertebral angle tenderness. 

There was no presacral edema.  Extremities:  Warm and well

perfused, trace lower extremity edema noted, no asymmetrical

lower extremity edema.  There were no palpable cords.  Neuro: 

The patient was alert and oriented x3, motor, strength, and

sensation were all grossly intact.  The patient's cranial nerves

are grossly intact.  I did not ambulate the patient.

INITIAL IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  The patient is a 70-year-old male

with a history of coronary artery disease, congestive heart

failure, prior transient ischemic attack, and atrial fibrillation

for which he is on Coumadin, who presents with a syncopal

episode.  The patient was sent in to the Emergency Department for

further evaluation and workup for this syncopal event. 

Differential diagnosis at this time includes a syncopal event

secondary to dehydration versus arrhythmia.  I do not feel that

the patient had a cerebrovascular accident.  The patient will

need to have screening laboratory studies and formal imaging.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  Upon arrival to the Emergency

Department, the patient had history and physical exam performed. 

The patient then had a 12-lead EKG performed.  The patient's

12-lead EKG was consistent with atrial fibrillation with some

T-wave flattening noted.  There were no definite acute ischemic

changes appreciated.  The patient had laboratory studies sent. 

The patient's laboratory studies were notable for a creatinine of

1.69.  The patient does have a history of renal insufficiency. 

The patient's cardiac markers were negative.  The patient's BNP

was elevated at 1380.  The patient's complete blood count was

normal.  The patient's coagulation studies were normal patient's

coagulation studies were notable for an INR of 2.2.  The patient

then had a noncontrast head CT scan performed.  The patient's

noncontrast head CT scan results are still pending at this time. 

The patient also had a 2-view chest x-ray ordered.  The patient's

chest x-ray results are also still pending at this time.  Dr.

Ross kindly and promptly saw the patient here in the Emergency

Department.  He was in agreement with admitting the patient to

Internal Medicine at this time.  The patient will be admitted

to a monitor bed.  The patient will need to rule out for possible

acute coronary syndrome or cardiac ischemia.  The patient will

need further monitoring for possible arrhythmia.  The patient was

in agreement with this plan for admission at this time.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSES:

1.  Syncopal event, possibly secondary to an arrhythmia.

2.  Atrial fibrillation.

3.  Renal insufficiency.

DISPOSITION:  The patient was admitted to Internal Medicine

and to a monitor bed.

CONDITION AT THE TIME OF DISPOSITION:  Stable and satisfactory.

______________________________

JUSTUS, ELLIS M.D.

D: 05/15/95

T: 05/15/95

Dictated By: JUSTUS, ELLIS

eScription document:4-4238782 IFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2095-05-15" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="75659490" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="56" text="ROOT, PERCY" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="57" end="65" text="05/15/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="66" end="79" text="JUSTUS, ELLIS" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="109" end="122" text="Queen Pickett" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="464" end="466" text="70" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="1484" end="1494" text="March 2095" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="1647" end="1657" text="March 2095" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="1823" end="1827" text="Ross" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P10" start="3357" end="3359" text="70" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="4975" end="4979" text="Ross" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="5732" end="5745" text="JUSTUS, ELLIS" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="5755" end="5763" text="05/15/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="5768" end="5776" text="05/15/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="5791" end="5804" text="JUSTUS, ELLIS" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P18" start="5826" end="5835" text="4-4238782" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>