<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2075-12-03

                     AGH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

HARDY,TERESA   360-52-41-3                    VISIT DATE: 12/03/75

This patient was seen concurrently with Dr. Jeter, whose note I 

have reviewed and with which I agree. 

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest pain.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 56-year-old female who 

presents with complaints of chest pain.  The patient has a known 

history of coronary artery disease and most recently had a stent 

placed in April of 2075.  The patient had an episode of chest 

tightness with dyspnea while walking to catch a bus.  The patient 

states that this is unusual for her.  She does not usually have 

discomfort with exertion since having her stent placed.  That did 

resolve with rest and now the patient states she had a just "trace" 

of chest tightness throughout the day otherwise.  The patient came 

to Abbeville General Hospital and while walking uphill towards 

the hospital entrance she had recurrence of her discomfort.  The 

patient is pain-free on arrival to the emergency department.   

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As per the written note. 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus, 

angioplasty, stent, coronary artery disease, pulmonary 

hypertension. 

MEDICATIONS:  Glyburide, aspirin, Lasix, and otherwise as per the 

written note.

ALLERGIES:  Actifed.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  This is a well-developed, well-nourished 

female in no acute distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Temperature 97.9, pulse 

87, respiratory rate 20, blood pressure 161/93.  Oxygen saturation 

is 98% on room air.  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils are 

equal, round, reactive to light and accommodation.  Extraocular 

motions are intact.  LUNGS:  Clear to auscultation bilaterally.  No 

crackles.  No wheezes.  CARDIOVASCULAR:  Regular rate and rhythm.  

Physical exam is otherwise as per the written note.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION: Labs are significant for an EKG which shows 

a sinus rhythm at 87 beats per minute.  There are 1-mm ST 

depressions in leads V5 and V6.  This was compared to a prior EKG 

from July 2075 and was found to be without significant change.  The 

only new change on the EKG is that a previously biphasic T-wave in 

V4 is now upright.  Glucose is 215, BUN 21, creatinine 1.1, sodium 

140, potassium 3.9, chloride 100, bicarb 32, CK 321, MB 3.1, trauma 

0.07, calcium 9.4, white count 8.8, hematocrit 40.1, platelets 247, 

PT 11.3, PTT 25.0.  Urinalysis shows no blood, no leukocyte 

esterase, no nitrates.  Chest x-ray shows no infiltrate, no 

pulmonary edema.

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was seen and evaluated 

in the emergency department with labs and studies obtained as 

documented above.  The patient's history is concerning for angina.  

The patient received an aspirin, as well as Lopressor, while in the 

emergency department.  She has remained pain-free throughout her 

period of observation while in the emergency department.  The 

patient will require serial cardiac enzymes due to her most recent 

chest discomfort being en route to the hospital and if these are 

unremarkable the patient will require a functional cardiac study 

such as an exercise tolerance test. 

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Angina.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 

admitted to the hospital in satisfactory condition. 

___________________________________                    JM057/26484 

LATRISHA ERVIN, M.D.       LE72                        D:12/04/75 

                                                       T:12/04/75 

Dictated by:  LATRISHA ERVIN, M.D.       LE72 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2075-12-03" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="52" text="AGH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="78" end="90" text="HARDY,TERESA" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="93" end="104" text="360-52-41-3" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="136" end="144" text="12/03/75" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="190" end="195" text="Jeter" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="332" end="334" text="56" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="501" end="514" text="April of 2075" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="899" end="925" text="Abbeville General Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2121" end="2130" text="July 2075" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P10" start="3456" end="3467" text="JM057/26484" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="3470" end="3484" text="LATRISHA ERVIN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="3497" end="3501" text="LE72" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="3527" end="3535" text="12/04/75" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="3595" end="3603" text="12/04/75" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="3620" end="3634" text="LATRISHA ERVIN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="3647" end="3651" text="LE72" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>