<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2090-05-28


 
NAME: Ocampo, Nathan-Oliver 
MRN: 80531359 
DOV: 05/28/90 


Mr. Ocampo comes in for follow up of his hypertension, 
hypercholesterolemia and also wants to assess his impotence.  Mr. 
Ocampo gets only semi-erections.  He was quite depressed about this 
issue during March, but he feels that his mood has improved.  His 
daughter, Urbina, did talk to me in the hallway about concerns that her 
father might be depressed although he feels that this was a significant 
component of the issue.  He had not had chest pain, chest pressure or 
fainting spells.  He has had no nausea, diarrhea, vomiting or 
constipation.  Urinary symptoms are stable.  His neurological status is 
fine. He tried to lose 5 pounds by exercising and was successful.

EXAM:  On physical examination today his blood pressure is 130/74.  His 
HEENT exam is unremarkable.  His chest is clear.  His heart shows no 
murmurs.  His abdominal examination is benign.  His rectal is guaiac 
negative with a smooth prostate.  I gave him a pack of stool guaiac 
cards.  

ASSESSMENT:  I will give him a prescription of Viagra and I gave him 
appropriate patient education.  I will see him in six months.  I will 
get some laboratory tests and write him a letter.  We will be tuned 
into the issue of depression going forward.

 
_______________________________ 
Kenneth X. Sylvester, M.D. 
 
DD: 05/28/90 
DT: 06/02/90 
DV: 05/28/90 
 
 



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2090-05-28" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="37" end="58" text="Ocampo, Nathan-Oliver" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="65" end="73" text="80531359" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="80" end="88" text="05/28/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="96" end="102" text="Ocampo" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="215" end="221" text="Ocampo" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="297" end="302" text="March" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="361" end="367" text="Urbina" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="1353" end="1373" text="Kenneth X. Sylvester" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1387" end="1395" text="05/28/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1401" end="1409" text="06/02/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1415" end="1423" text="05/28/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>