<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2084-12-12



Internal Medicine

030 Nashua Mall Street                                      FAIR, BILL

Plymouth, IN 46368                                      22041864

-----------                                           12/12/84





ATTENDING PHYSICIAN:  Elizabeth Keys, M.D.



CHIEF COMPLAINT:  diabetes management.



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Fair is a 61-year-old patient with a history of diabetes diagnosed more than 20 years ago.  He has known complication of retinopathy and is status post bilateral laser surgery about one year ago.  He has no known neuropathy or nephropathy.  He has no known history of CAD, CVA or PVD.  He had previously been followed by Dr. Elizabeth Keys at Pioneer Hospital at Findlay until June of this year which time he switched to a new primary care doctor.  At that time, he had been on glyburide, metformin and Avandia, his new PCP increased his glyburide and his Avandia.  He also stopped his hydrochlorothiazide out of concern that this is not an ideal agent for a diabetic patient. Over the next weeks to months, the patient had progressive peripheral edema, fluid weight gain and ultimately development of dyspnea on exertion, orthopnea and paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea.  He returned for care and was started on furosemide and has been recently titrated up to a dose of 60 mg orally on this.  He self adjusted his Avandia dose from 4 mg twice daily to 2 mg daily.  His prebreakfast blood glucose has been elevated ranging from 160-200.  He has had some resolution of his fluid overload with the Lasix and lower dose Avandia.  He says he has persistent feeling of swelling and tightness in his fingers and toes with episodic ankle swelling as well.  He denies chest pain, claudication polyuria, polydipsia.  He has been losing weight since starting Lasix.  He has never had hypoglycemia.



DIABETES SURVELLIANCE AND MANAGEMENT:

Hemoglobin A1c 11.4% (10/01/84).

Cholesterol 190, LDL cholesterol 190, HDL 49 (10/01/84) and LDL 118 (07/02/84).

Microalbumin to creatinine 19 (07/02/84).

Creatinine 0.9 (07/02/84).

Last eye exam 09/83.

Pneumovax never.

Influenza vaccine never.

Aspirin 325 mg daily.

ACE inhibitor yes (lisinopril 10 mg daily,).

Statin yes (Lipitor 40 mg daily).



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:

Diabetes as above.

Diabetic retinopathy.

Hypertension.

Osteoarthritis of the knees.

Status post hammertoe repair.

Pilonidal cyst status post I&D.

Severed Achilles tendon status post repair.

Right meniscus removal.



MEDICATIONS: Glyburide 10 mg twice daily, metformin 1000 mg twice daily and the Avandia 2 mg daily, Lipitor 40 mg daily, lisinopril 10 mg daily.  furosemide 60 mg daily, multivitamin one tablet daily and Viagra as needed.



ALLERGIES:  Amoxicillin gives him a rash.



FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  He works as a manager in a convenience store, he lives with his wife.  He has no kids.  He does not exercise secondary to joint pain.  He tends to eat a lot of carbohydrates and meats although he does not have a sweet tooth.  He denies tobacco, alcohol or recreational drug use.  



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As per HPI, otherwise, negative.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  His weight is 270 pounds, his blood pressure is 150/92 and then 155/92 to my a repeat exam, pulse is 70 and regular.  In general, he is a well-appearing gentleman in no acute distress.  His skin is warm and dry.  Extraocular movements are intact.  Oropharynx is clear.  Mucous membranes are moist.  He has no carotid bruits.  His thyroid is normal in size and contour.  Lung exam reveals crackles at the bases.  His heart is regular in rate and rhythm with an S1, S2, without S3 or S4.  Abdomen is obese, soft and nontender.  There is no hepatosplenomegaly.  His extremities are without clubbing or cyanosis.  There is 2+ pitting edema to the ankles.  His foot exam reveals that his distal pulses are okay.  Sensation is intact to monofilament.  There is no skin breakdown or ulcerations.  He has an extensive onychomycosis of the nails bilaterally.



Glucose 132.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  This is a 61-year-old gentleman with type II diabetes complicated by retinopathy and erectile dysfunction.  He has had inadequate glycemic control on oral agents which are currently at their maximal doses given the intolerable side effects of Avandia.  He has plans for elective knee replacement during the spring and we have advised him that before he consider that he should get his diabetes under better control, should make sure his blood pressure is controlled and should seek cardiac evaluation, especially given his history of pulmonary edema symptoms on Avandia.



1.  We will start insulin today initially NPH 25 units at bedtime to replace his evening dose of glyburide.  We have instructed him on use of the Inolet for insulin administration.  He will continue his glyburide 10 mg each morning, continue metformin 1000 mg twice daily and Avandia 2 mg each morning.  We will check hemoglobin A1c today as a baseline. We will follow up to determine appropriate titration of his insulin as well as addition of other doses during the day.

2.  His blood pressure is not optimally controlled at this time.  We will increase his lisinopril to 40 mg daily. He will continue his furosemide 60 mg daily and he will continue to titrate his Lasix dosing at the guidance of his primary care doctor.

3.  His last microalbumin to creatinine ratio and creatinine were normal.  Testing is up-to-date.

4.  The patient has an LDL that was above target this summer and Lipitor was initiated; however, he has not been on this long enough to see an effect. At his next visit, we will reevaluate his lipids to determine if his Lipitor needs titration.

5.  He is overdue for an eye exam and will contact Dr. Xuereb at Findlay him to have this done.

6.  We have made a referral to Dr. Liam Mcmahon for cardiology evaluation.  We have ordered an echocardiogram to be performed prior to this visit. We have also referred the patient to a number of possible PCPs in the OMC/CBC system. 



The patient was advised to return to the office in two months for follow up.











______________________________

Florence Mildred Yuan, MD





Dictated By: Florence Mildred Yuan





eScription document:2-8940866 EMSSten Tel







DD: 12/16/84

DT: 12/16/84

DV: 12/12/84



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2084-12-12" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P2" start="49" end="71" text="030 Nashua Mall Street" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="109" end="119" text="FAIR, BILL" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="121" end="129" text="Plymouth" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="131" end="133" text="IN" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="134" end="139" text="46368" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<ID id="P7" start="177" end="185" text="22041864" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="241" end="249" text="12/12/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="277" end="291" text="Elizabeth Keys" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="376" end="380" text="Fair" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P11" start="386" end="388" text="61" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="701" end="715" text="Elizabeth Keys" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P13" start="719" end="735" text="Pioneer Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P14" start="739" end="746" text="Findlay" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="753" end="757" text="June" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="1923" end="1931" text="10/01/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="1981" end="1989" text="10/01/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="2004" end="2012" text="07/02/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="2047" end="2055" text="07/02/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="2075" end="2083" text="07/02/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="2101" end="2106" text="09/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P22" start="2844" end="2874" text="manager in a convenience store" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<AGE id="P23" start="4094" end="4096" text="61" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="4391" end="4397" text="spring" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="5537" end="5543" text="summer" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P26" start="5784" end="5790" text="Xuereb" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P27" start="5794" end="5801" text="Findlay" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<NAME id="P28" start="5861" end="5873" text="Liam Mcmahon" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P29" start="6043" end="6046" text="OMC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P30" start="6047" end="6050" text="CBC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P31" start="6183" end="6204" text="Florence Mildred Yuan" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P32" start="6227" end="6248" text="Florence Mildred Yuan" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P33" start="6274" end="6283" text="2-8940866" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P34" start="6307" end="6315" text="12/16/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P35" start="6321" end="6329" text="12/16/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P36" start="6335" end="6343" text="12/12/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>