<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2076-04-24

EDVISIT^91464150^Godwin, Yair^04/24/76^MURRAY, MARION OSCAR

The patient was interviewed and examined primarily by me.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Right chest wall pain.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 70-year-old male

who presents to Bowne Hospital Emergency Department with no

one-week history of right-sided lateral chest wall pain.  The

patient states the pain is worse with movement including

stretching, bending, and reaching.  The patient states that

patient had slept with a hot water bottle on his right chest wall

for pain relief and had pain relief and was sitting in a chair. 

His lying down on his right side was painful, and this morning,

sat up and while getting up, exacerbated the chest wall pain. 

The patient discussed this pain with his primary care physician

during the past 2 weeks and who had been in agreement that it is

probable muscle strain.  The patient denies any headache, visual

changes, and dizziness.  Denies any neck pain.  Denies any

left-sided chest pain.  Denies any nausea, vomiting, diaphoresis,

or dyspnea.  Denies any abdominal pain.  He has been afebrile. 

No cough.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Includes hypertension and non-insulin

dependent diabetes.  The patient also has exposure to asbestos

and asbestos changes on CT scan previously.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Past tobacco, past ETOH, no IV drug abuse, lives

with his family, and he is retired.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As indicated in the history of present

illness, otherwise negative.

MEDICATIONS:  See nursing note for full list of medications.

ALLERGIES:  The patient has no known allergies to medications.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is awake and alert in no acute

distress.  Temperature 95.4, pulse of 67, respiratory rate of 16,

blood pressure 179/78, and O2 saturation 95% on room air.  HEENT

is atraumatic.  ENT:  No infection.  Pharynx is normal.  Neck is

supple and nontender.  Respiratory exam:  Chest wall is tender. 

Patient has reproducible, palpable right-sided posterior lateral

and anterior lateral chest wall tenderness.  Normal breath sounds

bilaterally, no rales, rhonchi, or wheezing.  Cardiac exam: 

Regular rate and rhythm, no murmur, and normal pulses throughout.

 Abdomen is soft.  The patient has some minimal amount of right

upper quadrant tenderness just subcostal at the infracostal

margin.  No rebound or guarding.  Skin is warm, dry, and intact,

no lesions, or rashes.  Extremities are nontender. Normal range

of motion.  No clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  Neurologic exam: 

Cranial nerves II through XII intact bilaterally.  No motor or

sensory deficits.

LABORATORY DATA:  Significant for white count of 10.6, hematocrit

of 38.5, platelets of 244,000.  Sodium 138, potassium 4.1,

chloride of 105, bicarbonate 23, BUN 38, creatinine 1.9, and

glucose of 165.  ALT of 11, AST of 16, amylase of 71, and lipase

61.

Given the fact that the patient had some right upper quadrant

pain and pain was radiating laterally to the right anterior

aspect, patient received a right upper quadrant ultrasound, which

was negative.  No evidence of stones or gallbladder changes,

consistent with cholecystitis.  The patient had a chest x-ray,

which showed no new changes from prior studies.  No evidence of

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

The patient received morphine IV, and subsequently received 2

Percocet tablets, and had resolution of his pain.  Patient's case

was discussed with Dr. Rivers, who is the patient's primary care

physician, and who is in agreement to discharge the patient home

with pain medications and muscle relaxants.  The patient is being

discharged home in satisfactory condition.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  Right chest wall pain.

______________________________

MURRAY, MARION OSCAR M.D.

D: 04/24/76

T: 04/25/76

Dictated By: MURRAY, MARION OSCAR

eScription document:8-7695417 BFFocus





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2076-04-24" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="91464150" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="57" text="Godwin, Yair" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="58" end="66" text="04/24/76" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="67" end="87" text="MURRAY, MARION OSCAR" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="236" end="238" text="70" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="270" end="284" text="Bowne Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="3534" end="3540" text="Rivers" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="3830" end="3850" text="MURRAY, MARION OSCAR" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="3860" end="3868" text="04/24/76" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="3873" end="3881" text="04/25/76" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="3896" end="3916" text="MURRAY, MARION OSCAR" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P12" start="3938" end="3947" text="8-7695417" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>