<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2075-01-10

CCU JAR ADMIT NOTE	Sharon FALLON 1703242

DOA to CCU 01/09/75

CARDS: Dr. Jimenez - covered by Dr. Herman

PCP: Dr Lehman.  Endocrine - Dr Saunders

Code status: Full



Chief Complaint	

72 year old lady w hx ESRD on HD, adm with SOB, no CP, positive troponin and non-specific ST-TW changes. 



History of Present Illness	



Ms Fallon is a 72 year old lady without significant past CAD who presented to the ER because of increasing SOB with minimal exercise.  She says she has been SOB  for 50 years  however in the last week or so, has noticed increased DOE, now w minimal exercise.  No CP, palpitations, sweating, cough, sputum, fever, haemoptysis.  Sleeps in a chair for last number of years.  No ankle swelling.



Called EMS and was given s/l TNG x 4 and O2 w effect.  In ER was given ASA and metoprolol 5mg iv. Refused Kayexylate, insulin and heparin. Had positive troponin 0.19 -  previous troponin in system was 18 months ago  - 0.04.  Transferred to CCU as no beds available in SDU



In CCU -

Pain free overnight. Feels significantly less SOB.  Was refusing SSI at usual doses out of concern for hypoglycemia. 



Past Medical History	

1)	DM2 for 35 years - causing ESRD, retinopathy with laser rx.

2)	HTN in past but not treated for several years due to low BP

3)	Hyperlipidemia

4)	History of DVT with IVC filter

5)	Gout

6)	History of CHF with preserved EF

7)	Chronic right lower extremity venous stasis ulcer



Medications	



At home:

Quinine 350mg bid

Phoslo 667 tid

Allopurinol 200mg qd

Mevacor 20mg

Lantus insulin 58u/day

 

On transfer: as above plus

ASA 325 mg qd

TNG

Metoprolol

SSI



Allergies	

Morphine and Novocaine have made her SOB in the past



Family History	

None relevant.



Social History	

Ethanol use: never

Nicotine use: never.

Lives w her husband. Is normally fairly independent ADLs.



Review of Systems	



General: No weight loss, no sweats, no chills, change in appetite

Respiratory: No wheeze, cough, +SOB, PND, orthopnoea

HEENT: No neck swelling, neck stiffness, hoarseness

Cardiac: No Chest pain, no palpitations, arrythmias, valve disease

Gastrointestinal: No nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, no bleeding or melena until yesterday.

Neurologic: No seizures, headache, weakness, numbness/tingling

Lymph nodes: No enlarged lymph nodes

Musculoskeletal: No back pain, neck pain, arm pain

Urologic: No hematuria, frequency, dysuria no obstruction



Physical Exam



BP 110 - 130/60 -80	Pulse  70s SR		Afebrile 	97% on 4L breathing 14/min

 

Overweight elderly lady, currently pain free.



H and N - No bruits, no LAD, no tracheal deviation.



JVP - 8cm with normal waveform.



CVS -  RRR. Impalpable apex. No M/R/G. Faint sounds.



Chest - Bilateral absent air entry in bases, bilateral crepitations.



Abdomen - Soft, obese, non-tender. No AAA.  G neg.



Groin - no bruits.  



Legs - Chronic venous stasis changes bilaterally with ulcer on posterior right calf/ankle.



LABS



Plasma Sodium           137                      135-145        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium        4.9       H              3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride         94        L              100-108        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide   27.7                     24.0-30.0      mmol/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen    67        H              8-25           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine       6.7       H              0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose          407       H              70-110         mg/dl



Calcium                 8.6                      8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus              6.6       H              2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium               1.9                      1.4-2.0        meq/L



Total Protein           6.9                      6.0-8.0        g/dl

Albumin                 3.0       L              3.1-4.3        g/dl

Globulin                3.9                      2.6-4.1        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin        0.1                      0-0.4          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin         0.2                      0-1.0          mg/dl

Triglycerides           116                      40-150         mg/dl

Cholesterol             160                                     mg/dl

High Density Lipoprotei 66                       35-100         mg/dl

Low Density Lipoprotein 71                                      mg/dl



Alkaline Phosphatase    129       H              30-100         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT       9                        7-30           U/L

Transaminase-SGOT       24                       9-25           U/L

Amylase                 74                       3-100          units/L

Lipase                  2.0                      1.3-6.0        U/dl



Creatine Kinase Isoenzy 7.3       H              0.0-6.9        ng/ml

Troponin-T              0.47      H              0.00-0.09      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase         83                       40-150         U/L



WBC                     9.3                      4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                     35.7      L              36.0-46.0      %

HGB                     10.9      L              12.0-16.0      gm/dl

RBC                     3.79      L              4.00-5.20      mil/cmm

PLT                     204                      150-350        th/cumm

MCV                     94                       80-100         fl

MCH                     28.8                     26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                    30.6      L              31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                     15.7      H              11.5-14.5      %

PT                      12.9                     11.1-13.1      sec

APTT                    25.7                     22.1-35.1      sec



CXR

To my eye, cardiomegaly, bilateral pleural effusions, bilateral lower zone reticulo-nodular exam.



ECGs

Sinus 76. Left ward axis, normal intervals. LVH by voltage w QRS of 125, TWI in 1, aVL, laterally.  Somewhat worsened from ECG in October. 



ECHO



MITRAL VALVE      ABN                            SEGMENT   BASE  MID  APEX

LEFT ATRIUM       ABN    LA    43  (25-38mm)

AV. A0. LVOT      ABN    AO    29  (24-39mm)     anterior               A

LEFT VENT.        ABN    LVIDd 49  (37-53mm)     ant.sep.

TV. RA. VC.       NORM   LVIDs 37                mid.sep.               H

PV. INF. PA.      NORM   PWT   12  ( 7-11mm)     inf.sep.

RIGHT VENT.       NORM   IVS   13  ( 7-11mm)     inferior

IAS. IVS.         NORM                           inf.pos.

COMPLEX CHD              EF    51 % ( >50 %)     pos.lat.

CORONARIES        UV                             lateral                H

PERICARDIUM       NORM



MITRAL VALVE

There is evidence of thickening of the anterior mitral leaflet.  There is

calcification of the anterior and posterior mitral annulus.  There is no

evidence of mitral valve prolapse.  The peak transmitral gradient is 10 mmHg.

The mean transmitral gradient is 5 mmHg.  There is mild to moderate mitral

regurgitation by color and spectral Doppler.

LEFT ATRIUM

The left atrium is dilated.



AORTIC VALVE, AORTA, LVOT

Multiple aortic leaflets are thickened but there is no stenosis.  The aortic

valve is tricuspid.  There is no evidence of aortic insufficiency by color or

spectral Doppler.



LEFT VENTRICLE

The left ventricular cavity size is normal.  The left ventricular systolic

function approaches the lower limits of normal.  There is symmetric left

ventricular hypertrophy.  There is segmental apical left ventricular

dysfunction (see wall motion plot).  There is no evidence of left ventricular

thrombus.  The estimated ejection fraction is 51 %.



TRICUSPID VALVE - IVC, SVC

There is color and spectral Doppler evidence of trace tricuspid insufficiency.



RIGHT VENTRICLE

The right ventricle is not dilated.  The right ventricular systolic function

is within normal limits.



PERICARDIAL DISEASE AND EXTRACARDIAC MASSES

There is no evidence of pericardial effusion.  There is a space between

visceral and parietal pericardium most c/w pericardial fat.



CONCLUSIONS

Compared to the study of 9/12/73, the EF has dropped by 10% and apical wall

motion abnormalities are now noted.





CCU Course/Plan	

72 year old woman with ESRD, positive troponin in setting SOB and pulmonary oedema on CXR. Suspect  leak  from demand.  



1)	ischemia: ASA, BB. Would doubt she needs urgent cath but will hold NPO for potential cath in am.  Would not add heparin. Check fasting lipids.



2)	rhythm: so far not an issue. BB as tolerated. 



3)	pump: she has LVH and likely diastolic dysfunction.  Would prefer to have ACE on board - will d/w renal as to why not.



4)	ESRD - can go for HD today. Need to contact dialysis unit to arrange time.



5)	DM 2 - SSI for now, will likely give back Lantus tonight. She is v reluctant to have SSI, will give at half usual doses.



6)	FEN cardiac, diabetic diet. Hold NPO pending possible cath in am.



7)	Prophylaxis: GI: Nexium, DVT: Heparin IV; BM: prn. 



8)	Dispo - to SDU today





Eddie Clark, 24144





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2075-01-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="47" end="60" text="Sharon FALLON" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="61" end="68" text="1703242" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="81" end="89" text="01/09/75" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="102" end="109" text="Jimenez" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="127" end="133" text="Herman" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="143" end="149" text="Lehman" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="167" end="175" text="Saunders" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="216" end="218" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="359" end="365" text="Fallon" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P10" start="371" end="373" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="5935" end="5942" text="October" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="8059" end="8066" text="9/12/73" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P13" start="8170" end="8172" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="8988" end="8999" text="Eddie Clark" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P15" start="9001" end="9006" text="24144" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>