<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2082-07-15


Internal Medicine
Room 4B
39 Mosele Court                                        Xanders, Ruth
Changchun, LA 14176                                      56419927
(109) 932-5237                                          
07/15/82


DIAGNOSIS:
1. Hypertension.
2. Pedal edema.
3. Diabetes.

HPI: Ruth is a 42 year old woman who presents for follow
up of medical issues as well as for new pedal edema over the
past 2 weeks.  When I saw her a few weeks ago, she was very
dehydrated and required a decrease in dose of her Lasix due
to symptoms of dehydration as well as a rise in her
creatinine and BUN.  She responded well to this and then did
well for a week or so.  Then she saw Dr. Vuong who
increased her dose of Lasix back to 20 mg in the evening. 
Subsequently, she developed pedal edema which, at times, is
up to her knees and has been very bothersome for her.  Of
note, she started Norvasc within the past few months and it
was gradually increased to 10 mg a day.  She reports her
blood sugars have been under excellent control, ranging from
90-120s-140s especially over the past couple of weeks.  She
has had a couple of lows in the 40s over the past couple of
months.  She again has not yet followed up with Dr. Vicki
Klein as I had recommended for help with her diabetes.  She
reports her blood pressure in Dr. Vuong's office was
normal as well.  She denies any orthopnea, PND, increased
shortness of breath or dyspnea on exertion.  No fever or
chills.  Remainder review of systems negative.  She does
report sweating with meals that she is unsure how long she
has had but has noted it over the past few months. 

MEDICATIONS: As noted in the record and confirmed.

ALLERGIES: Lisinopril causes cough.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: She is a pleasant woman in no acute
distress.  Her skin is very tanned.  Blood pressure 148/62,
on repeat it is 160/70, pulse of 88, weight of 150, weight
is up about 6 pounds for her.  HEENT within normal limits. 
Neck: no JVD.  Lungs clear to auscultation bilaterally, no
crackles or rhonchi.  Cardiovascular exam: normal S1, S2,
II/VI systolic murmur at right sternal border.  Abdomen is
benign.  Extremities: she has 1-2+ pitting pedal edema to
mid shin.  

IMPRESSION AND PLAN: 42 year old woman with:
1. New pedal edema.  Reviewing patient's recent lab results,
she does have proteinuria but it is actually improved since
the last time it was checked and also her creatinine has
improved.  I believe the pedal edema may be related to the
Norvasc.  Therefore, I advised her to stop the Norvasc and
she will call me tomorrow to let me know how she is doing as
it may take a few days to resolve.  Will consider increasing
her Lasix based on how she responds to discontinuing the
Norvasc and her labs.  Will check basic metabolic panel and
urinalysis as well.
2. Hypertension since discontinuing Norvasc.  Will start
atenolol in a low dose but advised her not to start this for
the next few days.  Will start at 12.5 mg a day and increase
to 25 mg a day and she will follow up in the next few weeks
for a repeat blood pressure check.
3. Diabetes.  The patient is strongly encouraged to make an
appointment with Dr. Vicki Klein regarding the diabetes to
see if there is anything more we can do to change her
insulin regimen.  

The patient to follow up with me by phone tomorrow and
otherwise in the next 3 weeks for a blood pressure check and
sooner if no resolution of her pedal edema.


______________________________
Susan A. Donaldson, M.D.


CC:

eScription document:7-376932

DD: 07/15/82
DT: 07/17/82
DV: 07/15/82



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2082-07-15" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="55" end="70" text="39 Mosele Court" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="110" end="123" text="Xanders, Ruth" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="124" end="133" text="Changchun" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="135" end="137" text="LA" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="138" end="143" text="14176" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="181" end="189" text="56419927" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P9" start="190" end="204" text="(109) 932-5237" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="247" end="255" text="07/15/82" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="321" end="325" text="Ruth" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="331" end="333" text="42" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="708" end="713" text="Vuong" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<PHI id="P14" start="1245" end="1256" text="Vicki
Klein" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="1345" end="1350" text="Vuong" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P16" start="2242" end="2244" text="42" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="3176" end="3187" text="Vicki Klein" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="3481" end="3499" text="Susan A. Donaldson" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P19" start="3533" end="3541" text="7-376932" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="3547" end="3555" text="07/15/82" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="3560" end="3568" text="07/17/82" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="3573" end="3581" text="07/15/82" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>