<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2133-11-13

Rheumatology Consult Note



Name:  Vastie Uecker

MR#: 7045247

Date of Admission to PCH: 11/13/33

Consult Date: 11/13/33



ID/CC: 60 yo F w/FH scleroderma, personal hx of fibromyalgia, Raynaud's phenomena, GERD, HTN and bronchiectasis p/w diffuse arthralgias, myalgia



HPI: This is a 60 yo F w/a hx of fibromyalgia, Raynaud's, GERD, HTN, bronchiectasis and recurrent PNA who developed severe pain, swelling and stiffness in the MCP joints of both hands 2 nights ago. She says there was initially some redness, no warmth in these joints. She could not open or close her hands. She says the pain migrated to involve all of the joints in her hands, wrists, elbows, shoulders and knees. She noticed swelling in her R knee, no swelling or redness in other joints. Her muscles are diffusely tender. She recalls similar muscle discomfort in prior episodes attributed to fibromyalgia, although not as severe. She also remembers shoulder and elbow pain of similar but less intense character in 2128 while taking rifampin/cipro/azithro for MAC. These symptoms resolved when drugs were stopped. She denies recent fevers or chills. She completed an 8 day course of augmentin for MSSA PNA two days ago. Symptomatically she feels her PNA has resolved and she is at her baseline from a respiratory standpoint w/stable cough and SOB. She does report some mild L-sided pleuritic CP since yesterday. She denies weight loss, skin changes, rash, change in BMs, N/V, dry mouth, change in vision, weakness, paresthesias. ROS + for brittle nails, eye dryness not bothersome. FH notable for mother w/scleroderma.



Her symptoms did not respond to Excedrin and she presented to the ER 11/12. Exam notable for BP 212/93, HR 125, T 98, SO2 98%,    tenderness w/movement in UE's, R knee   . WBC 11.7, HCT 39.8, PLT 421, chem. 10 wnl, CXR w/stable bibasilar lung nodularity. She was admitted to Internal Medicine for further evaluation. She reports decreased pain with Demerol, interval improvement in hand joint swelling/erythema/stiffness.



PMH:

Bronchiectasis: Recurrent PNA since 3yo, s/p RML lobectomy 2128

MAC: Treatment interrupted 2/2 liver failure 2128

Diverticulitis c/b perforation and sigmoid resection 2129

Raynaud's

Fibromyalgia: Dx 2122 when she p/w neck, shoulder, hip, chest wall, knee and jaw pain; followed by Dr. Christopher Sharp at DCHC

Migraine headaches

HTN

GERD

Hiatal and ventral hernias

S/p appy

Osteopenia



Home Meds:  

Medroxyprogesterone 5mg qd

Estradiol 2mg qd

Prilosec 20mg qd

Inderal 120mg qd

Nortriptyline 75mg qd

Colace 100 bid

Vitamin C + E

Prn fioricet, Excedrin, imitrex



Current Meds:

Nortriptyline 75 mg qhs

Inderal 240mg qd

Nexium 20mg qd

Prn Demerol



All:

Percocet/Darvon/Codeine-GI upset

Sulfa-   kidney problem   

Flagyl-   throat closed   

Levaquin, azithromycin-rash

  	

SH:  	Retired Firefighter, no ETOH, tobacco or drugs 



FH:	Mother w/systemic scleroderma (joint pain and swelling, skin changes, Raynaud's), CAD, DM died at 68 yo



Exam:  	

	VS:  	Afebrile Tc 97.5; BP 164/80; HR 84; RR 20

	HEENT: Anicteric, OP clear no lesions

	Lungs:  Decreased BS at bases

	Cor:  	RRR no M/R/G, JVP 8

	Abd:  	Soft, NT, ND, reducible hernia R of midline

	MSK: Marked muscle tenderness to palpation, particularly involving chest, arms, legs; mild boney tenderness along entire spine; decreased lateral, forward flexion and extension of neck which she reports is baseline; shoulders, elbows and wrists with full ROM, NT; slight tissue swelling/?synovitis involving MCP joints bilaterally, particularly L first MCP, no warmth or erythema; no PIP or DIP finger joint abnormalities; hips somewhat stiff but w/full ROM; R>L knee crepitus, full ROM; ankles w/full ROM; strength intact

	Skin/nails: No rashes, petechiae, or nail changes  

	

Labs:

PCH  BLOOD          13-Nov-2133 09:58  Accession# 8326S84259



WBC                              9.9                       (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                              36.0                      (36.0-46.0)      %

HGB                              12.7                      (12.0-16.0)      gm/dl

RBC                              4.06                      (4.00-5.20)      mil/cmm

PLT                              437              H        (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                              89                        (80-100)         fl

MCH                              31.4                      (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                             35.4                      (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                              13.3                      (11.5-14.5)      %

ESR                              79               H        (1-25)           mm/hr



Plasma Sodium                    134              L        (135-145)        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 3.6                       (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  99               L        (100-108)        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            25.0                      (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

Calcium                          9.1                       (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl

Phosphorus                       2.7                       (2.6-4.5)        mg/dl

Magnesium                        1.5                       (1.4-2.0)        meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             10                        (8-25)           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                0.8                       (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

Thyroid Stimulating Hormone      0.96                      (0.40-5.00)      uU/ml



Blood Culture - Pending



PCH  PA & Lat. Chest              12-Nov-2133 18:34 Accession# 0152809   Final

	

	The faint areas of nodularity at the lung bases, slightly more

	prominent than seen on August 15, 2130.  The relative stability of

	these findings suggests an underlying benign etiology.  However,

	correlation with CT of the chest would be useful for further

	evaluation.



EKG:	NSR 80 LAD TWI V1-V5 similar to prior

____________________________________________



Impr:	60 yo F w/longstanding fibromyalgia and bronchiectasis s/p recent MSSA PNA p/w diffuse arthralgias, myalgias and pleuritic CP. The constellation of myalgias, arthralgias/synovitis, ?pleurisy, Raynaud's, GERD, HTN and +FH invoke the possibility of scleroderma. Rarely, a variant of this disease can present without skin manifestations (systemic sclerosis sine scleroderma). The transient nature of her joint symptomatology is c/w possible crystal disease. The bilateral hand distribution is typical, but progression to involve other joints such as the knee is not. Postviral arthralgias/myalgias is another consideration given the quick resolution of the process. Her myalgias may well represent underlying fibromyalgia. We recommend

  	If available, past ANA, RF, ESR

  	Please check ANA, RF, parvovirus IgM and IgG, uric acid level, U/A

  	Plain films of bilateral hands, R knee

Thank you for this interesting consult. We will follow with you.







_________________________________

Lauren Fontenot, M.D.

Pager 87566      



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2133-11-13" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="64" end="77" text="Vastie Uecker" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="84" end="91" text="7045247" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="114" end="117" text="PCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="119" end="127" text="11/13/33" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="143" end="151" text="11/13/33" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="162" end="164" text="60" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="318" end="320" text="60" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1019" end="1023" text="2128" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1695" end="1700" text="11/12" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="2093" end="2094" text="3" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2116" end="2120" text="2128" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="2167" end="2171" text="2128" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="2226" end="2230" text="2129" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="2260" end="2264" text="2122" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="2346" end="2363" text="Christopher Sharp" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P18" start="2367" end="2371" text="DCHC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P19" start="2874" end="2885" text="Firefighter" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<AGE id="P20" start="3019" end="3021" text="68" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P21" start="3831" end="3834" text="PCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="3851" end="3862" text="13-Nov-2133" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P23" start="3881" end="3891" text="8326S84259" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P24" start="5584" end="5587" text="PCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="5618" end="5629" text="12-Nov-2133" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P26" start="5647" end="5654" text="0152809" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P27" start="5756" end="5771" text="August 15, 2130" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P28" start="6045" end="6047" text="60" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P29" start="7036" end="7051" text="Lauren Fontenot" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P30" start="7065" end="7070" text="87566" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>