<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2088-02-13

 



Rochester State Hospital

Internal Medicine



Name:	ETHERIDGE, SHARI

MR#:	2931335

CC:	84 yo F with abdominal distension, pain, and obstipation.



HPI:	84 yo F, with known mesenteric ischemia, who was recently hospitalized 1/18/88-1/30/88 with influenza A, demand cardiac ischemia, and an E. coli UTI. She was discharged to home on 1/30/88 and was doing home until 3 days, when she noted the onset of abdominal distension with failure to pass stool and flatus. Over the last two days, she has noted the onset of heartburn, nausea without vomiting; over the last one day, she has noted the onset of abdominal pain, which she describes as    someone kicking her,    diffuse, brought on primarily by standing, and not associated with food intake (though she has had very little to eat over the last three days).  Usually, she passes stool Q3d due to her baseline constipation, which is generalized resolved with MOM; at the current time, a suppository and MOM, with relief of small amount of stool.  She denies fevers, chills, CP. She endorses baseline SOB and baseline constipation.



	She endorses that she failed to present sooner because she    does not want a colostomy.   



PMHx: CAD, diastolic CHF (Echo 1/20/88: no MVP, no MR, no LAD no AS, no AR, nl LV size with EF 55% and no WMA, trace TR, no PR, RVSP 42 mmHg, no RV dilation, nl RV fcn, discrete upper septal hypertrophy without outflow obstruction), Type 2 DM, HTN, PVD, COPD, anemia



PsurgHx: Ileocecotomy with appendectomy (8/87, Gregory, PMH; pathology: transmural necrosis of cecum and ileal with perforation and acute serositis, likely ischemic atheroembolic in nature), aortobifemoral BPG (Trotter), SMA stent (Li), B femoral angioplasties, B carotid endarterectomies, open cholecystectomy



Meds:	(From recent discharge)

-Aspirin 81 mg. PO daily

-Glucotrol 2.5 mg. PO q.a.m.  

-Clopidogrel 75 mg. PO daily. 

-Protonix 40 mg. PO daily.  

-Iron 325 mg. PO daily.  

-Lopressor 50 mg. PO b.i.d.  

-Colace 100 mg. PO b.i.d.

-xanax prn



All:  Sulfur, ceftriaxone, HCTZ, Zoloft, codeine, PCN, azithromycin 

SHx: Widowed, son was recently diagnosed with metastatic pancreatic cancer; smokes 1 ppd for    many [unknown] years   -quit 7 years prior; no EtOH x 14 years

PE:	V/S	97.6  82  154/69  18  93RA    100 RA

Gen:	Elderly W who is apparent discomfort

HEENT: NCAT; sclera are anicteric

Chest:	Decreased BS diffusely with diffuse inspiratory and expiratory wheezes; no rales/rhonchi

CV:	RRR +S1/S2

Abd:	Firm and distended, diffusely tender to palpation, primarily periumbilically, LLQ, and RLQ without rebound/guarding. Scant BS. Well-healed surgical scars (midline vertical, RUQ, and B groin). No evidence of incisional or inguinal hernias though mildly tender at the L inguinal canal. Normal rectal tone without evidence of masses; no stool in the vault to guaiac.

Ext:	B LE are warm and well-perfused with CR <2 sec B. DP 2+ on R, 1+ on L

Labs:	

NA        		131(L)    	          	          	          	          

K         		4.5       	          	          	          	          

CL       	 	89(L)     	          	          	          	          

CO2       	               30.0      	          	          	          	          

BUN       	               30(H)     	          	          	          	          

CRE       	               1.7(H)    	          	          	          	          

GLU       	               208(H)    

 

CA        		10.1      	          	          	          	          

PHOS      	3.7       	          	          	          	          

MG        		2.0       	          	          	          	          

TBILI     		0.5       	          	          	          	          

DBILI     		0.2       	          	          	          	          

TP        		8.8(H)    	          	          	          	          

ALB       		4.1       	          	          	          	          

GLOB      	4.7(H)    	          	          	          	          

AMY       	                37        	          	          	          	          

LIPS      		4.2   

ALT/SGPT  	15        	          	          	          	          

AST/SGOT  	24        	          	          	          	          

ALKP      	124(H)     



CK        		19(L)     	          	          	          	          

TROP-T    	<0.01     



WBC       	9.8       	          	          	          	          

RBC       	               4.68      	          	          	          	          

HGB       	               13.1      	          	          	          	          

HCT       	               40.0      	          	          	          	          

MCV       	                86        	          	          	          	          

MCH       	27.9      	          	          	          	          

MCHC      	32.7      	          	          	          	          

PLT       		258       	          	          	          	          

RDW       	13.2      	          	          	          	          

DIFFR     	Received  	          	          	          	          

METHOD    	Auto      	          	          	          	          

%NEUT     	85(H)     	          	          	          	          

%LYMPH    	10(L)     	          	          	          	          

%MONO     	4         	          	          	          	          

%EOS      	1         	          	          	          	          

%BASO     	0         	          	          	          	          

ANEUT     	8.29(H)   	          	          	          	          

ALYMP     	0.98(L)   	          	          	          	          

AMONS     	0.40      	          	          	          	          

AEOSN     	0.10      	          	          	          	          

ABASOP    	0.01      	          	          	          	          

ANISO     	None      	          	          	          	          

HYPO      	None      	          	          	          	          

MACRO     	None      	          	          	          	          

MICRO     	None      	          	          	          	          	          	          	          	          	                    	          	          	          	                	          	          	         

Rad:	

PA/Lat CXR: 	   Minimal hazy opacity in the left lower lobe which may represent subsegmental atelectasis or consolidation.  Platelike subsegmental atelectasis of the right lung bases.    NGT below the diaphragm



KUB/Upright: Mechanical SBO vs adynamic ileus

Assessment/ Plan:  84 yo F, clinically with an SBO, likely due to adhesions. At this time, the patient is hemodynamically stable without peritoneal signs. She does not have a leukocytosis.

1.	Admit to the RSH Surgery Service

2.	NPO/IVF, NGT LCWS

3.	Strict I+Os

4.	Serial abdominal exams

5.	If the patient does not have resolution in 24-48 hr, we recommend CT abdomen/pelvis to evaluate obstruction. If she clinically deteriorates, we recommend exploratory laparotomy

 6. Will hold plavix and ASA in event of operative procedure



RSH

Surgery

Welsh General Hospital

Humana Hospital Ville Platte 294

942 077 9578













]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2088-02-13" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="33" end="57" text="Rochester State Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="86" end="102" text="ETHERIDGE, SHARI" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P4" start="109" end="116" text="2931335" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="122" end="124" text="84" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="188" end="190" text="84" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="259" end="266" text="1/18/88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="267" end="274" text="1/30/88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="368" end="375" text="1/30/88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1247" end="1254" text="1/20/88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1527" end="1531" text="8/87" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="1533" end="1540" text="Gregory" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P13" start="1542" end="1545" text="PMH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="1697" end="1704" text="Trotter" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="1718" end="1720" text="Li" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P16" start="6531" end="6533" text="84" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P17" start="6718" end="6721" text="RSH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P18" start="7049" end="7052" text="RSH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P20" start="7063" end="7085" text="Welsh General Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P21" start="7087" end="7115" text="Humana Hospital Ville Platte" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P23" start="7121" end="7133" text="942 077 9578" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>