<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2079-02-13

                     PMH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
WESTYN-NUEL,KELLI   898-97-85-6            VISIT DATE: 02/13/79
This patient was seen with Dr. Quilla Uehara, an Emergency 
Medicine resident.  The PRESENTING COMPLAINT, HISTORY OF PRESENTING 
COMPLAINT, PAST MEDICAL HISTORY, MEDICATIONS, ALLERGIES, SOCIAL 
HISTORY, FAMILY HISTORY, and REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As noted on the 
record by Dr. Uehara, and as reviewed with the patient and with Dr. 
Uehara.  Briefly, the patient is a pleasant 64-year-old woman, who 
has had episodes of severe left-sided pressure-like chest pain off 
and on through the course of this week.  This has occurred with 
exertion and has always cleared with rest.  She is pain-free at 
present, but presents to the Emergency Department because she 
reported to her family that she had ceased taking her high blood 
pressure medications. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The physical examination is as noted by Dr. 
Uehara.  Basically, the examination is completely normal with the 
exception of the blood pressure, which ranges from 220 to 230 over 
100 to 110.  The patient's electrocardiogram does not show acute 
changes. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  The cardiac troponin I is 0.53. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  I concur with Dr. Uehara that the 
patient has a strong history for unstable angina.  The patient will 
be admitted to the hospital for further evaluation.  She has 
remained pain-free while in the Emergency Department and has 
received nitroglycerin paste.  Her blood pressure will be treated 
with initiation of an ACE inhibitor. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Unstable angina. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 
admitted to the hospital in satisfactory condition. 
___________________________________                    IZ329/1982 
STEPHEN X. PIKE, M.D.  SP59                               D:02/13/79 
                                                       T:02/13/79 
Dictated by:  STEPHEN X. PIKE, M.D.  SP59 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2079-02-13" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="52" text="PMH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="76" end="93" text="WESTYN-NUEL,KELLI" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="96" end="107" text="898-97-85-6" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="131" end="139" text="02/13/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="171" end="184" text="Quilla Uehara" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="414" end="420" text="Uehara" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="469" end="475" text="Uehara" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="513" end="515" text="64" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="955" end="961" text="Uehara" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="1273" end="1279" text="Uehara" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P11" start="1799" end="1809" text="IZ329/1982" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="1811" end="1826" text="STEPHEN X. PIKE" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="1834" end="1838" text="SP59" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="1871" end="1879" text="02/13/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="1938" end="1946" text="02/13/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="1962" end="1977" text="STEPHEN X. PIKE" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="1985" end="1989" text="SP59" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>