<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2077-07-03





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

MESA VISTA HOSPITAL



Reason for visit   f/u labs DM, presync, htn, hyperlipidemia



Major Problems

Chest pain

June/ june77 - no recurrence.

Hypertension

The patient has been treated since November of 2076 with hydrochlorothiazide in addition to his atenolol and lisinopril and Norvasc.  Since that time, his creatinine has risen significantly.  Cre stable at 2.2.  Has htn today 160/90 and microalb quite high.  Will d/c hctz and double lisinopril to 40,  returning in two weeks for review of sx/labs.

Diabetes mellitus

Taking Glucophage 500mg po bid. He has stable nocturia without change. We will recheck his renal function and his hemoglobin A1c.  He is not fasting today, and we will check fasting in the near future

Syncope

He was admitted to Leake County Memorial Hospital in December-January 2077. It was thought that he was symptomatic because of dehydration. Had frank sync 1/10,77, and also Nov 18 lost consciousness. There was no sense of TIA or unsteadiness on his feet. He has a carotid bruit and was scheduled to have another ultrasound in the last few months. However, no ultrasound is at hand. Three or four years ago there was insignificant carotid disease documented. Has no symptoms now, no dizziness, sync, but + bruit, and distal peripheral vascular disease, we will proceed to re-image.

Renal failure

Creatinine is elevated high microalbumin and urind 2= alb.  Will check 24 hour urine after stable regimen.

Health maintenance

No cigarettes. No alcohol. Exercises 30 minutes per day. There is recent normal LDL cholesterol on 20 mg of lisinopril.  LFTs not done. No sx tc 169, LDL 86 and HDL 57 tis June.

Coronary artery disease

The patient is status post stent. He had exercise tolerance test after the stenting showing resolution of his inferoposterior ischemia. This was four to five years ago, and the patient has been stable since. His last exercise test was in 2072 with submaximal exercise loads..



Other Problems

Smoking

Never

Diabetes insipidus

error

Smoking Status: Former Smoker

more than 10 yrs ago.



Change in therapies and Renewals

lisinopril 40 mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 1/2/2076

hydrochlorothiazide 12.5 mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:6 Start: 11/1/2076 End: 7/3/2077 - Inactivated

Lotrimin cream    top  bid QTY: 60 g Refills: 5 Start: 7/3/2077  to feet



Review of systems

			

GU -- no frequency, dysuria nocturia 2x, no change.

 HE HAS INTERMITTENT CLAUDICATION AT ABOUT 5 BLOCKS 10 minutes- HAS HAD WHAT SOUNDS LIKE PVRS DONE.  Right is more consistently a problem.



Physical examination

Pulse 56   

Blood pressure 160/80   

Respiratory rate 12  

Weight 127   

Foot exam   Good hygiene and good sensation by filament.  Has t pedis bilat and r is >> left. long toenails some onychomychosis, no cellulitis. 

Extrem   No edema, no pt or dp pulses but toes warm.

Musc skel   No bony deformities.

height   



Disposition

f/utwo weeks. Pt wants me to be pcp.



Signed electronically by Oswald M Jeffers MD on Jul 07, 2077     



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2077-07-03" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="62" end="81" text="MESA VISTA HOSPITAL" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P2" start="177" end="181" text="June" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="183" end="189" text="june77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="257" end="273" text="November of 2076" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="821" end="851" text="Leake County Memorial Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="855" end="863" text="December" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="864" end="876" text="January 2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="956" end="963" text="1/10,77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="974" end="980" text="Nov 18" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1698" end="1702" text="June" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1968" end="1972" text="2072" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2205" end="2213" text="1/2/2076" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2273" end="2282" text="11/1/2076" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="2288" end="2296" text="7/3/2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="2367" end="2375" text="7/3/2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="3031" end="3047" text="Oswald M Jeffers" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="3054" end="3066" text="Jul 07, 2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>