<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2081-12-23

                     WMH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
JOHNSON,PEPPER E.   537-18-74-8                   VISIT DATE: 12/23/81
The patient was seen by me and examined.  Briefly, the history is 
as follows. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 52 year-old 
black male with multiple cardiac risk factors including insulin 
dependent diabetes, hypertension, and hypercholesterolemia, who now 
presents for evaluation of chest pain.  The patient states he 
developed substernal chest pressure this a.m. at approximately 9 
o'clock, associated with nausea, shortness of breath, diaphoresis, 
and generalized weakness.  He states the discomfort was a 
substernal tightness without radiation.  At the present time he 
states the pain is approximately 4/10 in intensity.  Of note, the 
patient had a stress test done on December 6, 2081, standard Bruce, 
for which he exercised 7 minutes, 30 seconds and stopped secondary 
to fatigue.  He went 74 percent of predicted and developed no 
symptoms.  The test revealed no evidence of ischemia. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As noted above. 
MEDICATIONS:  Lopressor, amoxicillin, aspirin, insulin, 
nitroglycerin p.r.n., Claritin, lisinopril, and Zocor. 
ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies. 
SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  The patient denies smoking. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  Well-developed, well-nourished, 
pleasant male in no acute distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Temperature 97, 
blood pressure 108/62, pulse 80, respiratory rate 18, O2 saturation 
97 percent on room air.  HEENT:  Mucous membranes were moist 
without lesions.  NECK:  Supple without jugular venous distension. 
LUNGS:  Clear to auscultation.  HEART:  Regular rate and rhythm 
without murmurs, rubs or gallops.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, non-tender and 
non-distended.  EXTREMITIES:  No clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  No 
calf tenderness.  Negative Homan's sign.  NEUROLOGIC:  Awake, alert 
and oriented times three, non-focal. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  CBC:  White count 8.9, hematocrit 40.8, 
platelets 323,000.  CPK was 1213, MB 10.5.  SMA-7 was within normal 
limits.  Cardiac troponin was 0.04.  EKG showed normal sinus rhythm 
with nonspecific T-wave changes.  There was a flipped T-wave in 
leads 1 and aVL, which is unchanged compared with prior tracing 
dated December 6, 2081. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was treated in the 
emergency department with O2, two liters via nasal cannula, 
nitroglycerin 1/150 sublingual times three, Lopressor 25 mg p.o., 
and aspirin 325 mg p.o.  The patient became pain-free and remained 
hemodynamically stable. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Chest pain, rule out myocardial infarction. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient will 
be admitted to the medical service for further evaluation and 
management, including usual rule out myocardial infarction 
protocol.  He was admitted in stable condition. 
___________________________________                    BW018/5369 
URIEL ERVIN, M.D.       UE24                        D:12/23/81 
                                                       T:12/24/81 
Dictated by:  URIEL ERVIN, M.D.       UE24 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2081-12-23" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="52" text="WMH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="76" end="93" text="JOHNSON,PEPPER E." TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="96" end="107" text="537-18-74-8" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="138" end="146" text="12/23/81" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="278" end="280" text="52" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="847" end="863" text="December 6, 2081" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="2302" end="2318" text="December 6, 2081" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="2965" end="2975" text="BW018/5369" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2977" end="2988" text="URIEL ERVIN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="3001" end="3005" text="UE24" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3031" end="3039" text="12/23/81" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="3098" end="3106" text="12/24/81" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="3122" end="3133" text="URIEL ERVIN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="3146" end="3150" text="UE24" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>