<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2085-06-13

EDVISIT^53718748^Johnson, Pepper^06/13/85^UMANA, BRUCE

The patient was seen by me along with Dr. Abbott on 06/13/2085. 

The history is documented by Dr. Abbott, was reviewed by me with

the patient, found to be accurate and complete.  The physical

exam was confirmed by my examination.  Evaluation and management

was also concurred with.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  In brief, this is a 56-year-old male

who enters with a history of after sitting playing a piano,

developed shortness of breath, had decreased ability to breathe. 

Says he had some diaphoresis this morning, dyspnea on exertion

which he has noted that he has been having repeated exertional

dyspnea over the past several days, worsening today when he had

diaphoresis accompanying with no chest pain but felt confused and

did not know where he is supposed to be going in the building until

he was overhead paged to report to specific room, when he looked

up 25 minutes had gone by and he was unaware of what had happened

during that time.  He has had some mild upper respiratory tract

infection about a week ago.  No nausea, no vomiting, no

dizziness, no abdominal pain, and the patient states that he is

feeling much better while he was being given some oxygen but just

feels like he has no energy.  The patient had a cardiac

catheterization in December of 2081 and had a luminal

irregularities and 30% stenosis and echocardiogram revealed 55%

ejection fraction.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  The patient has history of coronary

disease, MI, and hypercholesterolemia.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Smoked in the past for 30 years.  He is a

Senior Manager of Broadcasting by occupation.  Lives with his family.

Review of systems, allergies, and medications are as documented

in the chart.  Please see Dr. Abbott' notes for details.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Awake, alert, well-developed,

well-nourished male in mild distress.  Temperature 96.6, pulse

100, respirations 20, blood pressure 164/86.  Lungs clear. 

Cardiovascular:  Regular rate and rhythm.  Abdomen is flat,

nondistended, bowel sounds normoactive, nontender, no pedal

edema.

LABORATORY DATA:  White count 7.9, electrolytes are normal,

hematocrit 36.  CK was elevated at 657, troponin was negative. 

The patient's D-dimer was 211 and an EKG showed T-wave inversions

in aVL, V5 and V6 which ________ from previous chest x-ray was

negative.

DIAGNOSIS:  Acute coronary syndrome, rule out myocardial

infarction.

As such was admitted to Medicine on 06/13/2085.

______________________________

UMANA, BRUCE M.D.

D: 06/13/85

T: 06/13/85

Dictated By: UMANA, BRUCE

eScription document:9-2130535 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2085-06-13" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="53718748" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="60" text="Johnson, Pepper" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="61" end="69" text="06/13/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="70" end="82" text="UMANA, BRUCE" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="126" end="132" text="Abbott" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="136" end="146" text="06/13/2085" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="183" end="189" text="Abbott" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="420" end="422" text="56" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1358" end="1374" text="December of 2081" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P10" start="1639" end="1669" text="Senior Manager of Broadcasting" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="1805" end="1811" text="Abbott" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2517" end="2527" text="06/13/2085" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2562" end="2574" text="UMANA, BRUCE" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="2584" end="2592" text="06/13/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="2597" end="2605" text="06/13/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="2620" end="2632" text="UMANA, BRUCE" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P17" start="2654" end="2663" text="9-2130535" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>