<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2081-10-18

CCU JAR ADMIT NOTE



Patient Name: Jonathan Oswald

MRN:  4989555

Date of Admission: 10/18/81

Cardiology:  Xiang

CCU Attending:  Dennis Donnelly, M.D.





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: This is a 55 yr old male with cardiac risk factors of Hypertension, Type II DM, +FH, low HDL, and obesity who was in his USOH until yesterday morning when he developed 3/10 pain across his anterior chest while at rest that he describes as burning in quality with radiation into both jaws and through to his back.  The pain subsided without intervention after about 30 minutes.  He remained pain free until this morning when around 6:45 am, he again experienced this burning sensation in the same distribution.  He also felt nauseated and diaphoretic.  On the way to the hospital, the pain subsided.  He was pain free upon presentation to the ER, but developed chest pain briefly while in triage that had again disappeared by the time he was evaluated in Trauma.  He denies any SOB, fever, chills, or cough.  There was no positional component to his pain nor could he identify any relieving or exacerbating factors. 



HOSPITAL COURSE:

On presentation to the ER, the patient's BP was 155/83 HR 77 RR 20 T96.2 O2 sat 90%.  He was ASA 325mg po x 1, lopressor 5mg IV x 3 doses, IV TNG, a heparin bolus of 5000 and started on a drip at 1500 u/hr.  He was taken to the cath lab.



CATH DATA:  

RCA: clean

PDA with 60% distal occlusion

LM: clean

LAD: 95% stenosis after "huge" diagonal branch

Left CX: clean with large OMB 

Ramus: clean

LVEDP 15



PTCA of LAD and stent placed with "excellent" results. 





PMH:  

1.	Type II DM-last HGA1C 7.4 in 10/81

2.	Nephrotic Range Proteinuria (in setting of naprosyn)

3.	Obesity

4.	Hypertension

5.	Hereditary spherocytosis : s/p splenectomy at age 18 (pneumovax 12/2080)

6.	OSA; has been prescribed CPAP but not currently using

7.	DJD; bilateral knees

8.	Gout

9.	H/O nephrolithiasis

10.	S/P Pneumonia : 12/2078.

11.	Venous stasis; R>L secondary to old injury;



ALLERGIES:  

Keflex-hives



HOME MEDICATIONS:

NIFEDIPINE SR 30MG, 1 TabletPO QD

ENALAPRIL  20MG, 2 Tablets PO QD

FUROSEMIDE 40MG, 1 Tablets PO BID

DOXAZOSIN 8MG, 1 Tablet QD

ALLOPURINOL 300MG 1 Tablet QD



SOCIAL HISTORY:   Lives with his wife in Tornillo.  Does not currently smoke; social ETOH use. Admits to past history of recreational/illicit drug use.  Admits to past cocaine use and remote barbiturate, and "psychedelic use".  Last use of cocaine was 1-2 yrs ago; denies recent use.  He denies past marijuania use.  He is retired and previously ran an Italian restaurant. 

FH: Father with MI at age 48 and stroke in his 80's. Grandfather with MI at unknown age.



ROS:  

General:  denies fever, wt change, or night sweats

HEENT: no headaches, visual problems or dysphagia

CV:  see HPI

Respiratory:  no hemoptysis or sputum production

ABD: no diarrhea, constipation or melena

Neuro: no paralysis or seizures

End: no p/p/p/hot or cold intolerance

MS: no myalgias or arthralgias

HEME:  no epistaxis or gingival bleeding.

Physical Exam: 

Vital Signs: 

BP	123/64

HR	68-79

02 sat	99% on 2L

Temp	95



GENERAL:  morbidly obese gentleman in NAD

HEENT: PERRLA; EOMI; oropharynx moist with generous soft tissue.  JVP difficult to assess due to body habitus.  Carotid upstrokes 2+ without bruit.  

Chest: CTAB but distant

Heart: distant S1S2  

Abdomen:  obese +BS nt/nd; well-healed left sided scar from splenectomy

Extremities: 2+ DP, brachial, and radial pulses.  chronic venous stasis changes with 1+ edema to the knees.  Hematoma in the left antecubital fossa from sheath removal.  Sensation intact in forearm and hand.  

Neurological: CN II-XII.  MS 5/5 in bilateral upper and lower extremities.  Babinski downgoing bilaterally



DATABASE:



Sodium (Stat Lab)       137                      

Ptassium (Stat Lab)    3.6                      

Chloride (Stat Lab)     105                      

CO2 (Stat Lab)          28.5                     

BUN (Stat Lab)          25                       

Creatinine (Stat Lab)   1.2                      

Glucose (Stat Lab)      212       

Calcium                 9.6                      

Phosphorus              2.6                      

Magnesium               1.9                      

Total Protein           7.7                      

Albumin                 3.6                      

Globulin                4.1                      

Direct Bilirubin        0.2                      

Total Bilirubin         0.7

Transaminase-SGPT       27                       

Amylase                 294       

Lipase                  3.1                      

Transaminase-SGOT       22                       



WBC                     9.7                      

HCT                     46.

PLT                     471       

MCV                     86  

RDW                     14.0                     

Superstat PT            13.0                     11.1-13.1      sec

Superstat PT-INR        1.2

Superstat APTT          28.0                     22.1-35.1      sec

    

    Lipids: 

07-Feb-2081 



Triglycerides           78                       

Cholesterol             131                                     

High Density Lipoprotei 28        

Low Density Lipoprotein 87                                      

Cardiac Risk Ratio      4.7



Cardiac Enzymes:

			#1			#2			#3

CPK						60			72

CK-MB			neg			2.7

Troponin-T		neg			<0.01

	    





BNMC  CARDIAC ULTRASOUND   2080



MITRAL VALVE

  There is no evidence of mitral stenosis. There is no evidence of mitral

valve prolapse. There is no evidence of mitral regurgitation by color or

spectral Doppler.



LEFT ATRIUM

  The left atrium is dilated.



AORTIC VALVE, AORTA, LVOT

  There is no evidence of valvular aortic stenosis. The aortic valve is

tricuspid. There is no evidence of aortic insufficiency by color or spectral

Doppler. The aortic root appears dilated. The aortic diameter at the

sinotubular junction is 39 mm.



LEFT VENTRICLE

  The left ventricular size and systolic function are within normal limits.

There is symmetric left ventricular hypertrophy. There are no obvious

segmental wall motion abnormalities. The estimated ejection fraction is 69 %.



TRICUSPID VALVE - IVC, SVC

  The tricuspid valve appears normal.

PULMONARY VALVE, INFUND., P.A.

  The pulmonary valve appears normal.



RIGHT VENTRICLE

  The right ventricle is not dilated. The right ventricular systolic function

is within normal limits.



EKG:

EW:  NSR 78 with first degree AV block. PR 0.22. Q waves V1-V4. STE in V1-V6.  ST segment scooping in I and L.  1mm STE in II, III, F.  AVR with 1mm STD. 



CCU ADMIT:  NSR 61 with first degree AV block.  PR interval 0.22.  Q waves V1-V2.  STE V1-V5.  TW flattening 



CXR:

IMPRESSION:

	Clear lungs.

	The aorta is tortuous.  Detail of the lung is suboptimally to body

	habitus of the patient.  





Assesment and Plan: This is a 55 yr old male with cardiac risk factors of hypertension, DM, +FH, low HDL, and obesity who presents with anterior STEMI that was successfully treated with PCI to the LAD



Ischemia:



Treatment

 	ASA 325mg po qd

 	Plavix load then 75mg po qd

 	Continue Vasotec 20mg po qd

 	Initiate Lopressor at 12.5mg po tid and titrate as bp and pulse tolerates (monitor PR which was 0.22 on admit)

 	Lipitor 20mg po qd

 	Reopro for 12 hours

 	IV TNG prn bp control until oral regimen stable



Evaluation/Risk Factor Modification

 	Check homocysteine level

 	Re-check Fasting lipid profile

 	Will need extensive risk factor modication including wt loss, diabetes control, and exercise program



Rhythm:  

 	Routine peri-MI monitoring

 	Replete K and MG prn



Pump:

 	Last known EF 69% with no current signs of failure

 	Gently hydrate following cath

 	Will hold off on lasix (takes this at home for LE edema) while hydrating

 	BP control with Vasotec, Lopressor, TNG prn



OSA:  noncompliant at home with CPAP due to uncomfortable mask

 	Will ask respiratory therapy to initiate in-house and try to find comfortable mask

 	Continue education on importance of compliance with CPAP



DM

 	Check HGA1C

 	CZI for now.  Will gather data for 1-2 days.  

 	Will likely need outpatient treatment.  

 	Initiate oral med at discharge

 	Will need diabetes education



Prophylaxis: 

heparin SQ

Zantac 150mg po bid

 	 	 	 	 	 	 	 	



__________________________

Giselle Ulysses-Lyon, M.D.

Pager 16924









]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2081-10-18" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="64" end="79" text="Jonathan Oswald" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="87" end="94" text="4989555" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="115" end="123" text="10/18/81" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="138" end="143" text="Xiang" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="161" end="176" text="Dennis Donnelly" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="226" end="228" text="55" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="1669" end="1674" text="10/81" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="1815" end="1817" text="18" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1829" end="1836" text="12/2080" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1975" end="1982" text="12/2078" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P11" start="2291" end="2299" text="Tornillo" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P12" start="2603" end="2621" text="Italian restaurant" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<AGE id="P13" start="2651" end="2653" text="48" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P14" start="2672" end="2676" text="80's" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="5114" end="5125" text="07-Feb-2081" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P16" start="5488" end="5492" text="BNMC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="5515" end="5519" text="2080" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P18" start="6986" end="6988" text="55" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="8457" end="8477" text="Giselle Ulysses-Lyon" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P20" start="8491" end="8496" text="16924" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>