<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2088-09-14

LOVELAND INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Youngman, Cody
                                              06386371
                                              9-14-88
 
 
 
HPI:  Ms. Youngman is a 31 year old woman with a history of morbid obesity, 
complicated by diabetes, who was a former patient of Dr. Xitlali Crane.  
She comes in today for routine follow-up.  Patient's diabetes was 
initially diagnosed during gestation with her daughter.  Patient was 
formerly controlled by insulin but has lost 61 pounds over the last 16 
months and is now off all medications and states her finger sticks have 
been excellent with a peak of about 150, with most well below that.  
Patient also has a history of        in situ which was treated with laser 
treatment to the cervix.  She is a hemophiliac carrier.  Has a history of 
migraines and currently is being treated by Dr. Jacoby for depression.  
Since her last visit with Dr. Crane, patient apparently attempted suicide 
in July.  It is unclear how serious the attempt was although she did cut 
her left upper extremity.  Since then she states that she has been feeling 
a lot better and feels that she has really made progress with Dr. Jacoby.  
Her mood seems fine today in clinic.  Patient denies any medical symptoms 
at this time.
 
Patient's cardiac risk factors include smoking 5-6 cigarettes a day.  A 
positive family history of coronary artery disease including a mother who 
just died of a heart attack in May at age 53 and had had a previous MI at 
age 40 and a CABG at age 43.  Patient does not have hypercholesterolemia 
or hypertension but does have the diabetes history as noted above.
 
SOCIAL HISTORY:  Notable for tobacco use as noted above and she drinks 
about one beer per day when she is distraught that she continues to do.  
She says that she should not be drinking with her medications.
 
PHYSICAL EXAM:  Moderately obese Hispanic woman in no acute distress.  
Blood pressure: 120/70.  HEENT: unremarkable.  Neck: no JVD, carotids were 
2+ bilaterally without bruits.  Chest: clear.  Cardiac: within normal 
limits.  Abdomen: benign.  Extremities: without edema.
 
ASSESSMENT/PLAN:
1.   Weight control:  Patient has had excellent weight loss over the last 
     16 months.  I told her how impressed I was with this.  She, in fact, 
     does not require any oral hypoglycemics for good sugar control at 
     this time.  I will let her continue this dietary control for the next 
     six months and check her hemoglobin A1C at that time to assess her 
     control.  However, in the past, she has been very straight forward 
     with Dr. Crane according to her notes.
2.   Depression:  Patient continues to be actively depressed.  Is 
     currently on trazodone, Klonopin, Paxil and Motrin.  She will 
     continue to follow-up with Dr. Jacoby with whom she seems to be very 
     happy.
LOVELAND INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Youngman, Cody
Page 2                                        06386371
                                              9-14-88
 
 
 
3.   General health care:  Patient will need a pelvic exam in six months 
     time.  Patient currently has an intrauterine device which was placed 
     in June.  She does not take oral contraceptives because of her 
     history of diabetes and history of heart disease.  She was instructed 
     that she should go to Gynecological Clinic if any symptoms related to 
     the IUD occur.
4.   Diabetes:  Patient's blood sugars have had peaks of about 150 as 
     mentioned above.  I will check her hemoglobin A1C in six months time.  
     Patient feels good with no polydipsia, no urinary frequency and no 
     headache.  I elected, therefore, not to treat it at this time.  
     Patient was given prescriptions for fingersticks and lancets.
 
 
 
_________________________
Raymond Castaneda, M.D.
 
NW:ZR:8898
DD:9-14-88
DT:9-15-88
DV:9-14-88
 Attending Physician: YOCOM,GARY ZACHARY,M.D.




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2088-09-14" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="28" end="36" text="LOVELAND" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="75" end="89" text="Youngman, Cody" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="136" end="144" text="06386371" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="191" end="198" text="9-14-88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="215" end="223" text="Youngman" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="229" end="231" text="31" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="339" end="352" text="Xitlali Crane" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="906" end="912" text="Jacoby" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="961" end="966" text="Crane" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1009" end="1013" text="July" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="1222" end="1228" text="Jacoby" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="1502" end="1505" text="May" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P13" start="1513" end="1515" text="53" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P14" start="1550" end="1552" text="40" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P15" start="1571" end="1573" text="43" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="2651" end="2656" text="Crane" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="2852" end="2858" text="Jacoby" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P18" start="2903" end="2911" text="LOVELAND" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="2950" end="2964" text="Youngman, Cody" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P20" start="3011" end="3019" text="06386371" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="3066" end="3073" text="9-14-88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="3237" end="3241" text="June" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P23" start="3860" end="3877" text="Raymond Castaneda" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P24" start="3886" end="3896" text="NW:ZR:8898" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="3900" end="3907" text="9-14-88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="3911" end="3918" text="9-15-88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P27" start="3922" end="3929" text="9-14-88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P28" start="3952" end="3970" text="YOCOM,GARY ZACHARY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>