<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2087-10-19

LOVELAND INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Youngman, Cody
                                              06386371
                                              10-19-87
 
 
 
HPI:  Ms. Youngman is a 30-year-old woman with diabetes who comes in for a 
regular follow-up.
 
Assessment and Plan:
1.   Diabetes.  She said she has been doing well, sticking to her diet, 
     has had no hypoglycemic episodes, and that her fingersticks have been 
     ranging between 120 and 160, never above and never below.  This is 
     borne out by her last hemoglobin A1C on 6-04-87 which was 4.9.  She 
     definitely does have good control, and she is working hard as her weight 
     is down to 236 lb from 238.75 on 6-29-87.  She had a recent hemoglobin A1C 
     and urine dip.  She, however, is due for an eye exam as she has no had one 
     for over a year and is willing to go, so I referred her.  She also needs 
     to see a Podiatrist as she has not seen one; she will go.
 
2.   Health maintenance.  Patient does not want a flu shot.  Otherwise, 
     she is up to date except for a Pap smear, but she had her daughter 
     with her so asked if she could have her Pap smear on her next visit.  
     We will do so.
 
3.   Migraine headaches.  She said she has had one every day recently.  
     This is worse than her usual.  The Motrin was not helping.  I 
     therefore prescribed Midrin and explained to her expressly how to 
     use.  Should this not help, she will page me as she knows how to do.  
     I will see her back soon to make sure this is getting better.
 
4.   Ankle pain.  Patient has chronic ankle pain.  She went to an 
     Orthopedist who told her a while back to lose weight and see if it 
     got better.  She has been slowly losing weight with no improvement 
     and would like to go back to the Orthopedist.  I therefore referred 
     her at her request.
 
 
 
_________________________
Xitlali Crane, M.D. 
 
FS:XI:4842
DD:10-19-87
DT:10-20-87
DV:10-19-87
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2087-10-19" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="28" end="36" text="LOVELAND" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="75" end="89" text="Youngman, Cody" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="136" end="144" text="06386371" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="191" end="199" text="10-19-87" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="216" end="224" text="Youngman" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="230" end="232" text="30" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="591" end="598" text="6-04-87" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="737" end="744" text="6-29-87" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="1951" end="1964" text="Xitlali Crane" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P10" start="1974" end="1984" text="FS:XI:4842" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1988" end="1996" text="10-19-87" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2000" end="2008" text="10-20-87" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2012" end="2020" text="10-19-87" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>