<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2091-07-04







NAME:     Usrey, John  

MRN:        6762675



Patient presents for follow-up visit after long hospitalization. He went in to have an

AAA repair and suffered a postop MI. He was in CCU for 3-4 weeks at which time

he sustained a Pseudomonas pneumonia, small bowel obstruction, and PE. He

subsequently had his CABG done at the end of April and was discharged at the end

of May to Grant Clinic. He did well at Grant Clinic and was discharged

from there on the 10th of June, and he presents to me for follow-up today. 



He states that he feels well. He denies any chest pain or trouble breathing since

discharge. He does not remember anything from his hospitalization otherwise. He is

mentally intact. He reports that he has not had a bowel movement for 3 days and had

some pain a couple of days ago. He is passing gas, last done yesterday. No dysuria.

His daughter reports that he is eating well, that he is at his baseline mental status,

that he has had not had any acute complaints at home. 



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: As per HPI. Also, hypothyroidism, seizure disorder

due to a congenital AVM, osteoporosis, peripheral vascular disease.



ALLERGIES: No known drug allergies.



CURRENT MEDICATIONS: Aspirin 325 q.d., atenolol 25 b.i.d., Zocor 20 q.h.s.,

Carafate 1 gm p.o. b.i.d., Celexa 10 q.d., multivitamins, thiamine 100 q.d., Seroquel

37.5 q.h.s. and 12.5 q.a.m., Flomax 0.8 q.d., Synthroid 100 q.d., Dilantin 150 p.o. t.i.d.,

Colace 100 t.i.d. 



VITAL SIGNS: Blood pressure 112/52. Pulse 72. Weight 162. 



PHYSICAL EXAM: General - Elderly male in no acute distress. Appears well in

consideration of his recent long hospitalization. Neck - No JVD or bruits noted

bilaterally. Lungs - Clear to auscultation bilaterally with no wheezes or rales. CV -

RRR. Normal S1, S2. No murmurs. Abdomen - Positive bowel sounds heard in all 4

quadrants, although mildly decreased. Soft, mildly distended. No masses. No HSM.

No fluid wave. Extremities - He has 1+ firm pitting edema to his mid-shin. 



LABS: From June 13, 2091, show CBC with white count of 4.4, hemoglobin 11.2,

hematocrit 32.2. Chem 7 - BUN 26, creatinine 0.7, glucose 203, Dilantin 5.6. 



ASSESSMENT & PLAN: 76-year-old male, history of hypertension, hyperlipidemia,

coronary artery disease, peripheral vascular disease, status post CABG in April as

well as AAA repair returns after an extended hospitalization with complications of

pneumonia, SBO, and PE who comes in for follow-up visit. Despite everything,

patient looks well. 



(1)  CV. Will continue cardiac medications at this time. Will likely change Zocor

     back to Lipitor but will check his labs first. Patient would benefit from cardiac

     rehab at this time. He is scheduled to see Dr. Nutter at the end of this

     month. Will arrange for him to have regular cardiac care after this. He has

     seen Dr. Quesnel for his postop CABG issues.



(2)  PVD. Patient status post AAA repair. He has seen Dr. Uddin and is doing

     well. 



(3)  Neuro. Patient on Dilantin 150 t.i.d. as per Dr. Acuna. It would be okay to

     decrease him to 100 t.i.d. as he was before. Will check  his levels today but

     likely decrease to 100 t.i.d. Will refer back to Dr. Acuna for follow-up. 



(4)  Endocrine. Will check TSH. Likely will continue current Levoxyl dose.



(5)  Osteoporosis. Okay to restart Fosamax.



(6)  GI. Patient with constipation. He can start Citrucel or Metamucil twice a day.

     Can also use Dulcolax daily until he has a bowel movement and then decrease

     to every other day as needed. Can also adjust fiber therapy as needed.

     Instructed patient and daughter that if patient is passing gas, it is okay.

     However, if he stops, they should call immediately. 



(7)  Psych. They should continue Celexa and Seroquel for now. Will review charts

     from Grant Clinic to see why medications were started and will likely

     taper him off them.



In general, need to review records from Grant Clinic in order to see what

happened there. Will consider that in my recommendations for his further care.

Return to clinic in 2 weeks. 





Debra A. Rosenberg, M.D.



DAR/camp/quevedo







]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2091-07-04" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="44" end="55" text="Usrey, John" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="71" end="78" text="6762675" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="370" end="375" text="April" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="410" end="413" text="May" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="417" end="429" text="Grant Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="446" end="458" text="Grant Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="497" end="509" text="10th of June" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="2063" end="2076" text="June 13, 2091" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P9" start="2230" end="2232" text="76" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2364" end="2369" text="April" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2783" end="2789" text="Nutter" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2906" end="2913" text="Quesnel" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="3003" end="3008" text="Uddin" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="3092" end="3097" text="Acuna" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="3262" end="3267" text="Acuna" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P16" start="3891" end="3903" text="Grant Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P17" start="4025" end="4037" text="Grant Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="4175" end="4193" text="Debra A. Rosenberg" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="4203" end="4206" text="DAR" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="4207" end="4211" text="camp" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P21" start="4212" end="4219" text="quevedo" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>