<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2090-10-09



NAME:     Usrey, John 

MRN:       6762675



This is a 76-year-old man who comes in with a chief complaint of left calf pain. 

This occurs after walking about one block and pain is sufficient to prevent him

from walking further.  He will then stop, pain will disappear.  He will continue

walking at which time it will occur at about the same distance.  There is no rest

pain.  The pain had been present for a couple of months although it has been

increasing in severity.   



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Is significant for intracranial bleed secondary to an

AV malformation.  He refused surgery at that time at Campellton-Graceville Hospital and has done

well on Dilantin without any seizures.  There has been no further bleed or problem

from this malformation.  He also has treated hypothyroidism.  He is status post

TURP, cholecystectomy, and appendectomy.  He does have a chronic anxiety

disorder for which he is on Ativan intermittently.  He also has pustular psoriasis.



MEDICATIONS:  Dilantin 600 mg per day, which keeps his level at about 7.  At

these levels he has had no seizures.  He is also on Synthroid at 0.075 per day.  



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He is a mostly German-speaking man.  There is a

right-sided tremor which has been present since his intracranial bleed.  Neck

supple.  Blood pressure is at 140/80.  Weight 184.  Heart rate is at 70.  There are

no carotid bruits.  Lungs are clear.  Heart is regular without gallop or murmur. 

Abdominal exam - No mass, tenderness, or organomegaly.  There are multiple

scars. There is a bruit over the right femoral artery with a decreased pulsation there

compared to the left.  There is no pulse palpable below popliteal on the right side. 

There is no visible ischemic change of the right leg.  The left femoral is fuller, and

there is a palpable dorsalis pedis on that side.  



IMPRESSION:  Peripheral vascular disease, probably right iliofemoral.  He will

undergo arteriovascular studies.  He will also be placed on aspirin at 81 mg per

day.  In addition he is begun on Lipitor 10 mg per day for hyperlipidemia.  He will

follow up following that vascular study.  This evaluation was also communicated to

her daughter, Quinn, because of the language barrier.





Xenia Jaramillo, M.D.



XJ/camp/williams









]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2090-10-09" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="40" end="51" text="Usrey, John" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="65" end="72" text="6762675" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<AGE id="P3" start="86" end="88" text="76" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="644" end="674" text="Campellton-Graceville Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="1216" end="1222" text="German" TYPE="COUNTRY" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="2235" end="2240" text="Quinn" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="2280" end="2295" text="Xenia Jaramillo" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="2305" end="2307" text="XJ" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2308" end="2312" text="camp" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2313" end="2321" text="williams" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>