<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2066-06-17

SDU JAR Admit Note



Name:	Rivers, Ida	

MR: 468 48 69	

Date of Admission: 06/17/66



Cardiologist: Valdivia



CC: 73 yo woman with h/o Sjogren's syndrome, Diabetes (?Type I), vascular insufficiency who now presents with syncopal episode.

		

HPI:  Ms Rivers was in her USOH until the morning of admission, when she went into the city to buy some buttons and pay a bill at ViewSonic.  She noted that she was not feeling well throughout the morning, and she felt as if she may need to eat something.  However, because she did not have her insulin and blood sugar monitoring equipment, she decided not to eat.  She continued to feel poorly (she is somewhat vague on symptoms but reports feeling that her chest was congested and that she may have had some palpitations and felt chilled).  She saw a police cruiser, and walked over to it with the intention of getting help.  When she arrived, there was no one in the car, and she leaned forward to rest her head on the front of the car.  This is the last thing she remembered; when she awoke, she was surrounded by people.  She was told that she had falled backwards and hit the back of her head.  When EMS found her, she was confused, making repetitive statements, and stating that she had pain in her occiput that radiated down her neck.  When she arrived at the FMH ED, her blood pressure was 213/97 HR 84 RR20 O2 sat 99% RA Temp 97.3.  She received Labetolol 20 iv, Toradol 30 mg iv, ASA 325 mg and Tylenol 1000 mg po x 1.  Her mental status cleared somewhat, and her blood pressure came down to 130s/80s.  She did have one episode of emesis, during which her HR was noted to transiently dip to the 40s (not captured on the monitor); spontaneously recovered to the 60s.

She had a C-spine series and head CT which were negative for acute process, and a CXR which was negative except for R shoulder not well-visualized on CXR.  She was noted to have some superficial bleeding of her posterior scalp, but no obvious laceration.  She was admitted to the SDU because of the episode of bradycardia.



PMH/PSH 

-Diabetes Type I (by her report) followed at Hometown Medical

-Sjogren's disease, followed by Dr Vidal at RGH

-Pseudogout

-s/p benign breast mass resection 11 yrs ago.

-? Peripheral vascular disease?



Meds:  

Insulin: Lantus 9-10 U qhs, Humalog sliding scale.

ASA prn

Colchicine prn



All: 

PCN



SH:  

Lives alone in Las Vegas with her cat.  Her daughter lives in Cheboygan.  Remote h/o smoking, no EtOH or drugs.



FH:	

Unable to obtain



Exam:  	VS:   BP 152/76  HR 77 O2 sat 99-100% RA

	HEENT: posterior occiput with areas of oozing, no laceration or active bleeding, R pupil surgical, L reactive, nonicteric.  EOMI.  OP w/ dry mms, w/o exudates.

	Neck:  	supple, NT, full ROM, no LAD, JVP at 8 cm

	Lungs:  	CTA B

	Cor:  	Regular nml  S1S2, soft 2/6 SEM.

	Abd:  	soft, non-tender, with BS

	Extr:  	wwwp, no c/c, 2+ PP UE/LE, no edema.  R shoulder minimally tender, ROM preserved.

	Neuro: 	AAOX3, MS nl, CN II-XII grossly intact, Motor 5/5 UE/LE, Sensory gross intact. No nystagmus.



	

DATA:	



Sodium (Stat Lab)      139                       135-145        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)   3.9                       3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)    108                       100-108        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)         25.5                      23.0-31.9      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)         17                        8-25           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)  0.8                       0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)     155        H              70-110         mg/dl



Calcium                10.6       H              8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus             2.4        L              2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium              1.6                       1.4-2.0        meq/L

Total Protein          8.1                       6.0-8.3        g/dl

Albumin                3.7                       3.3-5.0        g/dl

Globulin               4.4        H              2.6-4.1        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin       0.2                       0-0.4          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin        0.5                       0-1.0          mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase   125        H              30-100         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT      24                        7-30           U/L

Amylase                58                        3-100          units/L

Lipase                 2.3                       1.3-6.0        U/dl

Transaminase-SGOT      28                        9-32           U/L



Creatine Kinase Isoenz NEGATIVE                  NEG

Troponin-I             NEGATIVE                  NEG



WBC                    5.2                       4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                    39.5                      36.0-46.0      %

HGB                    12.1                      12.0-16.0      gm/dl

RBC                    5.44       H              4.00-5.20      mil/cmm

PLT                    138        L              150-350        th/cumm

MCV                    73         L              80-100         fl

MCH                    22.2       L              26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                   30.5       L              31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                    13.8                      11.5-14.5      %

Superstat PT           11.9                      11.1-13.1      sec

Superstat PT-INR       0.9

  Result Text:

     PT-INR values are valid only for WARFARIN ANTI-COAG THERAPY.

Superstat APTT         21.1       L              22.1-35.1      sec

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST   RECEIVED

Diff Method            Manual

Poly                   43                        40-70          %

Bands                  3                         0-10           %

Lymphs                 47         H              22-44          %

Monos                  5                         4-11           %

EOS                    1                         0-8            %

Basos                  1                         0-3            %



UA-Specific Gravity    1.010                     1.001-1.035

UA-pH                  7.0                       5.0-9.0

UA-WBC Screen          NEGATIVE                  NEG

UA-Nitrite             NEGATIVE                  NEG

UA-Albumin             NEGATIVE                  NEG

UA-Glucose             2+                        NEG

UA-Ketones             NEGATIVE                  NEG

UA-Occult Blood                                  NEG

 

CXR:  

IMPRESSION:

	1.  No active disease seen in the chest.

	2. Mild degenerative change of the right acromioclavicular joint

	is noted.   Limited evaluation of the shoulder demonstrates no

	other significant abnormality. Dedicated shoulder imaging is

	recommended as clinically indicated.



C-spine films:

IMPRESSION:

	NO EVIDENCE FOR CERVICAL SPINE FRACTURE OR DISLOCATION.

	MULTILEVEL DEGENERATIVE CHANGES, MOST SEVERE AT C5-6 AND C6-7.

	

Head CT:

IMPRESSION:

	No evidence of an acute intracranial process.  Ventricular

	dilatation that may be mildly out of proportion to sulcal

	enlargement.



EKG: 

NSR rate 74, J-point elevation V2

____________________________________________



Impression: 

73 yo woman with h/o Sjogren's disease, ?Type I DM now admitted with syncopal event.  DDx includes hypoglycemia, seizure (unlikely), vasovagal episode, arrythmia or ischemia.



Plan: 	

1.Cardiac

Ischemia: Continue ASA, B blocker as tolerated for elevated BP.  Cycle enzymes, monitor EKG for new changes.

Pump: Echo today to assess function, r/o valvular disease or outflow obstruction.

Rhythm: In NSR, continue on monitor to assess for arrythmia.



2. Respiratory: ED CXR shows no significant pulmonary disease.  



3. Endocrine: will continue her home Lantus and use CZI Regular.  Will need to contact HMC re: her care. If she is Type I diabetic, will need basal insulin.  No evidence of DKA on urine or labs.  Check TSH, Hgbaic.



4.  Rheum: h/o Sjogrens, extent of her disease unclear.  Will contact her rheumatologist at RGH.  Consider dedicated R shoulder xray once rules out to assess for possible fx, particularly if pain persists.



5.  Neuro: imaging negative.  She is slow in her responses; monitor closely for evolving neuro sx.

  

6.  GU: Follow urine output.



7.  ID: Afebrile. Normal WBC



8. Hem: HCT stable.  Follow closely



9. F/E/N: replete magnesium, K prn.



10. Prophylaxis: nexium.







_________________________________

Rose Anaya, MD

Pager #76979









]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2066-06-17" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="56" end="67" text="Rivers, Ida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="74" end="83" text="468 48 69" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="105" end="113" text="06/17/66" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="131" end="139" text="Valdivia" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="147" end="149" text="73" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="285" end="291" text="Rivers" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="406" end="415" text="ViewSonic" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="1344" end="1347" text="FMH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P9" start="2135" end="2151" text="Hometown Medical" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2188" end="2193" text="Vidal" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P11" start="2197" end="2200" text="RGH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P12" start="2421" end="2430" text="Las Vegas" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P13" start="2468" end="2477" text="Cheboygan" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<AGE id="P14" start="7162" end="7164" text="73" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P15" start="7772" end="7775" text="HMC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P16" start="7995" end="7998" text="RGH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="8425" end="8435" text="Rose Anaya" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P18" start="8448" end="8453" text="76979" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>