<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2077-03-12









March 12, 2077



Urijah Whaley, M.D.
266 Bungalow Ave
Crystal Springs, MO 37319

RE:  Otis Narvaez
     MR #045-61-32-6

Dear Uddin:

Otis Narvaez is a 67 year old man who returned to the office today for follow-up after having
undergone an Adenosine PET scan on March 04, 2077.  His previous visit with me occurred on
February 19, 2077, where his acute complaint was shortness of breath with any activity.  He
denied chest pain, but did admit to a "tight" feeling down his left arm on occasion.  This was not
associated with activity.  He admits to being a very sedentary person.  

The results of his Adenosine MIBI were abnormal, with abnormal myocardial perfusion, global
LV function, and CT coronary angiography.  There were no significant findings on the clinical
evaluation.  The response was non-ischemic, and there were no EKG changes during infusion. 
The results revealed a small calcified plaque in the proximal LAD coronary artery without flow-
limiting stenosis.  There was a more heavily calcified plaque visualized in the distal RCA which
was flow-limiting, and there was a moderate amount of stress-induced ischemia on imaging. 
There was severe left ventricular systolic dysfunction with an ejection fraction of 32%.  The
narrowing in the distal segment of the RCA was greater than 70%.  

A lipid profile performed following his office visit on February 19, 2077 revealed a total
cholesterol of 182 mg/dl, an HDL of 43 mg/dl, an LDL of 71 mg/dl, and a triglyceride level of
342 mg/dl.  He has not been on any cholesterol-lowering medications.  

He had undergone previous cardiac catheterization in November 2072, which demonstrated
insignificant coronary artery disease, with an ejection fraction of 63%.

Since his last office visit, he continues to be significantly short of breath with any activity.  He
denies any chest pain or left arm discomfort.  

His current medications include Ritalin 20 mg five times daily, Ambien 10 mg at hour of sleep,
Neurontin 900 mg three times daily, Lasix 20 mg every other day, Lisinopril 60 mg once daily, 
Otis Narvaez
MR #045-61-32-6
Page 2
March 12, 2077
 
aspirin 325 mg with Oxycodone as needed.  He usually takes these once every other day.  He is
now on 20 units of an insulin preparation that he cannot identify.  He takes this at bedtime.

Review of systems reveals that he has chronic peripheral neuropathy in his feet.  This causes him
to feel imbalanced, and it is necessary for him to walk with a cane.

He was diagnosed with diabetes in 2068 and hypertension in 2067.  He also has chronic low
back pain due to degenerative joint disease, as well as lumbar disc disease.  He also has
degenerative joint disease in his knees.  He receives psychiatric follow-up for his diagnosis of
depression.  

He underwent a gastric bypass procedure at Harmon Medical Rehabilitation Hospital in 2068.

On January 20, 2073, he underwent a left lingular-sparing upper lobectomy for a T1 squamous
cell carcinoma.  

On physical examination, he appears healthy, albeit overweight, with a normal affect.  His
weight is 208 lbs, the heart rate is 84 beats per minute, the respiratory rate is 16 per minute, and
the blood pressure is 140/62 mm/Hg.  Examination of the head, eyes, ears, nose, and throat
reveals upper dentures in place.  There is no jugular vein distention, and the lungs are clear. 
There is increased AP diameter with bilateral gynecomastia.  On cardiac examination, the heart
sounds are distant, and there is a regular rhythm, a normal S1, a single S2, and no murmurs,
rubs, or gallops.  The lower extremity examination reveals a 2 cm tender superficial area on the
distal right calf.  There is no edema noted.

I discussed with Otis Narvaez and his wife, Santiago, my recommendations for a cardiac
catheterization followed by stent placement, as indicated.  He has agreed to this, and Dr. Yaziel
Kraft will perform the procedure.  His office will call Mr. Narvaez to schedule the
catheterization.  After leaving the office today, he will have a CBC, a PT, a PTT, and a
comprehensive metabolic profile performed.  He will return to see me in the office again in one
month.

Best personal regards.

Sincerely,


Kenneth Z. Sellers, M.D.
/huff


Charlene B. Bates, RN, BSN
Scribe for Kenneth Z. Sellers, M.D.




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2077-03-12" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="36" end="50" text="March 12, 2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="54" end="67" text="Urijah Whaley" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="74" end="90" text="266 Bungalow Ave" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="91" end="106" text="Crystal Springs" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="108" end="110" text="MO" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="111" end="116" text="37319" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="123" end="135" text="Otis Narvaez" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="145" end="156" text="045-61-32-6" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="163" end="168" text="Uddin" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="171" end="183" text="Otis Narvaez" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P11" start="189" end="191" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="300" end="314" text="March 04, 2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="356" end="373" text="February 19, 2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="1401" end="1418" text="February 19, 2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="1655" end="1668" text="November 2072" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="2103" end="2115" text="Otis Narvaez" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P17" start="2120" end="2131" text="045-61-32-6" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="2139" end="2153" text="March 12, 2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="2547" end="2551" text="2068" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="2572" end="2576" text="2067" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P21" start="2848" end="2886" text="Harmon Medical Rehabilitation Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="2890" end="2894" text="2068" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="2900" end="2916" text="January 20, 2073" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P24" start="3736" end="3748" text="Otis Narvaez" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P25" start="3763" end="3771" text="Santiago" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<PHI id="P26" start="3897" end="3909" text="Yaziel
Kraft" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P27" start="3964" end="3971" text="Narvaez" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P28" start="4218" end="4236" text="Kenneth Z. Sellers" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P29" start="4244" end="4248" text="huff" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P30" start="4251" end="4268" text="Charlene B. Bates" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P31" start="4289" end="4307" text="Kenneth Z. Sellers" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>