<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2073-02-03

                     SOUT SIDE EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

NARVAEZ,OTIS   045-61-32-6                      VISIT DATE: 02/03/73

The patient was seen with the medical resident.  This is a brief 

addendum to the chart.  I have discussed management with the 

internal medicine resident who saw the patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Briefly, this is a gentleman who 

is status post lung surgery who complains of feeling weak, with 

mild shortness of breath and fevers over the last couple of days.  

He has noted some drainage and redness of his surgical site on the 

left side.  He has had no headache, chest pain, abdominal pain.  He 

has had mildly loose stools and felt weak and somewhat 

light-headed.  His wife reports that he had been confused overnight 

after taking his medications.  The patient states that this 

happened last night and has now resolved. 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As documented.

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  As documented.  The patient is 

a past smoker.  He has a family history of MI.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL APPEARANCE:  The patient is mildly 

uncomfortable, in no acute distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Blood pressure 

is 170/70, respiratory rate 18, pulse initially of 112, temperature 

101.5.  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  NECK:  Supple.  CHEST:  

Clear.  Slightly dull on the left side.  He has superficial redness 

along the surgical incision site with drainage.  HEART:  Regular 

rate.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, nontender.  EXTREMITIES:  Nontender.  

NEUROLOGIC:  He is oriented x 4 and appropriate, with a normal 

neurologic exam.

CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  CT surgery has been consulted.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  This is a gentleman with fever and drainage from 

his surgical site.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient will 

be admitted for IV antibiotics.  A CT of the chest is pending at 

the time of this dictation.  Condition on admission is stable. 

___________________________________                    OP274/66298 

BRIAN YOCKEY, M.D.  BY01                                 D:02/03/73 

                                                       T:02/04/73 

Dictated by:  BRIAN YOCKEY, M.D.  BY01 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2073-02-03" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="58" text="SOUT SIDE" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="84" end="96" text="NARVAEZ,OTIS" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="99" end="110" text="045-61-32-6" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="144" end="152" text="02/03/73" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P5" start="2035" end="2046" text="OP274/66298" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="2049" end="2061" text="BRIAN YOCKEY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="2069" end="2073" text="BY01" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="2108" end="2116" text="02/03/73" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2176" end="2184" text="02/04/73" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2201" end="2213" text="BRIAN YOCKEY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2221" end="2225" text="BY01" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>