<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2077-10-05

EDVISIT^04561326^NARVAEZ, OTIS^10/05/77^THORNE, OLIVER

The patient was seen by me on 10/05/2077 with Dr. Bender. 

Resident's history was reviewed.  The patient was interviewed and

examined by me.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 68-year-old man

recently diagnosed with diverticulitis, treated with

ciprofloxacin and Flagyl.  He has had abdominal pain for the past

4 days, and was discharged from the hospital.  He complains of

left flank pain.  He has no abdominal pain.  Pain is colic in

nature.  See resident's note for details.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diverticulosis, diabetes, gastric bypass,

and coronary artery disease.

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Cipro and Flagyl.  See resident's note for

details.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He denies drugs or alcohol.  He denies cigarette

smoking.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  No chest pain, no shortness of breath, and no

fever.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Temperature 99, blood pressure 153/118,

pulse 93, respirations 18, and O2 saturation 98% on room air. 

HEENT:  Normocephalic and atraumatic.  Pupils are equal, round,

and reactive to light.  Extraocular muscles are intact.  Neck is

supple.  No meningeal signs.  CV:  Regular rate and rhythm. 

Lungs:  Clear.  Abdomen:  Positive bowel sounds, soft, and

nontender to palpation.  Back:  No CVAT.  Extremities:  No

cyanosis, clubbing, or edema.  Neurologic:  Alert and oriented

x3.  Cranial nerves are intact.  Motor and sensory are intact.

LABORATORY DATA:  Whit e count 8.8, hematocrit 44, and platelets

216,000.  Creatinine 1.7 and glucose 103.  Urinalysis is pending.

 Abdominal CT scan evaluated from 10/01/2077 reveals a 6 x 8 mm

stone in the left ureter, hydronephrosis, and adjacent stranding.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient in the Emergency

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

pain with stable vital signs.  He was seen by Urology.  He will

be admitted to the Urology Service for further management.

DIAGNOSIS:  Renal colic kidney stone.

______________________________

THORNE, OLIVER M.D.

D: 10/05/77

T: 10/06/77

Dictated By: THORNE, OLIVER

eScription document:0-1032417 BFFocus





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2077-10-05" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="04561326" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="58" text="NARVAEZ, OTIS" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="59" end="67" text="10/05/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="68" end="82" text="THORNE, OLIVER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="114" end="124" text="10/05/2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="134" end="140" text="Bender" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="274" end="276" text="68" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="1680" end="1690" text="10/01/2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2090" end="2104" text="THORNE, OLIVER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2114" end="2122" text="10/05/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2127" end="2135" text="10/06/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2150" end="2164" text="THORNE, OLIVER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P13" start="2186" end="2195" text="0-1032417" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>