<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2095-04-22

EDVISIT^93295529^OSTRANDER, BILL^04/22/95^OXENDINE, LAWRENCE

Seen and evaluated with resident, Dr. Castro.  I have reviewed

her note and assessment and plan, and I agree.  I have seen and

evaluated the patient myself.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 68-year-old

gentleman with past medical history of alcoholism, as well as

depression.  He has had a small-bowel obstruction in the past as

well as CABG x2, PTSD, and high cholesterol, now presenting to

the Emergency Room in the setting of having been separated from

his girlfriend of 15 years secondary to his excessive alcohol use

and drinking very heavily over the last week.  He was found in a

bar intoxicated, and upon EMS arrival stated that he wanted help

with his drinking problem as well as the fact that he was

depressed without any SI or HI.  He is also stating that he has

not taken any food in the last week, just alcohol.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  He is denying any chest pain, shortness of

breath, any nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, any headache or blurred

vision or any fall or trauma.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As above.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  As above.

MEDICATIONS:  He is on unknown medications.

ALLERGIES:  No known allergies.

ALLERGIES:  Current heavy alcohol use.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Does smoke cigarettes, but does not use illicit

drugs.  He is a retired transporation manager, and he was previously

living with his girlfriend, but has now been living alone for the

last week.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  When he presented, he had a heart rate of

65, respiratory rate of 16, BP of 150/79, and saturating 99% on

room air.  He was afebrile at 96.7.  He was alert, interactive,

appropriate, somewhat slurred speech, but gave a good history of

signs and symptoms.  HEENT exam:  He is nonicteric with dry

mucous membranes.  Heart was regular rhythm, no murmurs.  Lungs

were clear to auscultation bilaterally.  Abdomen was soft and

minimally diffusely tender.  He had no evidence of trauma and

pain to palpation in his extremities.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  This is a patient with severe alcohol

abuse, now presenting in the setting of an alcohol binge with no

p.o. food intake.  We did send laboratory studies notable for an

elevated white count of 9 as well as hyponatremia at 124, down

from 135 previously.  Please see the resident note for full

details.  His alcohol level was 277.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  We did treat the patient with IV

fluid as well as D5.  We did give him a p.o. diet here in the

Emergency Department and we monitored him for withdrawal signs. 

In addition, we contacted social work for help with his alcohol

dependence/abuse, and he will be admitted to the Ochsner for

further management of his hyponatremia as well as his alcohol

abuse.  We also treated him with multivitamins.

DIAGNOSES:

1.  Alcohol intoxication

2.  Alcohol dependence

3.  Depression.

4.  Hyponatremia.

______________________________

OXENDINE, LAWRENCE MD

D: 04/22/95

T: 04/22/95

Dictated By: OXENDINE, LAWRENCE

eScription document:1-81539559 HFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2095-04-22" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="93295529" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="60" text="OSTRANDER, BILL" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="61" end="69" text="04/22/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="70" end="88" text="OXENDINE, LAWRENCE" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="128" end="134" text="Castro" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="296" end="298" text="68" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P7" start="1379" end="1400" text="transporation manager" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="2720" end="2727" text="Ochsner" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2975" end="2993" text="OXENDINE, LAWRENCE" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="3001" end="3009" text="04/22/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3014" end="3022" text="04/22/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="3037" end="3055" text="OXENDINE, LAWRENCE" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P13" start="3077" end="3087" text="1-81539559" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>