<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2085-04-22

 
This patient wants to transfer his care from the McCook Erie Clinic to me. He 
got 
my name from a nurse who works in the hospital.  HE is a 58 year old white 
male retired Transportation Manager with a number of issues.  
1)  He had a cyst or a mass enlarge in his R submental region which was 
excised 
at the McCook Erie Clinic.  Note from his surgeon there said the path showed 
nonkaziating granuloma.  I hope cultures are pending.  The patient does 
volunteer at a homeless shelter so could  certainly be exposed to TB or 
atypical mycobacteria.  
2)  The patient has know mitral valve prolapse, mitral regurgitation followed 
at the MEC by a cardiologist. He had a stress test in the last year that was 
benign. Never had CHF or endocarditis.  
3)  Social situation.  The patient is a sober alcoholic and sober for the 
last 
2 years however he went through divorce probably because of his alcoholism 
10 years ago and took early retirement from Brookdale Metro Systems because 
of his alcoholism. He stays sober by going to meetings and also 
volunteering at the McCook Clinic. He lives with a woman. He has good 
relations with his grown children and his grand children.  His woman friend 
is very supportive and the patient is now feeling good enough about himself 
that he is ready to try and get work full time.  Previous attempts to do so 
have resulted in failure because of his Hx of alcoholism and his premature 
retirement.
 
Family Hx. Father died at age 79 of Altzheimers and some kind of cancer ? 
throat cancer.  His mother had diabetes and coronary artery disease and she 
died of colon cancer. The patient himself had a colonoscopy within the last 
year and it was normal.  One brother and 2 sisters, one of the sisters also 
has mitral valve disease. 
 
Past medical Hx the alcoholism and he was stabbed in the L hand I think in 
2059 and that was repaired. He also had a TNA in childhood. 
 
He has no known allergies to medications.
 
The only medication he takes is Lisinopril 5 mg for blood pressure. He was 
only started on this in the last year. He also takes a vitamin a day.
 
His other significant medical complaint is erectile dysfunction.  He has 
normal libido and good sexual drive however he tends to lose erection after 
he 
has gone for a few minutes.  He can achieve vaginal penetration.  His live in 
lover has been supportive but she would like him to have better performance 
and so would he. He does wake up in the morning frequently with erections. He 
has no known Hx of diabetes.  No prolonged hypertension or vascular disease.  
 
Social Hx.  The patient eats fairly well. He walks usually a mile or so a 
day.  
He does not do any aerobic activity. He does smoke  to a pack a day and has 
for many, many years.  He does wear seat belts when he drives and does not do 
any elicit drugs.  On system review:  Weight stable.  No change in skin. He 
always had a very gravelly voice.  He has had no change in his vision. He is 
very deaf in the L ear.  He has a morning cough no hemoptysis.  Cough is 
about 
a teaspoon of white/gray sputum. He has no dyspnea on exertion.  He has no 
angina.  No palpitations.  No presyncope or syncope.  NO claudication. He has 
no dysphagia. He has no epigastric discomfort.  No change in his bowel 
movements and no rectal bleeding.  He has no claudication.  No edema and no 
joint pains. No headaches and no low back pain.  No long bone pain.  He has 
no 
heat or cold intolerance.  He has no easy bruisability.  
 
PE: shows him to 5'7".  155 lbs.  Skin benign.  Nails do show some early 
clubbing. No cyanosis.  Normal no AV knicking.  Flat disks. Pupils equally 
round and reactive to light and accommodation at 3 mm. Nares normal.  TMs 
normal. Hearing is markedly diminished in the L ear. Head is normal cephalic. 
Thyroid not enlarged.  There is the scar at the site of his excision under 
the 
mandible. No associated adenopathy on either R or L neck or axilla or the 
supraclavicular region.  He is hyperesonant to percussion.  He has distant 
breath sounds. No rales, rhonchi or wheezes. He has normal S1.  Normal S2 and 
holosystolic blowing 2-3/6 mid systolic murmur radiates best to the axilla. 
No 
radiation to the clavicles. No carotid bruits.  Jugular venous pulsation to 7 
sonometers. Abdomen is soft and non tender. There is no enlargement of the 
liver. No adeventitious masses. There is a L inguinal weakness without frank 
hernia.  Phallus uncircumsized. Testes normal. Prostate is a little difficult 
feel because he has a band around the anal sphincter which makes it difficult 
for me to get beyond but I felt probably half of his prostate and it was 
normal and smooth. Stool was guac negative. Reflexes 3+ and equal throughout 
and normal vibratory sense and touch. Normal gait and station.
 
Assessment and Plan:
 
1)  Recent rapidly growing mass under the R mandible showing nonkaziating 
granuloma.  Culture is pending and we will plant a PPD and control early 
next week. I will have him tracked down the report of this from the MEC and 
get culture reports and will get chest x-ray today both for his COPD to 
rule out a cavitary lesion.  
2)  Alcoholism now sober.
3)  Erectile dysfunction try Viagra. He was given appropriate warnings and 
instructions.  I gave him 100 mg # 7.  
4)  Mitral valve prolapse by auscultation followed by cardiologist at the MEC.
5)  We spent a long time talking about smoking cessation.  He has some 
Wellbutrin at home from when he was depressed while getting sober and I 
encouraged him to take 150 b.i.d. and we made a plan for him to try and 
quit.   I will see patient again next week to plant a PPD and then see him 
again in about a month to see how he is doing.  We will certainly check the 
chest x-ray to make sure he did not have active cavitary disease.
 
Leroy X. Oshea, M.D.
 
 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2085-04-22" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="79" end="97" text="McCook Erie Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P2" start="171" end="173" text="58" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P3" start="203" end="225" text="Transportation Manager" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="342" end="360" text="McCook Erie Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="670" end="673" text="MEC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="983" end="1006" text="Brookdale Metro Systems" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="1101" end="1114" text="McCook Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="1503" end="1505" text="79" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1884" end="1888" text="2059" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="5073" end="5076" text="MEC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P11" start="5401" end="5404" text="MEC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="5845" end="5859" text="Leroy X. Oshea" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>