<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2096-04-10

                     GLENN HELEN EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
VINCENT,ROBERTA J.   380-18-32-2
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 59-year-old 
female who is status post renal transplant with history of 
hypertension and diabetes who presents complaining of recurrent 
shortness of breath.  She had a renal transplant in 2093 with 
history of chronic renal insufficiency.  She was last admitted here 
on February 23 for shortness of breath.  The patient has had sore 
throat and URI symptoms now for a few days.  No nausea and 
vomiting.  No sweating.  No chest pain or dizziness. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Complicated by hypertension, diabetes, pedal 
neuropathy, hernia, and hysterectomy. 
MEDICATIONS:  Premarin, insulin, Prilosec, prednisone, and sodium 
bicarbonate.  She is also on Lasix, hydralazine, and Talwin. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is afebrile.  Vital signs are normal. 
Oxygen saturation 97%.  Initial blood pressure is 214/118.  The 
second blood pressure is 188/100.  HEENT:  Normal.  Cardiac:  No 
murmurs or rubs.  Lungs:  Crackles bilaterally, but no wheezing. 
Abdomen:  Soft and nontender with good bowel sounds.  Extremities: 
Trace pedal edema 1+ throughout.  Neuro:  Intact. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Electrolytes here are normal.  Creatinine 
is pretty good.  She was 4.4 on February 26.  She is 3.3 now, so 
she has improved in creatinine.  White count is 12.9 and hematocrit 
of 36.  EKG showed sinus rhythm at 97, old left ventricular 
hypertrophy, and no acute changes.  Chest x-ray shows increased 
chronic pulmonary edema and old small right pleural fluid seen. 
CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  The Renal fellow is here.  The case 
has been discussed with the Renal fellow. 
ADMITTING DIAGNOSIS:  Congestive heart failure and hypertension. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 
going to be admitted to the Renal Service, admitted to Dr. Elias 
Mercado.  Admitted in stable condition. 
___________________________________                    VC341/8846 
DEXTER N. JOHNSON, M.D.  DJ50                             D:04/10/96 
                                                       T:04/10/96 
Dictated by:  DEXTER N. JOHNSON, M.D.  DJ50 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2096-04-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="60" text="GLENN HELEN" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="84" end="102" text="VINCENT,ROBERTA J." TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="105" end="116" text="380-18-32-2" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<AGE id="P4" start="168" end="170" text="59" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="358" end="362" text="2093" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="441" end="452" text="February 23" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="1337" end="1348" text="February 26" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PHI id="P8" start="1935" end="1949" text="Elias 
Mercado" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P9" start="2038" end="2048" text="VC341/8846" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2050" end="2067" text="DEXTER N. JOHNSON" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2075" end="2079" text="DJ50" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2110" end="2118" text="04/10/96" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2177" end="2185" text="04/10/96" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="2201" end="2218" text="DEXTER N. JOHNSON" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="2226" end="2230" text="DJ50" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>