<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2065-02-04

TRIBAL INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Hart, Matthew
                                              46103196
                                              2-4-65
 
 
 
HPI:  The patient is a 41 year old man with a history of non-insulin 
dependent diabetes, hypertension, obesity and substance abuse who I 
learned today was recently admitted for deep venous thrombosis and is 
presenting for follow up of his DVT.  The patient's current medical 
problems include:
1.   Recent DVT.  The patient was admitted between the days of 1-24 and 
     1-30 secondary to the development of a right lower extremity DVT.  
     The patient told me that he had been doing well and denied any 
     previous trauma to his leg or other predisposing factors such as long 
     car or airplane trips and he stated he had been as active as 
     previously over the recent few weeks.  The patient stated he awoke 
     in the morning of the 24th and noted tightness in his right 
     quadriceps and right calf.  He later developed progressive swelling 
     of the leg and therefore presented to the THD emergency 
     department.  He had lower extremity non-invasives performed which 
     confirmed the presence of a right lower extremity DVT.  He was 
     admitted and heparinized and then Coumadinized prior to discharge.  
     The patient disclosed a history that his daughter had a DVT at the 
     time of her pregnancy and therefore a hypercoagulability work-up was 
     sent off which was negative.  The patient currently returns to me 
     complaining of further right calf pain and swelling.  He states that 
     he was interested in physical therapy but states that that did not 
     occur during his hospital course.  The patient was also angry and 
     upset that I had not visited him during his hospital stay.  I 
     explained to him that I had not been notified of his admission or of 
     his emergency department visit.  I called all of the parties 
     responsible for his admission to clear the confusion that had 
     occurred.
 
2.   Hypertension.  The patient's previously been on anti-hypertensives 
     including lisinopril, unfortunately the patient has not tolerated ACE 
     inhibitors secondary to a severe cough and therefore these were 
     discontinued recently.  With a discontinuation of his drinking, the 
     patient's blood pressures have been under much better control.
 
3.   Adult onset diabetes mellitus.  I recently started the patient on 
     insulin.  He was scheduled for a follow up visit but unfortunately 
     did not make his visit.  His insulin dose was adjusted during his 
     recent hospitalization and his current dosage is 35 units of NPH in 
     the morning and 15 units of regular.  In the evening he takes 10 
     units of NPH and 10 units of regular.  The patient does not yet have 
     a home glucometer.  We will arrange for this.
 
THD INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Hart, Matthew
Page 2                                        46103196
                                              2-4-65
 
 
 
Physical Examination:  Vital signs showed a heart rate of 90.  Blood 
pressure: 135/92. Respiratory rate: 14 and unlabored.  HEENT: pupils 
equal, round and reactive to light, extraocular movements intact, 
oropharynx clear. Mucous membranes moist. Cardiac: regular rate and 
rhythm, normal S1, S2, no murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  Lungs: clear to 
ausculation. Abdomen soft, nontender with active bowel sounds.  
Extremities:  There was notable edema of his right lower extremity with 
significant pain and a positive Homan's sign.  
 
Impression:
1)   DVT.  Given his current physical examination, and lack of recent PT 
     check since time of discharge on the 30th, I am sending a stat PT.  I 
     encouraged the patient to elevate the leg. My feeling is that the DVT 
     has not successfully been treated and that likely his PT is not 
     therapeutic at the present time.  I have arranged for the patient to 
     follow up with Aguilar, the Internal Medicine nurse, on Wednesday for a repeat 
     check of his PT.  I left instructions that I should be called 
     immediately upon receiving the PT value, I also arranged for the 
     patient to meet with the physical therapist for the provision of a 
     cane to help with ambulation. 
 
2)   Adult onset diabetes.  I will recheck a hemoglobin A1C value at his 
     next office visit.  A finger stick in the office approximately three 
     hours after eating is 253.  I feel this is still too elevated.  I 
     will therefore adjust his insulin dose when I see him next week.  I 
     will follow up with the patient next week and make any necessary 
     adjustments in his medications at that time.
 
 
 
_________________________
Michael Uecker, M.D. 
 
PD:UD:1698
DD:2-19-65
DT:2-22-65
DV:2-4-65




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2065-02-04" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="28" end="34" text="TRIBAL" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="73" end="86" text="Hart, Matthew" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="133" end="141" text="46103196" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="188" end="194" text="2-4-65" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="224" end="226" text="41" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="561" end="565" text="1-24" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="576" end="580" text="1-30" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="956" end="960" text="24th" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P9" start="1116" end="1119" text="THD" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="2934" end="2937" text="THD" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2976" end="2989" text="Hart, Matthew" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P12" start="3036" end="3044" text="46103196" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="3091" end="3097" text="2-4-65" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="3767" end="3771" text="30th" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="4042" end="4049" text="Aguilar" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="4083" end="4092" text="Wednesday" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="4805" end="4819" text="Michael Uecker" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P19" start="4829" end="4839" text="PD:UD:1698" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="4843" end="4850" text="2-19-65" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="4854" end="4861" text="2-22-65" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="4865" end="4871" text="2-4-65" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>