<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2150-09-07

Franciscan Health Center

Emergency Department Record



Patient: CALDWELL, FRANK             MRN: 0028405        DOB:  8/12/2075     Sex: M

Registration Date/Time: 9/07/2150 1:35:00 PM            Provider: TERESA  LAMB





Time Patient Seen

3:18p

Chief Complaint

UNABLE TO AMBULATE X 2 DAYS

HPI

75 male comes in complaining of severe pain in his left hip and thigh with difficulty w ambulate.  States the pain is so bad he is unable to walk.  He has a  history for prostate cancer with probable metastases to the lung .  Was seen by his PCP this week as well as by neurology he has been set up for an MRI for next Thursday but the pain is  much worse today, he comes here for evaluation.  He denies any bladder or bowel dysfunction he denies any trauma to his back or legs. has had 20 lb wt loss recently

PMHx

DM, elevated cholesterol, hypertension,

PSurHx

AAA repair, prostate cancer,  lung lobectomy, renal stones, cataract surgery



Meds

Lipitor, glyburide, lisinopril, aspirin

Allergy

None



ROS

Constitutional

No major weight loss or gain, fatigue, fever, chills.

Head/Eyes

No visual changes, lesions, headaches

ENT/Neck

No hearing loss, tinnitus, vertigo, rhinorrhea, hoarseness, difficulty swallowing, oral lesions, stiffness

Chest/Respiratory

No coughing, wheezing, dyspnea

Cardiovascular

No chest pain, palpitations, PND, orthopnea

Musculoskeletal/Extr/Back

See HPI

Skin

No rashes, itching

Neuro

No paralysis, paraesthesias,



Physical Exam

General

nad, alert oriented

Constitutional

SEE nursing notes

Chest/Respiratory

Clear to auscultation and percussion, no crackles, wheezes or rhonchi

Cardiovascular

Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 & S2, no murmurs, gallops or rubs

GI/Abdomen

soft nontender

Musculoskeletal

Back exam- no tenderness,  able to do forward flexion to 90 DEG, lat flexion to 20 DEG, unable to heel toe walk on L leg, circulation/sensation  to legs intact, dtr's +2 thru out, SLR neg, unable to wt bear on L leg due to hip/thigh pain , 

 



rectal exam nl tone and sensation - WILKES

Skin

No rash, no lesions of significance

X-ray Interpretation

hip, pelvis

plain films L hip, femur, pelvis, LS spine - prelim read no fracture-WILKES

Impression/Plan

L leg pain - discussed with attending, hx and exam suggest radiculopathy. Pain controlled in the ER with morphine and ibuprofen. He reports he would not tolerate a closed MRI tonight even with suggestion. There are no red flags tonight for cauda equina and will discharge with pain medication and follow up with his schedule LS spine MRI in open machine on Thursday.-WILKES

Consults

Teresa Law



ED Attending Physician Note

HPI

See NP note for full details. Briefly, this patient has history of back pain, L buttock and leg pain for which he has been scheduled for an outpt open MRI next week. The pain was worse in the last few days such that he has had difficulty walking due to pain. He does not have any weakness or numbness no loss of control of bowel or bladder. No fevers/chills. Has hx of prostate CA which certainly puts him at risk for spine mets.

ROS

otherwise neg

Vitals

See Nursing Notes

PE

See NP note for full exam.

Neurologic exam: A & O x3, CN 2-12 intact, motor 5/5 all ext, sensation intact to light touch throughout, nl gait, normal finger-to-nose bilaterally, neg pronator drift. Pt reports that after having received pain medication he is now able to walk, whereas he wasn't earlier this evening when he first arrived because he was in too much pain.

Medical Decision Making ED Course

75M w/acute on chronic low back and left buttock pain, now improved after pain medication in the ED. The patient has no neurologic deficits at this time and is able to walk without assistance. Given the patient's history of prostate CA, he certainly needs further radiographic evaluation of his spine to evaluate for mets and should undergo MRI to assess for disc disease as well. Pt was offered MRI today, however he is certain he cannot tolerate a traditional closed MRI (he has tried before with medications). Given that the patient does not have any neurologic deficits, it is safe for him to be discharged home on an improved pain regimen with stool softeners as well and f/u with his already scheduled outpt open MRI next week. Pt and family understand to return if pt develops any neurologic symptoms.

Condition on Discharge

Stable

Diagnoses

Back pain

Review Comments

I have personally seen and examined the patient and confirmed the resident's examination, reviewed and agree with the resident's documentation of history, and discussed the evaluation, plan of care and disposition of the patient with the resident.



This note has been electronically signed by TERESA  LAMB, MD 9/13/2150 7:30:19 PM



Clinical staff documenting in the ED note include:



Attending/Nurse Practitioners(s)



TERESA  LAMB, MD

BRIANNA  WILKES, NP

VETRA  MOON, NP



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2150-09-07" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="28" end="52" text="Franciscan Health Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="94" end="109" text="CALDWELL, FRANK" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="127" end="134" text="0028405" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="148" end="157" text="8/12/2075" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="194" end="203" text="9/07/2150" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="236" end="248" text="TERESA  LAMB" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="331" end="333" text="75" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="650" end="658" text="Thursday" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2082" end="2088" text="WILKES" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2237" end="2243" text="WILKES" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2619" end="2627" text="Thursday" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2629" end="2635" text="WILKES" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2647" end="2657" text="Teresa Law" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P14" start="3583" end="3585" text="75" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="4759" end="4771" text="TERESA  LAMB" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="4776" end="4785" text="9/13/2150" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="4890" end="4902" text="TERESA  LAMB" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="4908" end="4923" text="BRIANNA  WILKES" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="4929" end="4940" text="VETRA  MOON" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>