<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2151-03-15



	CARDIOLOGY

	

	FRANCISCAN HEALTH CENTER

	



	Reason for visit:

   chest pain, with known LCX lesion admit for cardiac cath in am.



	Interval History:

   75 yr old male who is admitted with new onset chest pain. Pt has a hx of significant   AAA  repair in '31and newly diagnosed nonoperable pancreatic cancer. During evaluation of pancreatic cancer, CT revealed pseudoaneurysm of aortic graft. Before start of chemotherapy, pt underwent surgical repair of pseudoaneurysm. 

2/16/51 Pt had successful surgical repair of the pseudoaneurysm, complicated by a intraoperative NSTEMI with a peak troponin of .36. 

2/20/51 echo done showing EF of 70%.

2/22/51 cath revealing LM normal, LAD 40% stenosis after D1, 95% stenosis at ostium of D1 and LCX 80% at the takeoff of OM2 with 70%ostial OM2 lesion, and RCA non-dominant with no significant disease.

Because pt was not having any symptoms of angina, the decision was made not to intervene on the LCX lesion and to stress the pt at a later date.

Currently pt is to begin treatment of his pancreatic cancer with chemotherapy and radiation.  Today pt was to have his first treatment, but starting having chest pain and was sent to the ER for further evaluation. 

Recently for the past three days, pt reports on and off chest pain lasting 4-5 hours with raidation to jaw and left arm at rest and excertion. No assciated symptoms of SOB or diaphoresis. Pt thought he was having heartburn symptoms.

In the ER, EKG showed mild lateral ST depression in V5-V6, initial troponin neg and chest pain relieved with one SL nitrogylcerin. Heparin started and pt transferred pain free to Cardiology.   Upon arrival, pt had one episode of chest pain, EKG showed no acute changes, chest pain relieved with one SL nitrogylcerin.



	Past medical history:

   NIDDM

Spinal stenosis

Kidney stones

HTN

AAA repair '31

Cholecystectomy

Prostate Cancer '42, prostatectomy

Lung Cancer RLL '43, lobectomy



Medications at Home:

Glyburide 10mg BID

Lisinopril 5mg daily

ASA 81mg daily

Metoprolol 25mg BID

Zocor 20mg daily

Plavix 75mg daily







Allergies:

	

Allergy   IV contrast-parotid swelling

Drug allergy   sudaphed-insomnia  oxycodone-GI intolerance



	Family history:

   Father died aged 61 lung cancer

Mother died aged 71

Sister died of kidney failure



	Social history:

   Married and retired industrial instrument technician. Has five grown children and three grandchildren.

Smoked for 32 years, 1ppd and quit in the 20's. Denies any ETOH.



	Review of systems:

   Denies any headaches, stroke, visual distrubances, syncope or seizures.

Denies any chest pain, SOB, dizziness, or palpations.

Denis any SOB, cough, or difficulty breathing.

Denies any abd pain, nausea or vomiting, black or bloody stools.

Denies any difficutly with urination.

Denies any weakness, numbness, or tingling in the extremites.



Physical examination:

	

-BP: 190/102  

-Pulse: 60  

-resp. rate: 20  98%  on 2L NC

-temp: 98.2  

-General:   No acute distress.

-Skin:   No rashes, anicteric.

-HEENT:   Unremarkable

-Neck:   Carotids 2+ without bruits. JVP no jugular venous distention.

-Chest:   Clear to auscultation.

-Cardiac:   Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 and S2, with no S3 or S4. There were no murmurs, clicks or rubs. Porta cath noted to the right subclavin. 

-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds, soft and nontender, with no hepatosplenomegaly or masses appreciated.

-Extremities:   No cyanosis, clubbing or edema. 2+ femoral pulses without bruits. Bilateral vertical incisions noted with steri strips, C,D,I with no redness and no thrill or bruits noted. 2+ pedal pulses.

-Neuro:   A&O x3, MAE.



	EKG:

   No acute ST changes, normal axis with good R wave progression and <.5mm ST depression in V5 and V6.



Selected recent labs:

	 Metabolic

Date     NA       K        CL       CO2      BUN      CRE      GLU      CA       PHOS     MG       

03/15/51 140      4.3      102      26.2     22       1.2      166      9.5      2.9      1.7      



Cardiac enzymes

Date     TROP-I   

03/15/51 NEGATIVE 



Liver and Pancreatic Enzymes

Date     ALB      TP       ALKP     DBILI    TBILI    ALT/SGPT AST/SGOT LDH      AMY      LIPS     

03/15/51 4.5      7.9      88       0.1      0.4      27       32                65       3.1      

09/06/50                                                                145                        



Hematology

Date     HCT      RBC      WBC      PLT      %BAND-M  ALYMP    %MONO    %EOS     %BASO    

03/15/51 37.8     4.31     9.2      176               2.15     6        6        0        

03/05/51                                     9                                            



Coagulation

Date     PT       PT-INR   PTT      

03/15/51 11.2     0.9      PEND     



other

Date     HGB      MCV      MCH      MCHC     RDW      DIFFR    %POLY-A  %LYMPH-A ANISO    HYPO     

03/15/51 12.7     88       29.5     33.7     15.0     RECEIVED                   None     None     

03/05/51                                                       70.0     12.0                       



Date     MACRO    MICRO    DDIMR-NG %LYMPH   AEOSN    ABASOP   AMONS    %NEUT    ANEUT    METHOD   

03/15/51 None     None     2096     24       0.53     0.03     0.50     64       5.93     Auto     

03/05/51                                                                                           





	



	Assessment and plan:

   75 yr old male with unoperable pancreatic cancer who is s/p pseudoaneurysm repair and with LCX lesion who is having unstable angina, initial troponin negative and admit for cardiac cath in am.



Plan:

Admit to Cardiology

Currently on ASA and Plavix, will continue.

Continue ACE, BUN and Creatine WNL.

Continue BB, HR and BP well controlled.

Will cycle cardiac enzymes.

NPO for cardiac cath in am, pt will dye allergy, will pre medicate with po prednisone and benadryl.

Pt with recent surgical repair of pseudoaneurysm with bilateral arteriotomies of femoral arteries, question of sones approach.

Food and Nutrition Consult.

Will continue Heparin  and SS.

Pt has porta cath, will be flushed per protocol. 

Of note chemotherapy infusion stopped in ER and pump noted at bedside.

Dr. Angeline Barajas following for pancreatic cancer.

Further orders per attending.

	

-frances cramer, RN

	

Signed electronically by  frances cramer, RN

Document Status: Final



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2151-03-15" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="47" end="71" text="FRANCISCAN HEALTH CENTER" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P2" start="191" end="193" text="75" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="293" end="296" text="'31" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="511" end="518" text="2/16/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="646" end="653" text="2/20/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="684" end="691" text="2/22/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="1884" end="1887" text="'31" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1922" end="1925" text="'42" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1958" end="1961" text="'43" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P11" start="2275" end="2277" text="61" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="2308" end="2310" text="71" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P13" start="2386" end="2418" text="industrial instrument technician" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="2512" end="2516" text="20's" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="3947" end="3955" text="03/15/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="4087" end="4095" text="03/15/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="4240" end="4248" text="03/15/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="4341" end="4349" text="09/06/50" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="4548" end="4556" text="03/15/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="4640" end="4648" text="03/05/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="4785" end="4793" text="03/15/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="4933" end="4941" text="03/15/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="5034" end="5042" text="03/05/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="5238" end="5246" text="03/15/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="5339" end="5347" text="03/05/51" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P26" start="5475" end="5477" text="75" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P28" start="6268" end="6284" text="Angeline Barajas" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P29" start="6354" end="6368" text="frances cramer" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P30" start="6403" end="6417" text="frances cramer" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>