<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2126-01-29

Personal Data and Overall Health	

53 year old male scheduled for surgery on February 6th.



Chief Complaint	

The patient is scheduled for left total hip replacement.



History of Present Illness	

The patient complains of pain of left hip secondary to osteoarthritis.



Past Surgical History	

Prior surgery includes:  none



Family History	

There in no family history of adverse reactions to general anesthesia.



Past Medical History	

Current medical problems include:  obesity



Social History	

Smoking: no

Alcohol use: 3-4beers/day

Substance abuse: none

Allergen Exposure within 3 Months (blood/pregnancy/surgery):  none



Review of Systems	

Medications: Celebrex, Vicodin

Allergies:  penicillin cause swelling and difficulty breathing

Cardiovascular:  no history of hypertension, no MI; denies CP, DOE, syncope, ankle edema

Respiratory: no history of asthma or chronic lung disease; denies unusual shortness of breath

Neurological: no history of neurological problems

Gastrointestinal: no history of PUD; denies reflux

Hepatobiliary: no history of liver disease; denies jaundice or hepatitis

Renal/Genitourinary: no history of renal failure; denies hematuria, dysuria, obstructive uropathy

Musculoskeletal: pain of left hip

Endocrine/metabolic: no history of diabetes, no endocrinopathy 

Heme/Onc:  no history of bleeding, blood diseases; no history of malignancy, chemotherapy, or radiation therapy

Psychiatric: no significant psychiatric problems





Exam	

SaO2:97

Ht:5'11"

Wt:312

BP:142/79

P:84



HEEN&T:  good range of motion, no masses, neck veins flat, no bruits

Airway:  Mallampatti Class II

Teeth:  in good repair

Lungs:  clear bilaterally

Heart:  regular rhythm, no murmurs, S1=S2, no gallop

Abdomen:  not examined

Extremities:  not examined



Assessment	

ASA Physical Status:  II

Well prepared for surgery; no unusual concerns related to medical problems.



Plan	

Proposed Anesthetic: spinal or general anesthesia

Monitors:  standard

Pain Management:  IVPCA

Autologous blood:  none

Premedication:  none

Usual Medications:  take on day of surgery

Medications to be held on day of surgery:  none

Diabetic medications:  not applicable

NSAIDS:  avoid for 3 days before surgery

Aspirin:  avoid for 7 days before surgery

NPO: after midnight 



External Labs	

Not available



Attending Anesthesiologist Reassessment Note	

I have reviewed this preanesthetic assessment and concur with the assessment and recommended plan with the following exceptions:







______________________________                              



Patton, Chong, M.D.



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2126-01-29" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P1" start="63" end="65" text="53" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P2" start="105" end="117" text="February 6th" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="2617" end="2630" text="Patton, Chong" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>