<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2134-02-15

EDVISIT^72484104^URQUHART, WENDELL^02/15/34^MARQUEZ, RONALD

I evaluated this patient independently.  I concur with findings

as noted on the medical record, supervised the care as provided

by the resident in the Emergency Department.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  In brief, this is a 61-year-old male

with complaint of chest discomfort on exertion for the past six

weeks after climbing upstairs.  The patient noticed symptoms

again today.  He called his FLH physician who sent him to the

Emergency Department for probable admission.  The patient has had

a prior history of proximal RCA lesion and two stents placed in

06/2128 after similar episodes.  The patient has been doing well

since and recently has developed worsening symptoms.  He is

followed by Dr. Ure and contacted Dr. Ure's office who

sent him to the Emergency Department.  He denies chest pain at

rest.  He does not have abdominal pain.  No pain radiating to the

back.  No shortness of breath, dysuria, or additional symptoms.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypertension and coronary artery disease.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  As noted, past surgical history is stent

placement.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Past tobacco user.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Significant for that which is noted on the

HPI.  All other symptoms are negative as noted in the medical

record.

MEDICATIONS:  Please refer to the chart.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Vital signs are as noted in the medical

record.  I examined this patient and agree with physical exam

findings as noted on the record.  Please refer to the chart.  Of

note, the patient has no specific physical exam findings, a

benign physical examination.

LABORATORY DATA:  Pending.  EKG is normal sinus rhythm with

biphasic T waves in III, V6 but otherwise normal, no acute ST-T

wave changes.  The patient is currently pain free.

ASSESSMENT AND MEDICAL DECISION MAKING:  This is a 61-year-old

male with likely stable angina that is worsening in character. 

He will be admitted to Cardiology.  I discussed this case with

the cardiologist on call, Dr. Maxwell.  The patient will be

admitted for further workup and determination of catheterization

if necessary.

______________________________

MARQUEZ, RONALD M.D.

D: 02/15/34

T: 02/15/34

Dictated By: MARQUEZ, RONALD

eScription document:8-9594396 IFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2134-02-15" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="72484104" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="62" text="URQUHART, WENDELL" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="63" end="71" text="02/15/34" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="72" end="87" text="MARQUEZ, RONALD" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="314" end="316" text="61" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="487" end="490" text="FLH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="654" end="661" text="06/2128" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="797" end="800" text="Ure" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="819" end="822" text="Ure" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P10" start="1940" end="1942" text="61" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2112" end="2119" text="Maxwell" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2256" end="2271" text="MARQUEZ, RONALD" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2281" end="2289" text="02/15/34" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="2294" end="2302" text="02/15/34" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="2317" end="2332" text="MARQUEZ, RONALD" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P16" start="2354" end="2363" text="8-9594396" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>