<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2087-03-22


Internal Medicine


Reason for visit
Diarrhea
Fever
Chest pain
Fatigue


History of present illness  
The patient is here complaining of several days history of diarrhea with mild nausea, mild fever and retrosternal chest discomfort. That is intermittent mild and 
insiduous. The pain is not triggered by exercise or physical activity or position. She has been feeling weak.


Medical history  
Coronary vasospastic events 

Glucose intolerance + postprandial hyperglycemia
Hyperlipidemia
Hypertension
Postmenopausal
Cervical osteoarthritis DDD
Microscopic hematuria with negative work up
Hypovitaminosis D
Obesity - now loosing weight


Current meds


Amlodipine                 5 mg qd 
Metoprolol XL             50 mg qd
Valsartan                160 mg qd       -combined
Hydrochlorothiazide       25 mg qd       -combined
Atorvastatin              20 mg qd
Aspirin                   81 mg qd
Metformin                500 mg bid


Review of systems
Denies abdominal pain, vomiting, dyspnea


Family and social history
Place of birth        GambiaHome residence        JaffreyMarital status        MarriedHousehold members     HusbandOccupation            Composer



Mother       A       dementia 
Father       A       diabetes
Brothers     0 
Sisters      1 
Spouse       A 
Children     2 


Cancer       0 
Diabetes     +       F 
             +       M
CV Disease   0   
Stroke       0   


Labs and images
Reviewed


Exam
Vitals 110/72  96  16  98.0
HEENT eomi, conjunctiva pink, ears clear, nasal mucosa pink, no mucus, no sinus tenderness, no post nasal drip.
Neck is supple, no JVD, no thyroid imprint, no submandibular nodes.
Thorax expands symmetrically, clear to auscultation bilaterally. Pain reproduced on chest palpation.
Cardiovascular S1 and S2 with regular rhythm and rate. No murmurs.
Abdomen is soft, non tender, no palpable masses or organomegaly. Increased bowel sounds.
Extremities are symmetrical with no edema.
Neurological exam is grossly non focal.


Assessment and plan




Chest discomfort. The patient's history and exam do not suggest cardiovascular origin but pain originated in the chest wall, musculoskeletal in origin. She had an ECG in my office that was unchanged from previous ones, there were no ST-TW abnormalities, no extrasystoles or any other abnormality. She was reassured. For musculoskeletal pain I have recommended stretching exercises, and low dose diazepam for muscle contracture. She will avoid NSAID due to GI symptoms.

Abdominal discomfort with diarrhea. The patient will follow a CHO diet and will avoid dairy products and other substances with low-absorption high-residue. In addition, in context of weakness I have recommended her to have a chemistry analysis for investigating electrolytes. Should symptoms persist then I will recommend the patient to initiate Ciprofloxacin and Metronidazole.

Dehydration. The patient will initiate a strict fluid replenishment plan for rehydration.




                                   
David Delgado, M.D.







]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2087-03-22" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="1072" end="1078" text="Gambia" TYPE="COUNTRY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P2" start="1100" end="1107" text="Jaffrey" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P3" start="1187" end="1195" text="Composer" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="3013" end="3026" text="David Delgado" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>