<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2164-03-10





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

NORTHLAND MEDICAL CLINIC



Reason for visit

			

  Followup.



Major Problems





Hypertension

Blood pressure stable on his medications.



Diabetes mellitus

On higher insulin regimen.  He is followed by Diabetes clinic.  We recheck hemoglobin A1c soon.



Osteoarthritis

Left worse than right.  Shoulder pain chronic. saw Dr. Echeverria. Prefers to wait on surgery.



Bladder carcinoma

Followed by Dr. Morton.  Had a repeat cystoscopy in December that was within normal limits.



Hypercholesterolemia

Continues on Zetia and Pravachol.  Repeat fasting cholesterol soon. Start niaspan as well. reviewed side effects. recheck chol in 6 wks. 



Coronary artery disease

Stable.  Followed by Cardiology.



Neuropathy

continues with bilateral burning at night.   Continues on Neurontin which helps.



Allergies

Aspirin allergy   GI bleeding.

Drug allergy   Vioxx.  Zestril, gives a cough.

Penicillin allergy   Penicillin.



Active Medications



aspirin 81 mg po qd

atenolol 25mg po 2 tabs qd

econazole nitrate (spectazole) cream 1% topical qd prn

Imdur 30 mg po qd

Insulin syringes 

Klor con 10meq po qd take with food; do not chew tabs

Lasix 40mg po qd

Neurontin 100mg po tid take one pill in am, one at noon and three qhs

Nexium 40mg po qd

Niaspan 500mg sr po qhs do not cut/crush/chew; take with food

nph insulin 40units sc qam 10 units qpm

Ntg 0.3 mg SL Q 5 MIN x3 prn chest pain

Onetouch strips 

Pravachol 20mg po qd

regular insulin  sc 12u qam and 12u qpm

Tobradex ophthalmic solution 1 gtt ou tid

topical hydrocortisone cream 2.5% qid prn apply as needed for rash and itchy skin

Zetia 10mg po qd



Change in therapies and Renewals



Niaspan 500mg SR po qhs do not cut/crush/chew; take with food QTY:30 Refills:5 Start: 03/10/2164



Past medical history

			

  As above.



Review of systems

			

  As above, otherwise negative.



Physical examination

Blood pressure 120/70  

Pulse   60

Respiratory rate   18

Weight   222 pounds

Office blood glucose fingerstick 206  

General appearance   Well-developed, well-nourished male in no apparent distress

Heent   Pupils are equal and reactive.  Extraocular movements are intact.  No pharyngeal exudates

Neck   JVP is flat.  No goiter

Nodes   None palpable

Chest   Clear to auscultation bilaterally

Cor   Regular rate and rhythm without any murmurs, rubs, or gallops

Abdomen   Soft, nontender, and nondistended

Extrem   No clubbing, cyanosis, or edema

Musc skel   No bony deformities, but decreased range of motion of his bilateral shoulders and tenderness with extension of his left shoulder.  The patient also had some tenderness to palpation in the left lateral hip region.  There was good range of motion of his bilateral hips

Neuro   He is alert and oriented x 3.  Cranial nerves II through XII are grossly intact



Assessment and plan

			

  As above.



Disposition

Follow up in a few months. 



Signed electronically by Chavez, Barbara on Mar 19, 2164     



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2164-03-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="62" end="86" text="NORTHLAND MEDICAL CLINIC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="396" end="406" text="Echeverria" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="474" end="480" text="Morton" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="510" end="518" text="December" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="1822" end="1832" text="03/10/2164" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="2996" end="3011" text="Chavez, Barbara" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="3015" end="3027" text="Mar 19, 2164" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>