<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2086-11-07

 

 

November 07, 2086

 

Usha Gibbons, M.D.

Cooley Internal Medicine Associates

Cooley Dickinson Hospital

99 Greenfield Drive

Schuyler, FL  76969

 

Re:  Benitez, Wonda

     MRN: 89276954

 

Dear Usha:

 

I just had the pleasure of seeing Ms. Benitez for a follow up

cardiovascular examination.  She has been reasonably stable since

I saw her last in July.  She has had several episodes of chest

discomfort characterized as a tightness which has been quite

transient.  The frequency has been less than one time per month. 

The last occurred yesterday while she was walking in a shopping

mall.  She continued to walk and her symptom resolved.  She has

not had any associated shortness of breath or diaphoresis.  

 

She has had no symptoms of cardiovascular ischemia, denying

transient hemiparesis, hemiparesthesia, or amaurosis fugax.  She

denies claudication but does admit to back pain, bilateral hip

pain with walking.  She still notes paresthesias of both feet. 

She continues to be bothered by tinnitus as well as headaches.

 

Her current medical regimen includes losartan 75 mg p.o. b.i.d.,

nifedipine XL 60 mg p.o. q.d., aspirin 325 mg p.o. q.d.,

atorvastatin 40 mg p.o. q.d., metoprolol 12.5 mg p.o. b.i.d.,

Synthroid ? 5 mcg five days per week and 10.5 mcg two days per

week, furosemide 20 mg p.o. q.d. p.r.n., quinine sulfate 324 mg

p.o. h.s. (for cramping), nitroglycerin p.r.n., Zoloft 15 mg p.o.

h.s., lorazepam 15 mg p.o. q.h.s., magnesium oxide 250 mg p.o.

q.d. and Ranitidine 150 mg p.o. p.r.n. 

 

On examination she appears well.  Weight is 142 pounds.  Blood

pressure is 140/60.  Heart rate is 50 and regular.  Neck veins

are 6 cm above the mid right atrium.  There are bilateral carotid

bruits.  Lungs are resonant to percussion and clear to

auscultation.  On cardiac exam the PMI is in the fifth

intercostal space at the midclavicular line.  There is a 1+ left

ventricular lift.  The first heart sound is normal.  The second 

 

Benitez, Wonda                                    MRN: 89276954

November 07, 2086              -2-

 

 

is split physiologically.  There is a grade 2/6 mid systolic

murmur at the apex and a grade 2/6 systolic ejection murmur along

the left sternal border.  There is a fourth heart sound at the

apex.  Abdominal examination reveals no masses, no

hepatosplenomegaly.  Extremities are notable for 2+ bilateral

femoral pulses, palpable bilateral tibial artery bypass graft

pulses, absent bilateral popliteal pulses, 1+ right dorsalis

pedis, absent right posterior tibial and absent left pedal

pulses.

 

Her electrocardiogram shows sinus bradycardia with first degree

AV block and findings suggestive of a prior anterolateral

myocardial infarction.  There has been no diagnostic change since

July 18, 2086.

 

Carotid duplex ultrasound examination performed on October 31,

2086 showed a 55% stenosis of the right internal carotid artery

and a 50% stenosis of the left internal carotid artery.  The

velocity of the right internal carotid artery and the subsequent

calculation of stenosis was less than it had been in February

2086.  

 

Graft scans obtained on October 31, 2086 demonstrated patent left

femoral-anterior tibial artery bypass graft with increased

velocities consistent with a greater than 75% stenosis at the mid

thigh level and this was increased from a study of August 06, 2086. 

The right femoral-dorsalis pedis arterial bypass graft was patent

with no evidence of significant stenoses.  

 

In summary, her problems relevant to this visit include:

 

1.  Coronary artery disease.  Status post coronary artery bypass

surgery.  LIMA to the LAD and SVGs to the diagonal and

posterolateral left ventricular branch.  She has occasional and

very transient episodes of angina.  I have suggested continuing

her current medical regimen.  As noted previously, I prefer to

manage her medically unless her symptoms worsen.  

 

2.  Carotid artery disease.  She is asymptomatic.  I recommend

periodic surveillance with carotid ultrasound. 

 

3.  Peripheral arterial disease.  Both grafts are patent but the

left femoral-anterior bypass graft appears by ultrasound to have

a significant stenosis.  I have asked her to discuss this finding

with you further.

 

Benitez, Wonda                                    MRN: 89276954

November 07, 2086              -3-

 

 

4.  Hypercholesterolemia.  A lipid profile will be checked today. 

 

 

5.  Systolic murmur and query antibiotic prophylaxis for dental

procedures.  I am evaluating her murmurs, which were presumably

aortic sclerosis and mitral regurgitation, with an

echocardiogram.  

 

Sincerely,

 

 

 

Thomas Waller, M.D.

 

cc:

Terry W. Neel, M.D.

Vascular Surgery

Cooley Dickinson Hospital

20 Greenfield Drive

Schuyler, FL  76969 

 

TW/sanchez

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2086-11-07" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="34" end="51" text="November 07, 2086" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="56" end="68" text="Usha Gibbons" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="76" end="82" text="Cooley" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="113" end="138" text="Cooley Dickinson Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="140" end="159" text="99 Greenfield Drive" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="161" end="169" text="Schuyler" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="171" end="173" text="FL" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="175" end="180" text="76969" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="190" end="204" text="Benitez, Wonda" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P10" start="216" end="224" text="89276954" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="234" end="238" text="Usha" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="282" end="289" text="Benitez" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="392" end="396" text="July" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="2018" end="2032" text="Benitez, Wonda" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P15" start="2073" end="2081" text="89276954" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="2083" end="2100" text="November 07, 2086" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="2821" end="2834" text="July 18, 2086" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PHI id="P18" start="2891" end="2908" text="October 31,

2086" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PHI id="P19" start="3150" end="3164" text="February

2086" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="3196" end="3212" text="October 31, 2086" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="3417" end="3432" text="August 06, 2086" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P22" start="4320" end="4334" text="Benitez, Wonda" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P23" start="4375" end="4383" text="89276954" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="4385" end="4402" text="November 07, 2086" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P25" start="4726" end="4739" text="Thomas Waller" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P26" start="4755" end="4768" text="Terry W. Neel" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P28" start="4794" end="4819" text="Cooley Dickinson Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P29" start="4821" end="4840" text="20 Greenfield Drive" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P30" start="4842" end="4850" text="Schuyler" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P31" start="4852" end="4854" text="FL" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P32" start="4856" end="4861" text="76969" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P33" start="4867" end="4869" text="TW" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P34" start="4870" end="4877" text="sanchez" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>