<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2085-11-01

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

November 01, 2085

 

 

 

Usha Gibbons, MD

Cooley Internal Medicine Associates

Cooley Dickinson Hospital

49 Greenfield Drive

Schuyler, FL  76969

 

RE:  BENITEZ, Wonda

MRN: 892-76-95-4

 

Dear Usha:

 

I had the pleasure of seeing one of your patients, Ms. Benitez, in

my Cardiovascular Clinic today for follow-up status post coronary

artery bypass surgery.  As you know, Ms. Benitez has been having a

terrible past month with increasing episodes of substernal chest

discomfort.  One episode occurred during Ramadan when she was

fasting and another occurred while she was in a restaurant.  Both of

these episodes were relieved with sublingual nitroglycerine.  I

am concerned about her discomfort because of an earlier

Persantine MIBI study showing anteroapical redistribution on her

test and the fact that it was relieved by nitroglycerine. 

Currently she denies any PND, orthopnea or chest discomfort.  She

continues to have back and bilateral hip pain and has been taking

corticosteroid shots for that.

 

On physical examination, she is an anxious, concerned, elderly

woman.  Blood pressure is 160/70 in the left arm.  Jugular venous

pulse is not observed.  She has bilateral carotid bruits.  Chest

exam is clear.  Cardiac exam shows an S4 gallop, a normal S1, a

physiologically split S2 and a 2/6 systolic murmur at the left

sternal border.  Abdominal exam is benign.  Peripheral exam shows

trace pedal edema.

 

EKG shows sinus bradycardia at a rate of 50 beats per minute. 

There are Q waves in V1 through V4, consistent with an old

anterolateral MI.  The tracing was otherwise unchanged compared

with previous tracings.

RE:  BENITEZ, Wonda

MRN: 892-76-95-4              - 2 -          November 01, 2085

 

 

IMPRESSION:  I think we should schedule Ms. Benitez for a

Persantine thallium test as soon as possible.  If she can

exercise on this test, that would be even better. When the

results are back, I will get back you regarding further

recommendations.  My hope is that we will not have to

revascularize her again.  If we do, I am hoping to do so with

potential angioplasty and stenting.  In the meantime, I have

switched her from Zocor 40 mg to Lipitor 40 mg a day in the hopes

of targeting her LDL cholesterol to the new guidelines of 100. 

Her previous LDL cholesterol was 111.  I also suggested to her in

the meantime to cut down on her physical activities until we know

the results of the thallium test and also to forgo one episode of

her steroid injection for her back.

 

Please let me know if you have any further questions or concerns

regarding this patient.  Again, thank you for referring her to

our clinic.

 

With warm regards,

 

 

 

Gordon Q. Iniguez, MD

 

 

GI/JZ

 

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2085-11-01" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="52" end="69" text="November 01, 2085" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="80" end="92" text="Usha Gibbons" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="98" end="104" text="Cooley" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="135" end="160" text="Cooley Dickinson Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="162" end="181" text="49 Greenfield Drive" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="183" end="191" text="Schuyler" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="193" end="195" text="FL" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="197" end="202" text="76969" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="212" end="226" text="BENITEZ, Wonda" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P10" start="233" end="244" text="892-76-95-4" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="254" end="258" text="Usha" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="319" end="326" text="Benitez" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="440" end="447" text="Benitez" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="574" end="581" text="Ramadan" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="1718" end="1732" text="BENITEZ, Wonda" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P16" start="1739" end="1750" text="892-76-95-4" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="1779" end="1796" text="November 01, 2085" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="1848" end="1855" text="Benitez" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="2767" end="2784" text="Gordon Q. Iniguez" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="2796" end="2798" text="GI" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P21" start="2799" end="2801" text="JZ" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>