<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2076-12-11

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
December 11, 2076
 
 
Paul Arteaga, M.D.
677 Mill Street
Shady Cove, NY 43414
 
Re:  Christine Olivier
     MR #652-33-21-5
 
Dear Dr. Arteaga:
 
Mrs. Olivier returns for follow-up.  Since last seen, she reports
return in a non-exertional left shoulder discomfort syndrome,
occasionally associated with mild dyspnea.  Of note, she underwent
a dobutamine MIBI stress test last June for evaluating a similar
syndrome, and at that time she developed her typical chest and left
back pain syndrome in association with no diagnostic EKG changes at
a peak heart rate of 127, peak blood pressure of 160/60.  A
simultaneously obtained SESTA MIBI scan revealed a global left
ventricular fraction of 42%, a non-Q-wave myocardial infarction
involving 2 out of 20 segments of the inferior wall and minimal
peri-infarct ischemia.  In addition, a venous duplex ultrasound
study done to evaluate her severe left greater than right
peripheral edema showed no evidence of DVT.  
 
Currently she remains on a regimen of amlodipine 5 mg poqd,
atenolol 50 mg poqd, simvastatin 10 mg poqd, lisinopril 10 mg poqd,
Nitropatch .4 mg q.12 hours, Neurontin 400 mg potid, furosemide 40
mg poqd (recently increased), Lamactil 150 mg pobid, Trusopt and
Xalantan drops, insulin 10 units of CZI with 72 units NPH qam and
74 units NPH qpm. 
 
Physical exam reveals an overweight woman in no distress.  Blood
pressure, right arm sitting - 110/70, heart rate - 70 and regular,
respirations - 12 and unlabored, weight - 174 pounds which is four
pounds below her weight of six months ago.  The neck is supple with
JVP flat.  Carotids are 2+ without significant bruits.  Chest is
clear.  Cardiac exam shows normal S1, physiologically split S2, and
a I/VI holosystolic murmur radiating from the apex to the axilla. 
No significant diastolic murmur or rub.  The abdomen is benign. 
Extremities reveal marked left greater than right pedal edema. 
Peripheral pulses are diminished.  
 
Electrocardiogram shows sinus rhythm at a rate of 70, PR interval
of .12, QRS of .06, QT of .36, axis of -25.  There is borderline
Paul Arteaga, M.D.
December 11, 2076
Page Two
 
Re:  Christine Olivier
     MR #652-33-21-5
 
 
evidence for left ventricular hypertrophy with secondary ST and T-
wave changes.  Compared with the last electrocardiogram, there has
been no significant change. 
 
Presently, Mrs. Olivier has evidence of continuing chest and left
shoulder discomfort which she believes is similar to her pre-bypass
surgery angina.  In this setting, a dobutamine stress test
performed last June showed no evidence of provokable ischemia.  I
have spent some time discussing with Ms. Olivier our various
therapeutic and diagnostic options.  She made it quite clear that
she would not consider repeat cardiac catheterization at this time,
and furthermore, was very disinterested in pursuing the possibility
(should she require it) of either mechanical or surgical re-
vascularization.  It is not entirely clear to me that her left
shoulder syndrome is in fact ischemic in origin, and she certainly
understands it may be secondary to musculoskeletal abnormalities. 
I have suggested that she discuss that further with you.  In the
meantime, I have asked her (as her back and chest discomfort
syndrome appears to occur mostly at night prior to lying down for
bed) to apply her Nitropatch in the evening and take it off in the
morning.  She will call me within the next several days to report
how this helps her discomfort syndrome.  I do not believe that she
is having GERD to explain her symptoms.  In light of her reluctance
to undergo any further diagnostic cardiac studies, I will try to
tailor her anti-ischemic medications to minimize her chest
discomfort syndrome.  I, of course, will keep you fully informed as
to her progress, and I thank you for allowing me to assist in her
care. 
 
Sincerely yours,
 
 
Irineo Tovar, M.D.
/vuong
 
DD: 12/11/76
DT: 01/14/77
DV: 12/11/76
 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2076-12-11" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="42" end="59" text="December 11, 2076" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="64" end="76" text="Paul Arteaga" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="83" end="98" text="677 Mill Street" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="99" end="109" text="Shady Cove" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="111" end="113" text="NY" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="114" end="119" text="43414" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="127" end="144" text="Christine Olivier" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="154" end="165" text="652-33-21-5" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="177" end="184" text="Arteaga" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="193" end="200" text="Olivier" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="418" end="422" text="June" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2117" end="2129" text="Paul Arteaga" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2136" end="2153" text="December 11, 2076" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="2170" end="2187" text="Christine Olivier" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P15" start="2197" end="2208" text="652-33-21-5" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="2394" end="2401" text="Olivier" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="2586" end="2590" text="June" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="2678" end="2685" text="Olivier" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="3906" end="3918" text="Irineo Tovar" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="3926" end="3931" text="vuong" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="3938" end="3946" text="12/11/76" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="3951" end="3959" text="01/14/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="3964" end="3972" text="12/11/76" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>