<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2070-10-28

ID - 67 yo m recent NQWMI and newly diagnosed CHF.



HPI - 67 yo m c h/o htn, heavy EtOH use, and smoking who presented on 10/12/70 to LGH c CP.  BP on admit was 200/110.  Pt ruled in c peak CK 362 c MB fraction of 51.  no EKG changes.  Echo revealed ef 25-30%.  Pt was started on ecasa, atenolol, lasix, lisinopril, amlodipine and taken off HCTZ and terazosin (however cont'd to take terazosin.)  Cath revealed minimal RCA stenoses.

Since then has had no more CP.  c/o DOE after 1 block of walking, where 2-3 mo's ago he was able to walk > 20 blocks.  + 2 pillow orthopnea, + PND, - LE swelling.  Has stopped drinking EtOH and cut down on cigs.

BP by CDH:  148/90 (10/20) and 110/80 (10/22)



PMH - htn, EtOH, cigs, COPD, BPH



Alls - none



Meds - Atenolol 100 qd, ECASA 325 qd, Lasix 20 qd, lisinopril 40 qd, amlodipine 5 qd, terazosin 4 qd, MVI, thiamine, folate



PE - 130/80,  80

JVP 7

RRR S1 S2, no S3

minimal bibasilar rales

distended abd but says has not changed recently, no fluid wave/organomegaly, NT

no LE swelling, warm and well perfused



A/P - 67 yo m c h/o htn, heavy EtOH use and smoking who presented c CHF in setting of NQWMI.  Most likely had background of EtOHic CMP acutely worsened by decreased cardiac function secopndary to NQWMI.

-cont'd BB, ACEi, ECASA, Lasix and amlodipine - advised pt to stop taking alpha block

-checking BMP today to monitor renal function and k c recent addition of ACEi and lasix - will hold off titrating up until results are back.

-checking LFTs and lipid panel.  started pt on zocor.

-referral to nutrition for advice re salt and fluid intake

-referral to cardiac rehab

-stressed improtance of smoking cessation and continued avoidance of EtOH - declined nicotine patch



-Pt will f/u c Dr. E. Bird and Dr. Everson in one week. 





______________________________                              



Kitchen, Willie, M.D.

========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================

67 yo with recent NQWMI and dx cmp, also h/o tob, copd, bph, htn.  Since MI, has been doing well on atenolol, asa, lasix, lisinopril, and amlidopine.  BP 130/80, hr 80.  Still smoking.  Counseled re: smoking cessation. Will check lipids as pt likely to benefit from statin.  Check lytes. Refer to cardiac rehab.  Had been taking terazosin, will stop that. He will f/u next week, if bp up can increase atenolol. Kylee Compton



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2070-10-28" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P1" start="33" end="35" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P2" start="88" end="90" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="152" end="160" text="10/12/70" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="164" end="167" text="LGH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="683" end="686" text="CDH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="697" end="702" text="10/20" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="716" end="721" text="10/22" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="1101" end="1103" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="1793" end="1800" text="E. Bird" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="1809" end="1816" text="Everson" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="1900" end="1915" text="Kitchen, Willie" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="1995" end="1997" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2406" end="2419" text="Kylee Compton" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>