<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2072-01-10

                     LAGRANGE EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

LOUIS,ROBERT   855-88-85-2                   VISIT DATE: 01/10/72

This patient was interviewed and examined by me exclusively.

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest pain.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This patient is a 67-year-old 

male who has known atherosclerotic coronary heart disease 

manifested by myocardial infarction approximately five years ago.  

He also has congestive heart failure with an ejection fraction of 

25%, and this is thought to be due to alcoholic cardiomyopathy 

given a substantial history of alcohol ingestion.  Over the past 

several months, he has stopped taking his medicine because he could 

not get to his doctor and felt he could not buy the medicine.  Over 

the past two weeks, he has been beset by palpitations and dyspnea 

on exertion as well as palpitations at rest.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  He has had no vomiting, diaphoresis, radiation 

of the pain, change in bowel habits or any cough.  All of the 

systems are negative.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  He has had no significant surgeries.

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  He consumes alcohol slightly, 

once smoked in the past, but does not any longer.  He lives with 

his family.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  Physical examination shows a 

patient who is awake, alert, calm and oriented.  He is in no 

distress at the time of examination.  EYES:  He had no scleral 

icterus.  NECK:  There was no adenopathy.  His thyroid was not 

palpable.  CHEST:  His chest was clear.  CARDIOVASCULAR:  His 

cardiovascular exam showed a regular rate and rhythm.  ABDOMEN:  

His abdomen was soft and nontender.  EXTREMITIES:  His extremities 

showed no clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  SKIN:  He had no rash.  

NEURO:  Neurologic exam was physiologic.

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Electrocardiogram showed tachycardia and 

T-wave inversion diffusely, which was unchanged from prior 

electrocardiogram.  His CK and troponin were unremarkable.  His 

troponin was 1.1, which was similar to a previous admission.

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was treated with beta 

blocker and aspirin in the Emergency Department.

FINAL DIAGNOSES:

1.  Angina pectoris.

2.  Hypertension.

3.  Tachycardia.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was  

admitted to the Medical service for further evaluation.  He was 

admitted in satisfactory condition.

___________________________________                    FM381/03624 

WILLIAM YARGER, M.D.       RY70                         D:01/10/72 

                                                       T:01/10/72 

Dictated by:  WILLIAM YARGER, M.D.       RY70 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2072-01-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="57" text="LAGRANGE" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="83" end="95" text="LOUIS,ROBERT" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="98" end="109" text="855-88-85-2" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="140" end="148" text="01/10/72" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="300" end="302" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<ID id="P6" start="2506" end="2517" text="FM381/03624" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="2520" end="2534" text="WILLIAM YARGER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="2547" end="2551" text="RY70" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2578" end="2586" text="01/10/72" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2646" end="2654" text="01/10/72" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2671" end="2685" text="WILLIAM YARGER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2698" end="2702" text="RY70" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>