<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2089-01-27

Potomac Valley Hospital

Preadmission Testing Area

History & Physical Examination

and Anesthesia Assessment

Yvonne Easton, N.P.

Jenna Corona, N.P.

Xochitl Narvaez, N.P.



Frederick Q. Valladares, M.D.

Medical Director

January 27, 2089



Medical Record Number:  8751045  Francisco, Xue



Procedure:  The patient is a 56-year-old Spanish-speaking female scheduled for laparoscopic cholecystectomy.  Surgery is scheduled on January 28, 2089 by Dr. Xavier Israel kenneth Xenos.



Chief Complaint & Present Illness:  Patient briefly evaluated on 12/30/88 as part of preoperative evaluation for a laparoscopic cholecystectomy then scheduled for 12/31/88.  Over the past year patient has had difficulty with right upper quadrant pain as well as epigastric pain.  These episodes tend to happen more frequently after she has had a rich meal.  Other symptoms that occurred include nausea and vomiting.  Patient denies jaundice.  Today, patient states that she still has some abdominal tenderness greatest at the right costal margin and radiating into right flank.



At the time of evaluation on 12/30/88 patients had symptoms of URI and LRI.  She reported back/green sputum, mild shortness of breath and increased use of her grandson's inhaler.  After consultation with Dr. Valladares it was decided that patient should be evaluated by her primary care provider for further treatment of her respiratory tract infection and then follow-up with surgeon to reschedule her surgery.  Patient reports that she went to University Hospital and there they treated her with antibiotics and inhaler.  Unfortunately patient is unable to recall the name of the antibiotic or the inhaler.  Currently she denies any symptoms of sputum production, cough, shortness of breath, or wheezing.  Also denies fever, chills, nausea, vomiting, and diarrhea.



Patient does have a history of coronary artery disease.  She is status post an MI 11/82.  Patient had cardiac catheterization at OSH 12/3/82 that reportedly showed a critical mid right lesion and a mild left main and left anterior descending lesion.  12/09/82 patient underwent cardiac catheterization at PVH and a PTCA was done.  Patient did well until 10/83 when she was admitted to PVH with symptoms of chest tenderness, left arm pain, tachycardia, palpitations, diaphoresis, dry mouth, shortness of breath, dizziness, and darkening of revision.  Patient did rule out for MI by serial enzymes and there are no changes seen on her ECG.  Patient denies any difficulty with chest pain or left arm pain since that time.  She has had episodes of shortness of breath with exertion however, these seem more related to her respiratory status rather than her cardiac disease.



Stress test done 1/26 showed a normal exercise capacity (METS=7), ECG nondiagnostic for ischemia and the perfusion images were suggestive of anterior ischemia although body habitus limited the interpretation.







Past Medical History:  Significant medical problems include:  

1.  Hypertension

2.  CAD, status post MI 2082, status post PTCA 2082

3.  Asthma (no hospitalizations or intubations)

4.  Arthritis

5.  Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (with clinical manifestations of arthralgia, TTP and a high urine titer)

6.  Chronic low back pain, history of herniated discs

7.  Depression



Past Surgical History:  Prior surgery includes:

1.  Status post cardiac catheterization and PTCA, 9/82  

2.  Status post D&C secondary to prolonged menstrual bleeding

3.  Status post tubal ligation

4.  Status post T&A



Family History:  There is no family history of adverse reactions to general anesthesia.

Brother: alive, CAD

Brother: alive, kidney disease

2 brothers: both alive, diabetes

Sister: deceased age 38, breast CA



Medications:  

paxil 20 mg q.d.

atenolol 25 mg q.d.

prednisone 10 mg q.d.

hydroxychloroquine q.d.

nifedipine XR 60 mg q.d.

isosorbide 10 mg t.i.d.

asthma inhaler (patient unable to recall name)

aspirin



Allergies:  NKA

denies food and environmental allergies



Social History:



Smoking:  denies

Alcohol use:  denies

Substance Abuse:  denies

Allergen Exposure (blood products/pregnancy): none in last 3 months

Exercise:  going up and down stairs usually, shortness of breath, expanses released when she rests at the top of the stair and drinks water; able to do light housework

Occupation:  Firefighter

Marital Status:  divorced, four children



Review of Systems:  



General:  negative	

HEENT: currently, LRI symptoms have resolved and patient feels much better

Cardiovascular: see HPI

Respiratory: patient reports a diagnosis of asthma however her primary care provider (Dr. Younker X1-1335) who has seen patient for two years does not recall patient having any diagnosis of asthma

Neurological: 9/81 patient admitted to PVH with thrombocytopenia purpura.  Suffered a cerebral thrombus with infarction.  Symptoms at the time of admission were severe headache, facial numbness, and facial droop as well as mutism.  Patients underwent plasma phosphor uses and became acutely hypoxic and hypotensive requiring emergent intubation.  Was felt that patient's symptoms or secondary to a transfusion reaction.  No residual symptoms.

Gastrointestinal: negative

Hepatobiliary: negative

Renal/Genitourinary: negative

Musculoskeletal: arthritis affecting hands, and hips, knees, ankles, and elbows

Peripheral Vascular: negative

Endocrine/metabolic: history of SLE

Heme/Onc: negative

Psychiatric: negative

Skin: negative



Vital Signs:



	BP:  149/75 mm Hg

	P:  61 bpm

	SaO2:  98%

	Temp:  98.2 degrees F

	Resp:  16 rpm

	Ht:  64 inches

	Wt:  196.6 pounds



Exam:



General:  well developed, well nourished female

HEEN&T:  buffalo hump, fair range of motion, no masses, neck veins flat, no bruits

Airway:  Mallampatti Class I

Teeth:  in good repair

Lungs:  clear to auscultation

Heart:  regular rhythm, no murmurs, S1=S2, no gallop

Abdomen:  diffuse abdominal tenderness with increased tenderness to palpation at costal margin right upper quadrant and radiating into flank, soft, not distended, normal bowel sounds, no organomegaly or palpable masses

GU/Rectal:  no CVA tenderness

Lymphatics:  no lymphadenopathy

Peripheral Vascular:

	carotids:  2+ bilateral no bruits

	radials:  2+ bilateral

Neurological:

	cranial nerves: II-XII grossly intact

Extremities:  no edema, lower extremities

Skin:  no ulcers or rashes observed



Assessment:  

ASA Physical Status II

56-year-old female with a history of CAD, SLE, hypertension, arthritis, asthma and chronic low back pain presents for laparoscopic cholecystectomy.  Patient originally scheduled for surgery on 12/31/88 however because of LRI surgery was postponed.  Patient much improved, lungs clear, no wheezing, no shortness of breath.  It has only been three-week since her infection and therefore increased airway reactivity may be an issue.  Dr. Hoffman explained this to patient.  Dr. Hoffman also reviewed with patient medications to take prior to surgery 1/28/89.  Currently, patient denies any symptoms of cardiac ischemia.  Does have chronic chest pain/tenderness which is reproducible by palpation.  Patient states that this is not her "cardiac pain".



Plan:



	Proposed Anesthetic: general

	Monitors:  standard

	Pain Management:  oral

	Autologous blood:  none

	Premedication:  stress steroid dosing

	Usual Medications:  paxil, atenolol, prednisone, hydroxychloroquine, nifedipine, Naprosyn, isosorbide, asthma inhaler, aspirin

	Medications to be held on day of surgery:  hydroxychloroquine, Naprosyn, aspirin

	Diabetic medications:  not applicable

	NSAIDS:  will stop as of 1/27/89

	Aspirin:  will stop as of 1/27/89

	NPO: after midnight the evening before surgery



Ancillary Studies:  

Pending







_______________________________________________

Jenna Q. Corona, MSN, RN, CS





PATA Medical Director Note:  



I have reviewed this preanesthetic assessment and concur with the assessment and recommended plan with the following exceptions:  







signed:  ____________________________________________________________



Attending Surgeon Reassessment Note:



I have reviewed the above history and physical exam and agree with the findings.  Additional comments: 







signed:  ___________________________________________________________ 



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2089-01-27" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="28" end="51" text="Potomac Valley Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="139" end="152" text="Yvonne Easton" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="160" end="172" text="Jenna Corona" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="180" end="195" text="Xochitl Narvaez" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="205" end="228" text="Frederick Q. Valladares" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="254" end="270" text="January 27, 2089" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P7" start="298" end="305" text="8751045" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="307" end="321" text="Francisco, Xue" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P9" start="354" end="356" text="56" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="459" end="475" text="January 28, 2089" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="483" end="510" text="Xavier Israel kenneth Xenos" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="580" end="588" text="12/30/88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="678" end="686" text="12/31/88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="1125" end="1133" text="12/30/88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="1304" end="1314" text="Valladares" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P16" start="1542" end="1561" text="University Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="1948" end="1953" text="11/82" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="1999" end="2006" text="12/3/82" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="2117" end="2125" text="12/09/82" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P20" start="2171" end="2174" text="PVH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="2220" end="2225" text="10/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P22" start="2251" end="2254" text="PVH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="2756" end="2760" text="1/26" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="3061" end="3065" text="2082" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="3084" end="3088" text="2082" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="3433" end="3437" text="9/82" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P27" start="3756" end="3758" text="38" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P28" start="4382" end="4393" text="Firefighter" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<NAME id="P29" start="4675" end="4682" text="Younker" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P30" start="4684" end="4690" text="1-1335" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P31" start="4797" end="4801" text="9/81" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P32" start="4822" end="4825" text="PVH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P33" start="6486" end="6488" text="56" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P34" start="6679" end="6687" text="12/31/88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P35" start="6921" end="6928" text="Hoffman" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P36" start="6961" end="6968" text="Hoffman" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P37" start="7033" end="7040" text="1/28/89" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P38" start="7667" end="7674" text="1/27/89" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P39" start="7703" end="7710" text="1/27/89" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P40" start="7849" end="7864" text="Jenna Q. Corona" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>