<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2064-09-10

                                                       Patient Name: ISENBERG,MICHAEL [ MRN: 3674193HCC ]

                                                         Date of Visit: 9/10/2064



Vascular Surgery Consult Note:



I am asked to examine Mr. Isenberg and comment on recent CT findings of a intraluminal defect in the right subclavian artery.



PMH / PSH:

1.	CAD - S/p  2-V CABG off pump in 4/64

2.	CHF- EF 38%, mild MR, diffusely hypokinetic LV w/ apical aneurysm, RVSP 46mmHg, upper 

segment septal hypertrophy w/o evidence of obstruction on TTE on 3/24/64

3.	HTN

4.	Hyperlipidemia

5.	DMII

6.	CRI- Baseline Pcr is between 1.6-1.8



Medications: 

Plavix 75 mg qd

Aspirin 325 mg qd

Lipitor 80 mg qd

Lisinopril 2.5 mg qd

Atenolol 25 mg qd

Fluoxetine 10 mg qd

 	 	 	 	

Allergies: NKDA





Mr Isenberg is a 82 yo gentleman one week out from attempted placement of right subclavian pacemaker- complicated by brief arterial puncture, prompt removal of the arterial catheter and successful compression. Duplex ultrasonography after compression showed no evidence of a pseudoaneurysm. A CTA done yesterday to evaluate his thyroid was  read as: 



" Hematoma around right subclavian artery.  Narrowing of the artery. Apparent filling defect, most likely artifactual.  If thrombus is of clinical concern, upper extremity ultrasound may be obtained."



On physical examination, he has mild non expansile hematoma of the right chest wall. His right hand is warm and well perfused, with 1+ radial and brachial pulses. There are no thrills or bruits.



My review of arterial components of the CT show the following:

1). Hematoma- to be expected

2). Diffuse arterial calcifications- obscures the ability to read what is or is not in the lumen.

3). Venous contrast bolus delivered on the right side- obscures our ability to discern the anatomy in the area of the subclavian artery.

4). Contrast bolus inadequate to comment on arterial anatomy.



Based on his clinical exam, and the fact that he is on an anticoagulant, a follow up subclavian artery ultrasound examination is in order. This test should be geared towards determining whether there is any evidence of a pseudoaneurysm. If there is an intraarterial filling defect, I would not pursue it. He is anticoagulated and his arm is viable. There are no stigmata of atheroemboli.





Uriel A. Xavier, MD



     











]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2064-09-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="97" end="113" text="ISENBERG,MICHAEL" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="121" end="128" text="3674193" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="128" end="131" text="HCC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="207" end="216" text="9/10/2064" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="280" end="288" text="Isenberg" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="430" end="434" text="4/64" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="592" end="599" text="3/24/64" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="845" end="853" text="Isenberg" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P9" start="859" end="861" text="82" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2387" end="2402" text="Uriel A. Xavier" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>