<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2084-03-17

 



Mediquik Team 3 Medical Student Admission Note



Pt:  Vollmer, Ulyses	

MR#: 	8740465

Date of Admission: 03/17/84

Attending Oncologist: Dr. Xavier Otero

PCP:  Dr. Geno Guidry

Code Status: Full Code



ID/CC:  73-year-old man with stage IV-B metastatic esophageal adenocarcinoma presents complaining of three days of constant dizziness.



Source:  Patient, who is a good historian.  Past medical records.



History of Present Illness  



Mr. Vollmer is a pleasant 73-year-old man with a past medical history significant for metastatic esophageal adenocarcinoma s/p XRT and chemotherapy, CAD s/p LAD stent placement, and borderline DM who presents to the Health Care Center complaining of 48-hour history of dizziness and subjective fevers.  He was in his usual state of health until three days prior to admission, when he awoke in the morning with a severe headache.  As he got out of bed, he felt extremely lightheaded.  He describes the dizziness as internal, and    not like the room was spinning.     He laid down, with some resolution of the symptoms.  Of note, he reports that the dizziness is less severe when he lies down and comes on with standing or sitting up.  Throughout the day, he developed a cough productive of green sputum, a subjective fever, continued headache, and nausea without vomiting.  He denied any chills, shortness of breath, chest pain, palpitations, or pain upon deep breathing.  That evening, two nights prior to admission, he developed night sweats but had no rigors.  He continued to feel similarly throughout the day prior to admission, and presented to the emergency room for further evaluation.  



The current presentation is in the context of increasingly poor PO intake secondary to chemotherapy and treatment for esophageal cancer.  He reports a four-to-five month history of poor appetite, eating chicken soup.  He denies any trouble swallowing solids or liquids.  Of note, the day prior to the onset of symptoms, he was NPO for a restaging CT scan.  He reports eating two scrambled eggs after the scan, and a chicken potpie for dinner the night prior to symptoms starting.



In the emergency room, vitals were temperature of 95.6, pulse 52, blood pressure 132/68, RR=20, 95% on room air.   He received Zofran 4 mg IV once, levofloxacin 500 mg PO once, and a NS 500 cc bolus.  CXR showed bibasilar infiltrate and bilateral pleural effusions.



Oncology History (per attending notes)

Patient is a 72 year old man who began having dysphagia 6/83.  On 8/01/83 he was scheduled for a Colonoscopy, so his PCP suggested he have an UGI Endoscopy at the same time.  The Colonoscopy demonstrated Diverticulosis and the UGI Endoscopy demonstrated a partially obstructing esophageal/gastric cardia tumor which was biopsied.  Pathology revealed moderately to poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma.  On 8/10/83 an Abd and Pelvic CT were done showing:  marked thickening of the wall of the distal esophagus (35-40cm by endoscopy - partial obstruction and circumferential) extending into the gastric cardia, consistent with biopsy proven adenocarcinoma. Also felt to be bleeding silently so placed on Fe replacement. Also, enlarged gastroepiploic, celiac and aortocaval lymph nodes consistent with metastatic disease.  On 8/10/83 a Chest CT revealed thickening of the lower esophagus extending into the chest esophageal junction.  This is associated with lymphadenopathy in the (L) axilla, gastrohepatic ligament, celiac axis and retrocrural space.  The appearance is highly suspicious for esophageal cancer and nodal spread.  There is a 3mm nodule adjacent to the (R) major fissure in the lung. PET scan confirmed axillary and abdominal involvement with cancer. The lung nodule was too small for PET to evaluate. 3/14/84 Restaging work-up revealed progressive disease (see imaging below).



His last Taxotere treatment was February 17; further treatment was stopped secondary to a chemotherapy burn on the right arm.



Past Medical History:  



1.	Metastatic esophageal adenocarcinoma:  Stage IV-B s/p Taxotere therapy.

2.	Diabetes mellitus:  Not taking any medications for sugar control.  Last HgBA1c (06/19/83) was 5.30.

3.	HTN:  On multiple medications for blood pressure control.  No evidence of end-stage renal damage.

4.	Hypercholesterolemia:  Being treated with Lipitor 10 mg daily.  Last total cholesterol (06/18/83) was 139; HDL=38, LDL=72.

5.	CAD s/p LAD stent placement 04/12/83

6.	Renal vein thrombosis, on coumadin.

7.	s/p Zenker diverticulum repair in 2080

8.	Chronic renal insufficiency:  Baseline creatinine of 1.2-1.5. 



Medications:  	

Atenolol 25 mg QD

Triamterene/HCTZ 50/25 QD Three times a week

Vitamin B Complex 100 u QD

Folic Acid 1 mg QD

Iron Sulfate 1 tab BID

Lipitor 10 mg QHS

Terazosin 5 mg QD

Ducolax 2 tabs QD

Warfarin 5 mg QD

Zantac 75 mg QD PRN heartburn.



Allergies: 

Codeine. Reaction-dizziness



Family History:   

Mother and maternal grandmother died from heart disease.  Father died from renal failure.  No family history of cancer.



Social History:  

	Smoking:  Denies history of smoking.

	Alcohol use:  Drinks rarely, approximately six beers each year. 

	Substance Abuse: Not assessed.  

	Occupation:  Retired.  Former aerospace engineer of forty years.

	Marital Status: Never married  

Living Situation:  Lives alone at home.  Independent ADLs.



ROS:	

General:   Reports anorexia, 20-pound weight loss over the last year.

Head:  As per HPI.  Reports dizziness, headache, h/o head injury, and lightheadedness.

Eyes: Denies vision changes.

Ears: Denies hearing loss, tinnitus, vertigo, or earaches/discharge.  

Nose and Sinuses: Reports nosebleeds secondary to Coumadin.  Denies frequent colds, stuffiness, itching, hayfever, or other sinus troubles.

Mouth and Throat: Denies dry mouth.

Neck:   Denies lumps, pain, swollen glands, or stiffness in the neck.

Respiratory:  Denies SOB, , wheezing, and asthma.

Cardiovascular: Denies palpitations, tachycardia.

GI:  Mild heartburn. Denies dysphagia, hematemasis, BRBPR, diarrhea, constipation.

Urinary Tract: Denies pain/burning upon urination, discharge.

Peripheral Vascular: Denies claudication, varicose veins, cold limbs.

Endocrine:  Reports some cold intolerance. Denies excessive sweating, thirst, and hunger. 

Neurological:  One episode of syncope one year ago because of hypotension secondary to too many blood pressure medications. Denies generalized weakness, numbness/sensation loss, or memory loss. 

Psychiatric: Denies depression, suicidal ideation.  



Exam:  	Pt is a pleasant, well-appearing man who is in no acute distress.  Patient is cooperative to interview.

	VS:  	Temperature=97.5; BP=140/70; HR=74; RR=18.

HEENT:  NC/AT, PERRL, nonicteric.  EOMI. No temporal tenderness.  MMM, w/o exudates or evidence of mucocitis or thrush.

Neck:  	Supple, NT, full ROM, 2+ carotids w/o bruits, no LAD. JVP <5cm

Lungs:  	Decreased bibasilar breath sounds, R>L. Fine crackles at the right base. Without wheezes.

Cor:  	RRR; normal S1S2, 3/6 systolic ejection murmur heard best at the right sternal base, radiating to the axilla, consistent with AS.

Abd:  	BS active.  Abdomen mildly distended.  Tympanic to percussion over all quadrants.  Soft, nontender to palpation in all areas.  Liver spanned 10 cm at the midclavicular line.  NO hepatosplenomegaly, liver edge not felt.  

G/R: 	Brown stool.  Non-tender prostate.

Extr:  	1+ edema bilateral lower extremities.   2+ DP, radial pulses bilaterally.

Skin:	Large, sharply demarcated erythematous patch over right wrist.

Neuro: 	AOx3, MS nl, CN II through XII intact, some nystagmus on lateral and vertical gaze, motor and sensory nonfocal-5/5 plantarflexion, dorsiflexion, grip strength, hip flexors and extensors; DTR's 2+ and symmetric throughout in biceps and patellar tendons. Babinski down.





Labs:  



Chemistry:	   

          	03/17/84  

          	08:51     



NA        	139       

K         	3.8       

CL        	112(H)    

CO2       	24.4      

BUN       	14        

CRE       	1.3       

GLU       	145(H)    

CA        	8.8       

PHOS      	2.5(L)    

MG        	1.8              	          

TP        	6.4       

ALB       	3.3       

GLOB      	3.1       

ALT/SGPT  	19        

AST/SGOT  	29        

ALKP      	47        

TBILI     	0.8       

DBILI     	0.3       







Cardiac markers

          	03/17/84  

          	09:51     



CK-MB    	Negative  

TROP-I    	Negative  

         	          

Hematology:	

          	03/17/84  

          	08:47     



WBC       	4.5       

RBC       	5.27      

HGB       	11.9(L)   

HCT       	38.4(L)   

MCV       	73(L)     

MCH       	22.6(L)   

MCHC      	31.0      

PLT       	168       

RDW       	17.1(H)   

DIFFR     	Received  

METHOD    	Auto      

%NEUT     	84(H)     

%LYMPH    	11(L)     

%MONO     	4         

%EOS      	1         

%BASO     	0        

 ANEUT     	3.81      

ALYMP     	0.51(L)   

AMONS     	0.18(L)   

AEOSN     	0.02(L)   

ABASOP    	0.01      

ANISO     	1+        

HYPO      	2+        

MACRO     	None     

MICRO     	3+        



Coagulation:

 

          	03/17/84  

          	08:47     



PT        	22.9(H)   

PTT       	29.2      



Miscellaneous Labs:

 

          	03/17/84  

          	08:47     



ESR       	24(H)     

 

UA:  Pending.

    	          	          	          

EKG:  NSR with ventricular rate of 83.  PR interval=180 ms; QRS interval=92 ms; QT=383 ms. Axis normal.  Good R-wave progression V3-V4.  No evidence of atrial enlargement or ventricular hypertrophy. No evidence of bundle branch blocks.  No  ST segment changes or Q waves.  Mild T wave flattening in III, aVF.



IMAGING:

CXR 03/17/84.

IMPRESSION:

	Bibasilar pneumonia with bilateral pleural effusions, greater on

	the left. In patient of this age group, follow up chest films are

	recommended to clearing.



Chest CT 03/14/84.

IMPRESSION:

	1.  Increasing mediastinal lymphadenopathy suspicious for

	metastatic disease.  Stable left axillary lymphadenopathy.

	2.  New small pericardial effusion and left pleural effusion.

	There is partial loculation of the left effusion.  There is

	significant increase in size in the right pleural effusion.

	3.  Interval increase in size in lingular and right upper lobe

	subpleural nodules suspicious for metastatic disease.

	4.  Stable bronchiectasis and bronchial wall thickening at both

	bases likely due to aspiration or radiation changes.



Abdominal/Pelvic CT:

IMPRESSION:

	Evidence of interval progression of disease, with worsening

	lymphadenopathy at the celiac axis and in the upper

	retroperitoneum and small amount of perihepatic ascites.

	

_____________________________________________________________________________________



I/P: 



73-year-old man with metastatic esophageal adenocarcinoma presents with bibasilar pneumonia and small bilateral pleural effusions.



1.	Pneumonia:  The patient presents with a two-day history of dizziness, subjective fevers, and productive cough of green sputum. Physical exam reveals decreased bibasilar breath sounds, right greater than left.  The constellation of symptoms can be attributed to the pneumonia found on chest imaging.  The possible causes of the pneumonia include aspiration, infectious, and post-obstructive causes. The patient reports no problems with swallowing and has not vomited, making aspiration pneumonia lower on the differential.   The chest CT does not show any evidence of tumor obstruction around the bronchi.  Further, the pneumonia and pleural effusions are bilateral, meaning that the obstruction would have to be higher in the bronchial tree, making obstruction less likely.  In this case the most likely cause is infectious in nature; the agents most likely to cause pneumonia in this patient are the typical bacteria, such as pneumococcus, H. influenza, Staphalococcus, and other gram-negative bugs, atypical bacteria such as Legionella sp, Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and Chlamydia pneumoniae, and viral causes.  Based upon imaging findings, pneumonia most consistent with a bacterial infectious agent.

a.	Start Levofloxacin 750 mg daily for antibacterial coverage.

b.	Sputum gram stain and culture

c.	Blood cultures

d.	Pneumococcus antigen screening

e.	U/A, urine Legionella

f.	  NS at 75 cc/hour.  If PO intake is not increased, will switch fluids to D5  NS.

g.	Tylenol for fever, Zofran for nausea.

h.	Incentive spirometry every two hours while awake.

2.	Dizziness:  The patient presents with a two-day history of dizziness.  Potential causes include orthostatic causes secondary to hypotension, dehydration, or poor sympthathetic tone; anxiety; cardiac causes (dysrhythmias, CAD), anemia, and electrolyte abnormalities (e.g. hypoglycemia).  This patient has a history of CAD, but EKG findings and cardiac enzymes do not suggest cardiac insult.  The patient has not had an increase in the BUN or creatinine from baseline, making dehydration less likely.  Labs did not show any electrolyte abnormalities; therefore hypoglycemia is low on the differential diagnosis.  The dizziness was positional in nature.  The patient reports long-standing poor PO intake, particularly because he was NPO for much of the day prior to the start of symptoms. In this patient, the cause of the dizziness is most likely orthostatic in nature, secondary to poor PO intake and decreased sympathetic tone.  

a.	  NS at 75 cc/hour.  If PO intake is not increased, will switch fluids to D5  NS.

b.	Check orthostatics daily.

3.	Metastatic esophageal adenocarcinoma:  Patient presents with known Stage IV-B metastatic esophageal adenocarcinoma with new CT findings suggestive of disease progression, particularly in the retroperitoneum.  Has been on Taxotere for the last six months.

a.	Patient does not know of new findings, to discuss with Dr. Otero in AM.

b.	Consider alternative therapies.

4.	Anemia: Patient presents with microcytic anemia (MCV=73).  Not known to be iron-deficient.

a.	Iron studies (Iron, Ferritin, TIBC) to assess iron deficiency versus anemia of chronic disease.

b.	Guaiac stool for evidence of occult blood.

5.	HTN:  

a.	Check orthostatics daily.

b.	Patient is stable on current regimen.  No changes to medications.

6.	CAD/hypercholesterolemia:

a.	Continue with Lipitor 10 mg daily

b.	Cardiac enzymes negative times one.  Per Oncology fellow, no need to cycle given stability of TW changes in EKG and lack of anginal symptoms

c.	Low fat diet

7.	Renal vein thrombosis: 

a.	Stable on Coumadin.

b.	Clarify goal INR level.  Currently INR=3.4.

8.	Prophylaxis:

a.	Nexium for GI prophylaxis

b.	Colace/Mylanta for constipation.

c.	Low-fat, no added salt, no concentrated sugar diet.

d.	Finger sticks after each meal.









_______________________________

Nathan Altman, HCC III 

Pager #74972







Team 3 Intern Addendum:

The patient was seen and examined.  Agree with above excellent HCC3 note.  Briefly, the patient is a 73 year-old male with h/o esophageal CA (Stage 4B), DM, HTN, CAD s/p LAD stent, renal v. thrombosis on Coumadin.  He presents today with 2 days of malaise, nausea, and    dizziness,     which he states does not consist of "room spinning" but that he does feel off-balance and is associated with nausea.  His PO intake has been decreased due to nausea.  Has has had a cough productive of green sputum, and CXR evidence of bibasilar consolidations and decreased breath sounds on exam R > L.  He was admitted to medicine for treatment of PNA in the setting of multiple comorbidities, and for lightheadedness on standing which is likely orthostatic.  



Will treat with Levofloxacin 750 PO QD to cover CAP.  Send legionella urinary Agn, and sputum cx (blood cx sent in ED).  Check orthostatics.  IVF gentle hydration.  Need to clarify goal INR in setting of Coumadin use for renal vein thrombosis.  Microcytic anemia-will check anemia labs; already on iron supplementation.  EKG and 1 set of cardiac enzymes do not suggest an acute cardiac event.  Will treat nausea symptomatically.  Discussed with onc fellow (Dr. Kramer).





____________________________

Gerald Echols MD

Pager 69793



      



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2084-03-17" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="33" end="41" text="Mediquik" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="88" end="103" text="Vollmer, Ulyses" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="112" end="119" text="8740465" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="140" end="148" text="03/17/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="176" end="188" text="Xavier Otero" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="200" end="211" text="Geno Guidry" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="247" end="249" text="73" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="482" end="489" text="Vollmer" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P9" start="504" end="506" text="73" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="694" end="712" text="Health Care Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P11" start="2482" end="2484" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2525" end="2529" text="6/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2535" end="2542" text="8/01/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="2875" end="2882" text="8/10/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="3292" end="3299" text="8/10/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="3784" end="3791" text="3/14/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="3895" end="3906" text="February 17" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="4178" end="4186" text="06/19/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="4392" end="4400" text="06/18/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="4459" end="4467" text="04/12/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="4546" end="4550" text="2080" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P22" start="5262" end="5280" text="aerospace engineer" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="7913" end="7921" text="03/17/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="8416" end="8424" text="03/17/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="8545" end="8553" text="03/17/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="9186" end="9194" text="03/17/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P27" start="9306" end="9314" text="03/17/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P28" start="9749" end="9757" text="03/17/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P29" start="9946" end="9954" text="03/14/84" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P30" start="10834" end="10836" text="73" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P31" start="13903" end="13908" text="Otero" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P32" start="14852" end="14865" text="Nathan Altman" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P33" start="14867" end="14870" text="HCC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P34" start="14884" end="14889" text="74972" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P35" start="14985" end="14988" text="HCC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P36" start="15023" end="15025" text="73" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P37" start="16135" end="16141" text="Kramer" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P38" start="16179" end="16192" text="Gerald Echols" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P39" start="16203" end="16208" text="69793" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>