<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2069-05-06

                     INDEPENDENT EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

JOSHI,KATHY   158-42-11-2

The resident's note was reviewed.  The patient was interviewed and 

examined by me.  I concur with the workup and evaluation of the 

patient in the emergency department.  For a more detailed note on 

this patient, please review the resident's note.  Please review the 

resident's note for past medical history, surgical history, review 

of systems, medications, allergies, social history and family 

history. 

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This patient is a 63-year-old 

female who presents to Independent Living Center Emergency Department with complaints of dyspnea on exertion.  The 

patient also complains of paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea.  She also 

complains of a cough.  She also complains of having fluid on her 

lower extremities.  She denies any other acute complaints.  She 

denies chest pain.  She denies nausea or vomiting or diaphoresis.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils 

are equal, round and reactive.  Fundi was positive for AV-nicking.  

NECK:  Mild jugular venous distention.  CHEST:  Rales audible 

bilaterally.  HEART:  Normal S1, S2.  No S3, S4.  No murmur.  

ABDOMEN:  Benign, soft, nontender.  No masses, guarding, rebound or 

organomegaly.  EXTREMITIES:  Grossly within normal limits.  

NEUROLOGICAL:  Awake, alert, able to follow all commands.  Negative 

Babinski. 

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Chest x-ray, electrocardiogram, CK, 

troponin I are all pending.  Electrocardiogram in the emergency 

department notes a second degree AV block of mobic type I.  She is 

also noted to have a rate of 69.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Most likely congestive failure.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The plan is an 

IV, 60 of Lasix IV, chest x-ray, CK, troponin, CBC, electrolytes, 

further workup and evaluation and most likely admission.  The 

patient is currently in stable condition. 

___________________________________                    JJ418/48466 

F. JORDAN FUCHS, M.D.       JF43                       D:05/06/69 

                                                       T:05/06/69 

Dictated by:  F. JORDAN FUCHS, M.D.       JF43 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2069-05-06" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="60" text="INDEPENDENT" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="86" end="97" text="JOSHI,KATHY" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="100" end="111" text="158-42-11-2" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<AGE id="P4" start="582" end="584" text="63" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="619" end="644" text="Independent Living Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<ID id="P7" start="2042" end="2053" text="JJ418/48466" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="2056" end="2071" text="F. JORDAN FUCHS" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2084" end="2088" text="JF43" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2113" end="2121" text="05/06/69" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2181" end="2189" text="05/06/69" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2206" end="2221" text="F. JORDAN FUCHS" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2234" end="2238" text="JF43" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>