<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2062-11-29

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
November 29, 2062
 
 
 
Benjamin Taylor, M.D.
58 Cathedral Circle
Three Rivers, NM  34963
 
RE:  Kathy Joshi
     ILC #158-42-11-2
 
Dear Dr. Taylor:
 
Mrs. Joshi returns after a one year hiatus.  She continues to
complain of rare retrosternal chest discomfort only occasionally
secondary to exertion.  These episodes occur on a roughly once a
month basis lasting anywhere from seconds to several minutes. 
Addition of long acting nitrates to her medical regimen has had no
effect on the frequency or severity of this syndrome and she does
not take Nitroglycerin for it.  A stress test performed last
January showed Mrs. Joshi exercising for 4 minutes and 30 seconds
of a Bruce protocol stopping at a peak heart rate of 119, peak
blood pressure of 150/70 secondary to dyspnea.  She had no ischemic
EKG changes noted, however, a simultaneously obtained Sesta-MIBI
scan revealed a minor fixed anterior wall defect as well as a small
surrounding area of transient ischemia.  In addition, there was a
moderately severe fixed inferior wall defect again with peri-
infarct mild ischemia.  Of note, her last serum cholesterol was 266
with an HDL of 52 and an LDL of 192. 
 
She remains on a regimen of Isosorbide mononitrate 60 mg p.o. q.d.,
aspirin 1 tab p.o. q.d, Metoprolol 50 mg p.o. b.i.d., NPH 12 units
S.C. q a.m. with 6 units CZI S.C. q a.m., and 15 units NPH S.C. q
p.m.. 
 
Physical exam reveals a well nourished, overweight woman in no
acute distress.  Blood pressure right arm sitting 160/90, heart
rate 67 and regular, respirations 12 and unlabored, weight 264
pounds, which is six pounds above her weight of one year ago.  The
neck is supple.  JVP flat.  Carotids are 2 + without bruits.  Chest
 
                             Page 2
 
Kathy Joshi
ILC #158-42-11-2
11-29-62
 
remains clear.  Cardiac exam reveals normal S1, physiologically
split S2 and a soft I/VI systolic ejection murmur.  The abdomen is
benign.  Extremities without appreciable edema.  
 
Electrocardiogram shows sinus rhythm at a rate of 67, P-R interval
.22, QRS .10, Q-T .36, axis 20 degrees.  There are isolated atrial
premature depolarizations noted along with first degree AV block
and a prior inferior posterior myocardial infarction with minor
nonspecific ST and T wave changes.  Compared to his last
electrocardiogram there has been no significant change.
 
Impression:  Mrs. Joshi continues to have evidence of mild, stable
angina.  I have asked her to begin Simvastatin at 20 mg p.o. q h.s.
for her significant hyperlipidemia and I strongly encouraged her to
more aggressively try to lower her caloric intake and increase her
aerobic activity level.  In addition, I have asked her to obtain
her blood pressure at least two or three more times on an
ambulatory basis and told her that if she remained reliably above
140/85 then I would consider initiating pharmacologic
antihypertensive therapy.  In addition, as long as she remains
active and asymptomatic, I will plan on repeating her exercise MIBI
stress test in one to one and a half years time.  Beyond this I
have not altered her present regimen. 
 
Of course, I thank you for allowing me to assist in her care.
 
Respectfully yours,
 
 
 
 
Brandon W. Neilson, M.D.
 
DD: 11-29-62
DT: 12-06-62
DV: 11-29-62
 
 
/wise
 
Crete Municipal Hospital
82 Auburn Street
Rehoboth, NM  42761
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2062-11-29" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="48" end="65" text="November 29, 2062" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="72" end="87" text="Benjamin Taylor" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="94" end="113" text="58 Cathedral Circle" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="114" end="126" text="Three Rivers" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="128" end="130" text="NM" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="132" end="137" text="34963" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="145" end="156" text="Kathy Joshi" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="162" end="165" text="ILC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<ID id="P9" start="167" end="178" text="158-42-11-2" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="190" end="196" text="Taylor" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="205" end="210" text="Joshi" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="649" end="656" text="January" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="669" end="674" text="Joshi" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="1790" end="1801" text="Kathy Joshi" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P15" start="1802" end="1805" text="ILC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<ID id="P16" start="1807" end="1818" text="158-42-11-2" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="1819" end="1827" text="11-29-62" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="2409" end="2414" text="Joshi" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="3232" end="3250" text="Brandon W. Neilson" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="3263" end="3271" text="11-29-62" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="3276" end="3284" text="12-06-62" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="3289" end="3297" text="11-29-62" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P23" start="3303" end="3307" text="wise" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P24" start="3310" end="3334" text="Crete Municipal Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P25" start="3335" end="3351" text="82 Auburn Street" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P26" start="3352" end="3360" text="Rehoboth" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P27" start="3362" end="3364" text="NM" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P28" start="3366" end="3371" text="42761" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>