<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2085-07-25

EDVISIT^51639357^NOONAN, FRANCE^07/25/85^ELROD, RYLEY

This patient was seen with Dr. Ussery.  I confirm that I have

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed the

evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 73-year-old male with a

history of cough and pleuritic type chest pain.  The patient

denies any nausea or vomiting.  He does have history of MI as

well as multiple risk factors for coronary artery disease.  He

also reports lower extremities swelling worse than usual, and has

left greater than right edema at baseline due to a reconstructive

surgery following motor vehicle collision.  Of note, the

patient's medications include Coumadin, which he is on for atrial

fibrillation.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is awake, alert, and in no

distress.  His vital signs show heart rate of 70, respiratory

rate of 24, blood pressure 112/72, and oxygen saturation 96% on

room air and 98% on 2 liters.  His lungs are clear and heart is

irregularly irregular.  This is somewhat limited due to body

habitus.  The abdomen is soft and there is a chronic left upper

quadrant tenderness.  The back shows left CVA tenderness.

LABORATORY DATA:  The laboratory analysis shows a hematocrit of

42.1 and a white blood cell count of 7.6.  Cardiac biomarkers are

negative, and the troponin is less than 0.1.  A d-dimer is less

than 200.  The INR is 1.7.  UA is pending.  ECG shows an atrial

fibrillation with some nonspecific T-wave changes in leads V3

through V6.

IMAGING STUDIES:  A chest radiograph was a markedly limited due

to patient's habitus.

DECISION MAKING AND EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  There was no

clear etiology to the patient's shortness of breath.  Given his

anticoagulation and a negative d-dimer, we feel that this is

unlikely to be PE.  It is clearly possible to be cardiac, given

the history of coronary artery disease and a slightly abnormal

electrocardiogram.  This may be pneumonia, and the chest x-ray is

not terribly helpful.  We are obtaining a CT scan of the chest

without IV contrast to better delineate the pulmonary

architecture, and are admitting the patient to the Medicine

Service for monitoring and cycling of enzymes and ECGs.

DIAGNOSES:

1.  Shortness of breath.

2.  T-wave inversions on electrocardiogram.

______________________________

ELROD, RYLEY M.D.

D: 07/25/85

T: 07/25/85

Dictated By: ELROD, RYLEY

eScription document:5-9812947 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2085-07-25" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="51639357" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="59" text="NOONAN, FRANCE" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="60" end="68" text="07/25/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="69" end="81" text="ELROD, RYLEY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="114" end="120" text="Ussery" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="366" end="368" text="73" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="2461" end="2473" text="ELROD, RYLEY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="2483" end="2491" text="07/25/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2496" end="2504" text="07/25/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2519" end="2531" text="ELROD, RYLEY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P11" start="2553" end="2562" text="5-9812947" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>