<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2088-11-29

LCFMC D Housestaff Admission Note
Intern: Woods
Att:Ball




CC: 

Dyspnea/Chest pain


HPI: 76 year old Spanish speaking male with numerous medical problems (IDDM, Afib, HTN, PVD, Cr baseline 1.7, no prior HF,, normal echo 2085, normal MIBI 2085) who was just dishcharged 28 days ago for LE edema admission, who complains of 3 weeks of sore throat. He states that because of this he has suffered from a gradual dyspnea, complicated by orthopnea and PND for two days.  He states he has left sided pleuritic chest pain worse with inspiration.  He states he also has noticed increased baseline LE edema for 2 weeks, but denies and increase in abdominal girth.  He states he decided to seek medical treatment for his gradual onset shortness of breath.


The patient states he has been taking all of his medications and has not increased the sodium in his diet recently.  He denies fever, chills, dysuria, asymettric leg swelling, or any palpable blood vessels in his legs.


Of note the patient is on 80 mg BID of lasix for his LE edema though his most recent echo, 2085, shows a normal EF and the patient has no history of CHF.


Ed Course: Routine labs and blood cultures were drawn.


ROS:  As above


PMH:

chronic LE ulcers AF on Coumadingout - currently no symptomsDMHTN OSAPVD CRI, bl cr=1.8Hypercholesterolemia


MEDS: patient doesnt know, from last DC summary

1. WARFARIN SODIUM   4 MG PO  QPM  2.  ACETAMINOPHEN   650 MG PO  Q4H     PRN Pain3.  ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID   325 MG PO  DAILY  4.  DOCUSATE SODIUM   100 MG PO  BID  5.  FLUTICASONE PROP/SALMETEROL 250/50   1 INHALATION INH  BID  6.  FUROSEMIDE   80 MG PO  BID  7.  GABAPENTIN   300 MG PO  TID  8.  INSULIN ASPART   Sliding Scale (subcutaneously) SC  AC+HS  9.  INSULIN NPH HUMAN   50 UNITS SC  BID  10. IPRATROPIUM AND ALBUTEROL SULFATE   2 PUFF INH  QID  11. LORATADINE   10 MG PO  DAILY  12. METOPROLOL TARTRATE   25 MG PO  BID  13. MUPIROCIN   TOPICAL TP  BID  14. NORTRIPTYLINE HCL   25 MG PO  BEDTIME  15. PROTONIX  (PANTOPRAZOLE)   40 MG PO  BID  16. POLYETHYLENE GLYCOL    17 GM PO  DAILY  17. SENNOSIDES   8.6 MG PO  BID  18. SIMVASTATIN   20 MG PO  BEDTIME  19. SPIRONOLACTONE   25 MG PO  BID  20. ALISKIREN   150 MG PO  DAILY  
ALL: NKDA


SH:Born in Paraguay. Wife died of colon cancer. Used to work in publishing, now retired. No smoking, rarely drinks EtOH. Occasionally smokes marijuana for pain relief.  Now lives w son. 



FH:Mother and brother with DM. Brother with MI 



PE: VS: T^ 96.4 P 69, P 114/62 RR 18 90% RA
General: well appearing, NAD
HEENT: Eyes: PERRLA, EOMI
Neck: very obese neck with no visible JVD
Lungs: CTA b/l, no rales/rhonchi/wheezes
Heart: RRR, 2/6 SM at LUSB
Abdomen: obese, soft, ND/NT, +BS, no hepatosplenomegaly
Extremities: 2+ radial/DP pulses, his lower extremities are wrapped in ace bandages and when unwrapped show signs of chronic venous stasis with no sign of active infection


LABS:
Results11/29/2088 NA 133 (*),  K 4.5,  CL 94 (*),  CO2 29,  BUN 72 (*#),  CRE 2.75 baseline 1.7 (*#),  EGFR 23 [1],  GLU 194 (*#)[1] RESULT COMMENT: (Abnormal if &lt;60 mL/min/1.73m2If patient is black, multiply by 1.21)11/29/2088 ANION 1011/25/2088 GLU-POC 340 (*)11/29/2088 CA 9.6,  PHOS 3.8,  MG 2.6,  TBILI 0.4,  TP 8.3,  ALB 3.8,  GLOB 4.5 (*)11/29/2088 ALT/SGPT 15,  AST/SGOT 17,  ALKP 103,  TBILI 0.411/29/2088 CK 165,  CK-MB 5.0,  TROP-T 0.03 (*), Troponin I always less than assay in past11/29/2088 WBC 8.68,  RBC 4.86,  HGB 15.2 (#),  HCT 45.1,  MCV 92.8,  MCH 31.3,  MCHC 33.8 (#),  PLT 18911/29/2088 RDW 14.311/29/2088 %POLY-A 62.4,  %LYMPH-A 31.1,  %MONO-A 5.2,  %EOS-A 0.9,  %BASO-A 0.411/29/2088 ANEUT-A 5.42,  ALYMP-A 2.69,  AMONO-A 0.45,  AEOS-A 0.08,  ABASO-A 0.0311/29/2088 PT 18.7 (*),  PT-INR 1.5 (*),  PTT 35.711/25/2088 PT 20.5 (*#) [1],  PT-INR 1.7 (*),  PTT 36.2 (#)[1] RESULT COMMENT: VERIFIED11/29/2088 proBNP 210


STUDIES:
11/29 EKG: Afib, rate 66, no ST changes


11/29 CXR:  IMPRESSIONS: Lingula opacity may represent pneumonia and/or     effusion. No effusion on Lateral view.     



9/13/85 Echo: Left Ventricle: Overall left ventricular function is normal. The estimatedejection fraction is 60%. There are no regional wall motion abnormalities.

2085 Cardiac MIBI: In summary, the test results were:     1.  Clinical Response:  Non-ischemic.     2.  ECG Response:  No ECG changes during infusion.     3.  Myocardial Perfusion:  Normal.     4.  Global LV Function:  Normal.



A/P: 76 yo male with PVD, COPD, LE edema, DM, comes in pan-pos ROS and chest pain/dyspnea x2-3d. Doing well until 3wks ago and then got sore throat. Chest pain/SOB started 2d ago. 
#) Chest Pain: nl echo in 2085; nl MIBI '06; symptoms w/inspiration not exertion; troponin up, MB flat, EKG w/out change; ? PE; ?Bornholm; pleuritis more likely-trend cardiac markers-Echo in AM*#) Acute/Chronic Renal Failure: ? from aggressive diuresis; spironolactone; s. poor forawrd flow-hold spriro/lasix/aliskiren-Echo in AM as above-renally dose all meds-gentle IVF over night*#) SOB: ?pnd; ?orthopnea: BNP nl, does not appear in any resp discomfort; cxr w/?pna but no other clincal sx-start levo 750mg q48hr-f/u echo
- will obtain non-con chest CT for better visualization*#) DM, type II: poorly controlled at home-NPH 50unit BID + SSI-diabetic diet*#) LE edema/Ulcers: looks good- cont wraps; wound care*#) HTN: on aliskiren/aldactone/metop- holding aliskiren/aldactone*#) FEN/PPx-heparin SC q8hr; renal diet; dM diet; coumadin;


Code: Full Code
HCP:NOONAN, WENDY
, child, 424-995-4624 





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2088-11-29" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="28" end="33" text="LCFMC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="70" end="75" text="Woods" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="80" end="84" text="Ball" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P4" start="121" end="123" text="76" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="252" end="256" text="2085" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="270" end="274" text="2085" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="1091" end="1095" text="2085" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="2256" end="2264" text="Paraguay" TYPE="COUNTRY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P9" start="2309" end="2319" text="publishing" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2938" end="2948" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3151" end="3161" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="3170" end="3180" text="11/25/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="3196" end="3206" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="3279" end="3289" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="3338" end="3348" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="3428" end="3438" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="3532" end="3542" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="3551" end="3561" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="3631" end="3641" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="3713" end="3723" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="3763" end="3773" text="11/25/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="3850" end="3860" text="11/29/2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="3883" end="3888" text="11/29" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="3925" end="3930" text="11/29" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="4048" end="4055" text="9/13/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="4212" end="4216" text="2085" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P27" start="4447" end="4449" text="76" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P28" start="4649" end="4653" text="2085" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P29" start="4664" end="4666" text="06" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P30" start="5482" end="5495" text="NOONAN, WENDY" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P31" start="5505" end="5517" text="424-995-4624" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>