<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2069-04-15

EDVISIT^49921666^Schwartz, Xavier^04/15/69^NOLAN, N. YANCY(49863884)

TIME OF DICTATION:  10:40 p.m.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Schwartz is an 82-year-old male

who presents to Gwinnett County Hospital Department of

Emergency Medicine.  He was sent to ED by his primary care

physician because of cough, productive of whitish sputum,

wheezing, and mild shortness of breath.  He denies fever.  He

denies chills.  He denies any other acute complaints.  He admits

to the above-mentioned symptoms.  At times they last for two to

three days' duration.  He has a temperature of 95, a pulse of 80,

respiratory rate of 20, blood pressure 153/80, and O2 saturation

95% on room air.

The resident's note was reviewed.  The patient was interviewed. 

The patient was examined by me.  I concur with the workup and

evaluation of the patient in ED.  For a more detailed note on

this patient, please review the resident's note.  Please review

the resident's note for past medical history, surgical history,

review of systems, medications, allergies, family history and

social history.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils

were equal, round, reactive.  Fundi were benign.  Neck was

supple.  Chest was positive for coarse rhonchi and wheezes

bilaterally.  Heart:  Notes a normal S1, S2.  No S3, S4.  No

murmur.  Abdomen is benign, soft, nontender, no masses, guarding,

rebound, and organomegaly.  Extremities:  Grossly within normal

limits.  Neurologically, awake, alert, able to follow all

commands.  Negative Babinski.

Chest x-ray in the emergency department was negative for

infiltrates.  Also negative for interstitial edema.  The EKG

notes a paced rhythm at a rate of 91.  White count of 8,

hematocrit was 36, normal serum electrolytes.  Normal CK, normal

troponin.

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

breath most likely secondary to acute bronchitis.

PLAN:  Admit to the Inpatient Service for further workup and

evaluation.

______________________________

NOLAN, N. YANCY M.D. (49863884)	D: 04/15/69

					T: 04/16/69

Dictated By: NOLAN, N. YANCY





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2069-04-15" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="49921666" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="61" text="Schwartz, Xavier" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="62" end="70" text="04/15/69" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="71" end="86" text="NOLAN, N. YANCY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P5" start="87" end="95" text="49863884" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="163" end="171" text="Schwartz" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="178" end="180" text="82" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="212" end="236" text="Gwinnett County Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2058" end="2073" text="NOLAN, N. YANCY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P10" start="2080" end="2088" text="49863884" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2093" end="2101" text="04/15/69" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2111" end="2119" text="04/16/69" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2134" end="2149" text="NOLAN, N. YANCY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>