<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2090-04-09

                     VALLEY LANE EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

                                                VISIT DATE: 04/09/90

The patient was seen and examined in the emergency department on 

04/09/90.  The patient was seen with Dr. Jarman.  I have discussed 

management with the resident physician, reviewed the medical 

record.  

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Possible seizure.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 72-year-old gentleman 

who was brought in after having an episode of being unresponsive, 

per his wife.  He seemed to have his eyes roll back in his head.  

There was no definite tonic-clonic movement.  His wife relates the 

fact that he had seizures in the past although she does not know if 

this was a seizure.  Patient denied chest pain, shortness of 

breath, or abdominal pain.  No history of trauma.  

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Patient denies fever or chills, otherwise, 

negative.  

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diabetes, CABG, seizure disorder.

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Patient is a past smoker.  

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  Patient is comfortable, awake, 

alert but not oriented to date, in no acute distress.  HEENT:  

Normocephalic, atraumatic.  CHEST:  Clear. HEART:  Regular rate.  

ABDOMEN:  Soft, nontender.  EXTREMITIES:  Nontender.   

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  White count 8.3, hematocrit 36.2, 

creatinine 0.7, CK 107.  EKG shows peak T-waves anteriorly, T-waves 

are peak compared to old.   

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  This gentleman had a syncopal 

episode which may represent seizure activity.  Also, with his EKG 

changes, plan is for hospital admission for telemetry, for 

observation, and will also get neurologic consultation.  

CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  Neurology.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 

in stable condition.

___________________________________                    KW419/3572

ANDREW TANG, M.D.  AT57                                 D:04/09/90 

                                                       T:04/11/90 

Dictated by:  ANDREW TANG, M.D.  AT57 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2090-04-09" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="60" text="VALLEY LANE" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P2" start="146" end="154" text="04/09/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="223" end="231" text="04/09/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="264" end="270" text="Jarman" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="452" end="454" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<ID id="P6" start="1943" end="1953" text="KW419/3572" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="1955" end="1966" text="ANDREW TANG" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="1974" end="1978" text="AT57" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2013" end="2021" text="04/09/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2081" end="2089" text="04/11/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2106" end="2117" text="ANDREW TANG" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2125" end="2129" text="AT57" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>