<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2079-06-10

					

Novolog 3-10 tid	683-51-28

Lantus 19-20 at hs	Xuan, Wendy

CellCept 1000 mg bid 

Rapamune 2/1 mgs qod

Toprol XL 25 mg qd

Lipitor 10 mg qd

Neurontin 600/1200 mg bid

Tums 200 mg ii qd (should be at least bid)

Prilosec 20 mg bid

MVI i bid

ASA 325 mg qd

Tylenol 1325 mg over the day for arthritis

Wellbutrin 150 mg bid

Androgel to leg qd

DHEA 25 mg qd

Celexa 80 mg qAM  (Dr. Colin Keane)



Jun 10, 2079



Interim History:	

Comes to review her medical problems.

She has been well overall but has been bothered by trigger finger (R ring). She has seen Dr. Ibarra, who has suggested surgery since a steroid injection did not help.

Brings no test results. No severe hypoglycemia.

Retinopathy:	Saw Dr. Aragon yesterday. Stable. Last laser was about 5 years ago. 1 year.

Nephropathy:	Reports that she cannot do blood tests at KJH since she gets copays. Covered if done at Promptcare. She does not recall when her BUN/Cr were last checked but says that it was prior to January and that results were sent to Dr. Hayes. 

Neuropathy:	Not much troubled by neuropathy.  She still has the sensation of food or liquid getting stuck mid sternal level. BaS last year showed GERD and dysmotility. I am not sure that Reglan would help, but have reluctance to try it in any case because of her long history of depression. 

Cardiac:	She thinks that she may be having dyspnea on exertion that is easier to precipitate than it had been. She has had some sternal discomfort at rest on two occasions while sitting at rest - felt bony. She says that she has been    trying to ignore    the possible increase in dyspnea on exertion. She sees Dr. Dotson in October. 

Vascular:	No claudication



Past Medical History: 

Medications: Stopped Quinine; increased Celexa. Did not start simvastatin since did not have blood work done. 



Social History:

Ivory is well. 



Review of Systems: above

Skin: Saw colleague of Dr. Keeler yesterday. Given cream for scalp.

Gyn: Report that Yareli Kilgore will no longer see her for routine follow-up. Periods are regular. Does not use contraception. Has never been pregnant. Discussed this and she left it that she is not worried about it.



Physical Exam:	

Looks well.

BP:   120/76		P:   82, regular

Wt:   161.5 without shoes, stable

HEENT:	Anicteric. 

Carotids:	Normal pulses, without bruits

Chest:	Clear to auscultation

Breasts:	No masses; no nodes	

Nodes:	No cervical, supraclavicular, axillary

Heart:	Normal S1; physiologic S2.  S4.  2/6 systolic ejection murmur

Abdomen:	No hepatosplenomegaly. No masses. No tenderness. No palpable AAA. 

Extremities:	No edema.        DP 1-2+,=.  PT absent.   L great toenail appears to be about to be lost, thickened with probable subungual hematoma.

Neurological:	AJ absent.  



Impressions and Plan:	

Will get ETT with imaging. Need approval from her insurance. Call if she has any more convincing cardiac symptoms.

She should see Yareli Holcomb, NP for Pap with history of HPV and abnormal Paps in the past. 

She should see Dr. Xie for foot care. 

Strongly suggest she get some labs in the next week or so, fasting:

A1c, lipids, Electrolytes, BUN/Creatinine, CBC, SGOT, SGPT, alkaline phosphatase, Bili T/D, urinalysis





Appointments:	Yareli Holcomb, NP as above

	Me 4 months



cc:	Xavier Dotson, M.D.

	Henry Hayes, M.D.





			Yacob T. Kane, M.D., Ph.D.





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2079-06-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="52" end="61" text="683-51-28" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="82" end="93" text="Xuan, Wendy" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="420" end="431" text="Colin Keane" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="436" end="448" text="Jun 10, 2079" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="603" end="609" text="Ibarra" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="748" end="754" text="Aragon" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="872" end="875" text="KJH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="918" end="928" text="Promptcare" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1014" end="1021" text="January" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="1056" end="1061" text="Hayes" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="1674" end="1680" text="Dotson" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="1684" end="1691" text="October" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="1879" end="1884" text="Ivory" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="1951" end="1957" text="Keeler" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="2010" end="2024" text="Yareli Kilgore" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="2959" end="2973" text="Yareli Holcomb" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="3058" end="3061" text="Xie" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="3270" end="3284" text="Yareli Holcomb" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="3319" end="3332" text="Xavier Dotson" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="3341" end="3352" text="Henry Hayes" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P21" start="3367" end="3380" text="Yacob T. Kane" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>