<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2061-01-31

EDVISIT^32707420^GIPSON, ALEXANDER^01/31/61^VELASQUEZ, WALTER

This patient was seen by myself and Dr. Hardin on 01/31/2061.  I

confirm I interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the

resident's documentation, and discussed the plan of care with the

patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 73-year-old gentleman who

has a history of CAD status post stent in 2060, who developed

acute chest discomfort, pressure like, diaphoresis, and weakness,

while he was working as a chiropractor.  He says although this

was quite significant, it was not like his prior MI discomfort. 

He denies any radiation to his back or his arm.  He denies any

jaw pain.  He denies any fever, chills, or sweats.  He denies any

vomiting.  He denies any headache or neck pain.  He denies any

bowel or bladder changes and no lower extremity edema.  He is

taking his medicines.  He also took an aspirin, did get some

nitroglycerin.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diabetes, hypertension,

hypercholesterolemia, and CAD.

MEDICATIONS:  Cozaar, aspirin, Altace, metformin, and Toprol.

ALLERGIES:  He has no known drug allergies.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He is a past smoker, not a drinker or drug user.

 He lives with his family.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As noted in the HPI, otherwise negative.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He is in no acute distress at rest.  He

says his chest pain is essentially gone on oxygen.  Vital signs

are as noted.  Head, eyes, ears, nose, and throat:  Normocephalic

and atraumatic.  Pupils are equal and reactive to light. 

Extraocular motions are intact.  Oropharynx is unremarkable. 

Neck is supple.  There is no jugular venous distention.  Chest is

clear to auscultation.  Heart is regular rate and rhythm.  His

abdomen is soft and nontender.  There is no hepatosplenomegaly. 

There are no masses.  His skin is warm and dry.  There is no

lower extremity edema.  He has equal pulses.  His neuro exam is

alert and oriented to person, place, and time.  His cranial

nerves are intact.  He is grossly nonfocal.

LABORATORY DATA:  He has a white count of 8, hematocrit of 46,

and platelet count of 200,000.  His SMA-7 is unremarkable.  CK-MB

and troponin are flat and INR is 1.  His EKG shows less than 1 mm

ST depressions in V2, without any reciprocal or other changes.

ASSESSMENT:  The patient with a history of CAD with concerning

symptoms.  He did have a fight earlier in the day, although was

not under significant stress at the time of this event.  Given

his prior CAD history, the patient was given Lopressor.  Decision

was made to admit him for rule out acute coronary syndrome.  The

patient was admitted in stable condition.  The patient had

already got an aspirin and the patient remained in stable

condition until he was admitted.

DIAGNOSIS:  Rule out acute coronary syndrome.

______________________________

VELASQUEZ, WALTER M.D.

D: 01/31/61

T: 02/01/61

Dictated By: VELASQUEZ, WALTER

eScription document:9-1137686 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2061-01-31" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="32707420" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="62" text="GIPSON, ALEXANDER" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="63" end="71" text="01/31/61" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="72" end="89" text="VELASQUEZ, WALTER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="131" end="137" text="Hardin" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="141" end="151" text="01/31/2061" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="335" end="337" text="73" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="404" end="408" text="2060" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P9" start="518" end="530" text="chiropractor" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2871" end="2888" text="VELASQUEZ, WALTER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2898" end="2906" text="01/31/61" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2911" end="2919" text="02/01/61" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2934" end="2951" text="VELASQUEZ, WALTER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P14" start="2973" end="2982" text="9-1137686" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>