<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2060-07-28




GIPSON, ALEC
32707420
07/28/2060


Vernon Lozano, M.D.
CV Division, Ireton Medical Clinic
91 Neptune Lane
Abilene, FL  81494

Dear Vernon,

I write to summarize for your records the recent IMC course of your patient, Dr. Alec Gipson, who was admitted to our cardiology service on 07/25/2060 with progressive angina and a small, non-ST elevation MI.  His cardiac troponin rose to 0.13.  There were no demonstrable ECG changes, though we queried the possibility of a left circumflex event.  He had been previously scheduled for semi-urgent catheterization and angiography on 07/26/2060.

His condition stabilized with institution of anti-thrombotic and anti-ischemic therapy.  He was taken to the catheterization laboratory by Dr. Otero on 07/26/2060.  Angiography demonstrated a high-grade lesion in the proximal portion of a large first diagonal branch, as well as a significant stenosis in the first obtuse marginal branch.  The diagonal lesion was managed with angioplasty and deployment of a drug-eluting stent.  A drug-eluting stent could not be delivered to the obtuse marginal lesion; a bare-metal stent was positioned without difficulty.  He did have smoldering chest discomfort of an anginal nature following the procedure.  The cardiac troponin elevated further to a peak value of 0.86 as of 07/27/2060 (08:54).  He also had a mild, vagal reaction characterized by flushing and transient bradycardia.

He felt much improved the following day.  A repeat cardiac troponin returned at a lower level of 0.75.  An abdominal ultrasound showed no evidence of an AAA.  After consultation with you, we felt that he could return home, under the care of his wife.

He was discharged on the afternoon of 07/27/2060.  His medications included Ecotrin 325 mg daily, clopidogrel 75 mg daily, losartan 100 mg daily, metformin 500 mg b.i.d., Toprol-XL 50 mg b.i.d., niacin 500 mg b.i.d., ramipril 2.5 mg daily, and nitroglycerin if needed.

Please let me know if I can provide you with any further information.

Sincerely yours,


______________________________
Victor Quijano, M.D.





eScription document:6-5332849 DFFocus



DD: 07/28/60
DT: 07/29/60
DV: 07/28/60



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2060-07-28" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="31" end="43" text="GIPSON, ALEC" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="44" end="52" text="32707420" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="53" end="63" text="07/28/2060" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="66" end="79" text="Vernon Lozano" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="99" end="120" text="Ireton Medical Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="121" end="136" text="91 Neptune Lane" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="137" end="144" text="Abilene" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="146" end="148" text="FL" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P9" start="150" end="155" text="81494" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="162" end="168" text="Vernon" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P11" start="220" end="223" text="IMC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="252" end="263" text="Alec Gipson" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="311" end="321" text="07/25/2060" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="604" end="614" text="07/26/2060" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="760" end="765" text="Otero" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="769" end="779" text="07/26/2060" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="1332" end="1342" text="07/27/2060" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="1732" end="1742" text="07/27/2060" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="2085" end="2099" text="Victor Quijano" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P20" start="2131" end="2140" text="6-5332849" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="2156" end="2164" text="07/28/60" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="2169" end="2177" text="07/29/60" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="2182" end="2190" text="07/28/60" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>