<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2121-05-09

                     BCH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

HOLCOMB,DENNIS   833-12-06-0                       VISIT DATE: 05/09/21

This patient was seen, interviewed and examined by myself as well 

as Dr. Petty whose I have reviewed and whose findings I have 

confirmed.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 53-year-old male who 

presents with complaints of palpitations, shortness of breath and a 

general feeling of weakness.  The patient states he has been 

feeling unwell for the past three days and has noticed his heart 

racing.  He actually has had his significant other take his heart 

rate and blood pressure while he was at home, and his readings have 

been in the 1 teens to 120s.  The patient has had a decreased 

appetite with vomiting and nausea as well as chest tightness in his 

mid-chest.  The patient felt himself get worse, and he, therefore, 

presents to the emergency department.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As per the written note.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Insulin dependent diabetes mellitus.

MEDICATIONS:  Insulin.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  As per the written note.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  This is a well-developed, well-nourished 

male in moderate distress.  Pulse 160-177, respiratory rate 40, 

blood pressure is 130/68, oxygen saturation is 100% on room air.  

NECK:  Supple, full range of motion, no jugular venous distension.  

CARDIAC:  Regular, tachycardic, no murmur is auscultated, clear S1 

and S2.  LUNGS:  Positive rales at the bases, otherwise clear, good 

air movement, tachypneic.  NEURO:  Alert and oriented x 3, follows 

all commands appropriate.  Further details of the exam are as per 

the written note.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Labs are significant for a glucose of 322, 

BUN of 31, creatinine of 1.8, bicarbonate of 19, CK of 186, MB of 

4.0, troponin of 1.11, calcium of 9.9.  White count of 15.6, 

hematocrit of 47.6, platelets of 206.  PT of 14.0, PTT of 29.0.  

EKG shows wide complex, regular, tachycardia.

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was seen, interviewed 

and examined in the emergency department with labs obtained and as 

documented above.  In addition to the above studies, the patient 

had a chest x-ray which shows increased pulmonary vasculature.  The 

patient's EKG along with his history is concerning for a 

ventricular tachycardia.  The patient, therefore, initially 

received amiodarone.  The amiodarone affected no change in the 

patient's heart rate.  The patient remained tachypneic and 

tachycardic and generally well appearing.  The decision was made to 

proceed with cardioversion.  The patient received morphine and 

Ativan and had a synchronized cardioversion once at 52 volts with 

immediate change to sinus tachycardia in the 1 teens.  The patient 

stated that his chest tightness resolved immediately following 

cardioversion.  The patient received aspirin, beta-blockers, oxygen 

and heparin while in the emergency department.  He is on amiodarone 

drip.  Individuals from the Cardiac Service were contacted 

regarding possibly getting the patient to the catheterization lab 

especially in light of his ruling in for a myocardial infarction.  

The plan at this time is for the patient to be admitted to the CCU, 

be observed and then to proceed to cardiac catheterization 

thereafter.

CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  Cardiac Service.

FINAL DIAGNOSES:

1.  Myocardial infarction.

2.  Ventricular tachycardia.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 

admitted in satisfactory condition.  Critical care time is 70 

minutes.

___________________________________                    PY989/54741 

KATHLEEN IRELAND, M.D.       KI30                        D:05/09/21 

                                                       T:05/10/21 

Dictated by:  KATHLEEN IRELAND, M.D.       KI30 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2121-05-09" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="52" text="BCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="78" end="92" text="HOLCOMB,DENNIS" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="95" end="106" text="833-12-06-0" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="141" end="149" text="05/09/21" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="226" end="231" text="Petty" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="338" end="340" text="53" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<ID id="P7" start="3716" end="3727" text="PY989/54741" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="3730" end="3746" text="KATHLEEN IRELAND" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="3759" end="3763" text="KI30" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="3789" end="3797" text="05/09/21" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3857" end="3865" text="05/10/21" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="3882" end="3898" text="KATHLEEN IRELAND" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="3911" end="3915" text="KI30" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>