<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2129-02-19

Lee County Community Hospital0021 New Hampshire AvenueKigali, NJ  47798497-045-1949 






Dennis Holcomb
Medical record #83312060
Date of visit-February 19, 2129




 
Date of birth: December 14, 2067


Chief complaint: The patient presents today in follow up for his diabetes and coronary disease, as well as a reevaluation of his recent left proximal humeral fracture




Problems
Diabetes mellitus type 2 : insulin requiring
H/O left foot infection 
Erectile dysfunction 
Onychomycosis 
Hyperlipidemia 
Coronary artery disease 
inferior myocardial infarction 
H/O Ventricular tachycardia 
Obesity 
diabetic retinopathy 
ischemic cardiomyopathy 
low testosterone 
Polyp of colon 
Fracture of humerus 


Procedures
Cardiac catheterization 
Coronary stent : rca stent, ptca of diagonal
Implanted cardiac defibrillator 




Allergies
NKA 


Medications
Atenolol 100 MG (100MG TABLET Take 1) PO QAM, to be taken in conjunction with 50 mg tab at qhs #90 Tablet(s)
Atenolol 50 MG (50MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS, to be taken in conjunction with 100 mg qam #90 Tablet(s)
Enteric Coated Aspirin (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated) 81MG TABLET DR Take 2 PO QD #Tablet(s)
Folate (FOLIC Acid) 1 MG (1MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #Tablet(s)
Furosemide 40 MG (40MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Insulin Nph Human 40 UNITS SC QD #4 Bottle(s)
Insulin Regular Human Variable (100 U/ML VIAL ML) SC #2 Bottle(s)
Lisinopril 5 MG (5MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Mvi (MULTIVITAMINS) 1 TAB PO QD
Simvastatin 20 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS #90 Tablet(s)
Ultram (TRAMADOL) 50 MG TABLET PO Q4-6H PRN pain, 1-2 tabs before bedtime and as needed, max of 300 mg per day #60 Tablet(s)
Vitamin B12 (CYANOCOBALAMIN) 250 MCG (250 MCG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #Tablet(s)
Vitamin E (TOCOPHEROL-DL-ALPHA) 1000 UNIT CAPSULE PO QD #Capsule(s)


Family / Social History
Cerebral Aneurysm:
       Relative: Father;
Hypertension:
Cardiac:
       Relative: Grandmother, maternal;
       Relative: Grandfather, maternal;


Social history: Engaged, does not smoke, drink or use drugs, works as a architect at the Alaska Air Group in Juneau


History of Present Illness: The patient presents today for follow up of his diabetes and heart disease, and to follow up as well as recent proximal humeral fracture that will not require surgery per his orthopedic specialist. The patient fell down a couple weeks ago on ice and landed on his left shoulder, sustaining a proximal humeral fracture that is currently well aligned. The patient was seen by orthopedics at the Boulder County Hospital, he was told to have no work for the next 3 months. He also received reports no chest pain, PND or orthopnea, he also denies any AICD firing, and reports only occasional low blood sugar reactions. He has a history of poorly controlled type 2 diabetes, he currently uses NPH insulin 42 units daily with sliding scale to 3 times a day at a maximal 8 units at a time. He reports no polyuria or polydipsia. His only risk doctor for fracture includes a low testosterone diagnosed about 3 years ago. He is currently on no replacement for testosterone, and only recently started calcium and vitamin D after his fracture. He has not had an eye examination in over a year.




Physical Examination: 
Vital SignsBP 118/62, P 74, RR 16, Temp 98.3 F, Ht 70.5 in, Wt 225 lb 


O2 SAT 97
BMI 31.9


HEENT: Normocephalic, atraumatic, pupils are equally round and reactive to light and accommodation, oropharynx is clear without erythema or exudate, tympanic membranes are clear without erythema or effusions, sinuses were nontender, nostrils are patentNeck: Supple, without JVD, lymphadenopathy, thyromegaly, and both carotids were 2+ without bruitsLungs: Clear to auscultation bilaterally, without wheezes, rubs or rhonchiHeart: Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1, S2, no murmurs, rubs or gallops were appreciatedAbdomen: Soft, nontender, nondistended, bowel sounds were active, there is no organomegaly, there is no CVA tenderness, and there was no suprapubic tendernessExtremities: There is no clubbing, cyanosis, or edema notedNeuro: Alert and oriented x3, all cranial nerves are intact, motor is 5 out of 5 throughout, sensory examination is intact to light touch throughout, reflexes were 2+ throughout, and gait was normalSkin: There were numerous small skin tags of the neck bilaterally, and extensive ecchymotic area in the left upper arm in the setting of his recent humeral fractureLymphatic: There is no lymphadenopathy presentMusculoskeletal: There is discrete tenderness of the left proximal humerus with extensive ecchymosis extending to the elbow
Assessment and Plan: 1. Proximal humeral fracture-the patient will be out of work for 3 months, and is really taking calcium and vitamin D twice a day, and strong he recommended a bone density test for future should fracture assessment given his low testosterone 3 years ago, the patient is not willing to schedule it today, but will call me in the next month to do so he is on Ultram on a p.r.n. basis with good relief of pain and he did not tolerate oxycodone well initially
2. Poorly controlled type 2 diabetes-will recommend hemoglobin A1c, lipid profile, and urine for microalbumin as well as a TSH, and considered poor the patient from NPH to Lantus or possible to 70/30 insulin, with the patient might ask her benefit with formal endocrine consultation given his poor glycemic control and history of cardiac disease.
3. CAD-will check his lipid panel tonight, aiming for an LDL of below 100
___________________________Robert Lincoln, M.D.



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2129-02-19" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="28" end="57" text="Lee County Community Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P2" start="57" end="82" text="0021 New Hampshire Avenue" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="82" end="88" text="Kigali" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="90" end="92" text="NJ" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="94" end="99" text="47798" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P6" start="99" end="111" text="497-045-1949" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="119" end="133" text="Dennis Holcomb" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="150" end="158" text="83312060" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="173" end="190" text="February 19, 2129" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="212" end="229" text="December 14, 2067" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P11" start="2076" end="2085" text="architect" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P12" start="2093" end="2109" text="Alaska Air Group" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P13" start="2113" end="2119" text="Juneau" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P14" start="2543" end="2566" text="Boulder County Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="5540" end="5554" text="Robert Lincoln" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>