<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2096-12-29

EDVISIT^28297534^OGRADY, MICHAEL^12/29/96^AVILA, KRISTOPHER

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Chest pressure.

Mr. Ogrady is seen by the resident and also seen and examined by

me.  He is a transfer from an outside hospital to be admitted

because of his chest pain.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 67-year-old man who was

loading some luggage in a car this morning at about 4:30 a.m.  At

that time, he experienced acute onset of squeezing, chest pain,

and chest pressure associated with shortness of breath.  He

described his pain as being very intense about 9/10, described

heaviness across his chest and shortness of breath.  He stated

that while he was walking into his place his chest pain got worse

and since then it was intermittent and stuttering in nature.  He

was taken to Muncy Valley Hospital where he was seen, treated,

and transferred here.  He is currently pain free.  At Oakridge State his troponin was negative.  His CPK was

negative.  His EKG showed a Q-wave in III and aVF and had no

acute ST elevation or ST depression on his cardiogram which

correlates with our cardiogram here.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  His history, however, is significant in

that he has a cardiac catheterization that was done in 06/2093. 

At that time, he had proximal LAD lesion of 30%, left main was

30%, and left circumflex was also 30%.  He had an RCA lesion

which was 100%, RCA proximal lesion, with good collateral flow. 

His last echocardiogram was in 03/2093.  At that time, his LV

function was normal and he had an EF of 55% to 60%.  His past

medical history is significant for diabetes and hypertension as

well as high cholesterol, had an myocardial infarction in 2084,

history of metastatic esophageal cancer and history of DVT in his

left lower extremity in 2090.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  He has had an esophagectomy.  He

underwent fem-pop bypass surgery in 2088.  He has also had a

cholecystectomy and appendectomy.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He is a 40-pack-year smoker.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Also, has a strong family history of cardiac

disease.

MEDICATIONS:  He is now pain free but described his pain this

morning as squeezing, pressure like, and heaviness in his chest.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  His vital signs here are normal.  His

HEENT exam is benign.  His neck is supple with clear lungs

bilaterally.  He has a 3/6 systolic murmur.  He has no rubs or

gallops.  His pulses are normal, well perfused throughout and

warm extremities.  Abdomen is soft without any masses, good bowel

sounds.  Extremities are normal.

LABORATORY DATA:  EKG as described above again, a Q in III and

aVF, otherwise no acute changes on his cardiogram.  His CK is 33

and his troponin is negative.  His creatinine is 1.9 with a BUN

of 27.  All other labs are normal including his blood sugar which

is 156.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient's cardiologist is Dr.

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

rule out and maybe even need another cardiac catheterization if

necessary.

DIAGNOSIS:  Chest pain and chest pressure with history of an MI

and history of coronary artery disease.

______________________________

AVILA, KRISTOPHER M.D.

D: 12/29/96

T: 12/29/96

Dictated By: AVILA, KRISTOPHER

eScription document:3-0867902 BFFocus





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2096-12-29" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="28297534" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="60" text="OGRADY, MICHAEL" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="61" end="69" text="12/29/96" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="70" end="87" text="AVILA, KRISTOPHER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="128" end="134" text="Ogrady" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="320" end="322" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="812" end="833" text="Muncy Valley Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="917" end="931" text="Oakridge State" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1253" end="1260" text="06/2093" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1487" end="1494" text="03/2093" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1705" end="1709" text="2084" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="1803" end="1807" text="2090" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="1904" end="1908" text="2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="3171" end="3188" text="AVILA, KRISTOPHER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="3198" end="3206" text="12/29/96" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="3211" end="3219" text="12/29/96" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="3234" end="3251" text="AVILA, KRISTOPHER" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P18" start="3273" end="3282" text="3-0867902" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>