<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2095-12-24



Grafton State Physician Group

567 Derby Circle                                    OGRADY, MICHAEL

Tbilisi, OR 91623                            28297534

575-433-3737, 128-526-1384                                           12/24/95





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Ogrady is a 66-year-old gentleman who is coming in to Grafton Clinic to establish care and to discuss several medical issues.

1.  Pain.  He has whole body pain, mostly in his abdomen and his leg, and this has been longstanding for 2 years' time.  Has been treating with Percocet initially at about 3-4 per day but most recently, as high as 6 per day and in fact, 6 per day is the average.  He was seen in the pain clinic and was started on Neurontin.  It is unclear how compliant he has been with that regimen.  Dr. Hoover has been renewing his Percocet prescriptions.  He has had a CAT scan done in the past because of a history of esophageal cancer, which showed no evidence of cancer or no other etiology for his pain.

2.  Esophageal cancer status post resection by Dr. Patton.  He has been doing okay from that standpoint, is followed up with Dr. Yan.  The last CT scan was in June 2095 that showed some pulmonary nodules and a renal cyst that needed followup.  He has not yet had a repeat CT scan that was scheduled for yesterday, and he did not go to the appointment because he wants to do it at the Cancer Center where he feels more relaxed.

3.  Coronary artery disease.  He is status post an MI in 2084.  He has had several angiograms but no angioplasties by his report.  He is followed by Dr. Mckee at the Trimont Health Care Center.

4.  Status post fem-pop bypass of the left side.  He says he has been having increasing pain over the last several years on that side, which is why he takes the Percocet.  



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for coronary artery disease and diabetes mellitus with unclear control.  His last hemoglobin A1c was 6.5 and that was in 10/94.  Status post cholecystectomy, status post appendectomy, esophageal cancer status post resection, and history of idiopathic thrombocytopenia.



MEDICATIONS:  Diovan 80 mg p.o. b.i.d., metformin 1000 mg p.o. b.i.d. diltiazem 240 mg p.o. q.d., Lipitor 20 mg p.o. q.d., Prilosec 20 mg p.o. b.i.d.  Percocet 5/325 six times per day, Dyazide 37.5/25 one time p.o. q.d., isosorbide 60 mg p.o. q.d., and Lopressor 125 mg  p.o. q.d.  



SOCIAL HISTORY:  Lives with his wife.  He is retired.  He used to smoke, quit in 2084.  Smoked for 20 years 2 packs per day.  No alcohol, no drugs.  



FAMILY HISTORY:  Mother died of cancer, unclear what type.  Father died of an MI and had diabetes mellitus.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Comprehensive review of systems was done and reveals that that he has chronic abdominal pain that is unchanged, occasional chest pain, and chest palpitations that has been evaluated by his cardiologist.  No fevers or chills.  No burning or pain with urination.  The rest of the review of systems was negative.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Today, his blood pressure is 122/80 and his pulse is 80.  His height is 6 feet and his weight is 230 pounds.  In general, he is in no acute distress.  He is well appearing.  Sclerae are anicteric.  Conjunctivae noninjected.  Pupils equal, round, and react to light.  His extraocular are movements intact.  Oropharynx is without erythema or exudate.  Oral mucosa is moist.  Neck has no significant lymphadenopathy.  JVP is flat.  His thyroid is within normal bilaterally.  Lungs are clear to auscultation bilaterally.  Good aeration, good air movement, no accessory muscle use.  Cardiac exam is regular rate and rhythm, normal S1, S2.  He has a systolic murmur, which has been reported previously.  His abdominal exam is soft, nontender, nondistended.  He has a large central hernia.  He has several surgical scars.  His extremities, he has no edema, his DP pulses are 1+ bilaterally.  His reflexes are trace in the knees, toes are downgoing.  His skin exam, he has multiple nevi, some that are rather dark.  No specifically suspicious lesion.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  A 66-year-old gentleman with multiple medical issues.

1.  Diabetes, recheck hemoglobin A1c today.  He is going to find out when the last time it was he had an eye exam.

2.  Pain.  He has had this pain syndrome for quite some time.  He is on short-acting narcotic and I think this is appropriate.  I am going to start him on a fentanyl patch 25 mcg p.o. q.d. and decrease his Percocet to 4 per day.  Hopefully, we will be able to wean him off his Percocet altogether.

3.  Esophageal cancer.  Follow up with Dr. Yan and Dr. Patton.

4.  Pulmonary nodule.  I emphasized the need for him to repeat his CT scan.  I sent an email to Dr. Yan.  He wants to only do them at the Cancer Center and that is where last films were done.  I explained how important it was.

4.  Idiopathic thrombocytopenia.  We are going to watch this.  He had a workup by Dr. Sawyer in the past.  He reports no bleeding.

5.  Coronary artery disease.  I asked him to get Dr. Landers's records for me, especially his last angiogram.  We are going to check his cholesterol today.  He will follow up with me in approximately 1 month's time to reevaluate his pain.

6.  His EKG today shows a sinus rhythm at the rate of 60, normal intervals, normal axis, and poor R-wave progression in the precordial leads and as indicated above, possible septal infarct and possible inferior infarct.  I do not have a baseline for comparison.4. 5.











______________________________

Scott Koontz, MD





Dictated By: Scott Koontz





eScription document:9-6525022 EMSSten Tel







DD: 12/24/95

DT: 12/25/95

DV: 12/24/95



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2095-12-24" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="30" end="43" text="Grafton State" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P2" start="61" end="77" text="567 Derby Circle" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="113" end="128" text="OGRADY, MICHAEL" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="130" end="137" text="Tbilisi" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="139" end="141" text="OR" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="142" end="147" text="91623" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<ID id="P7" start="175" end="183" text="28297534" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P8" start="185" end="197" text="575-433-3737" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P9" start="199" end="211" text="128-526-1384" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="254" end="262" text="12/24/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="301" end="307" text="Ogrady" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="313" end="315" text="66" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="818" end="824" text="Hoover" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="1076" end="1082" text="Patton" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="1154" end="1157" text="Yan" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="1184" end="1193" text="June 2095" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P18" start="1409" end="1422" text="Cancer Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="1510" end="1514" text="2084" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="1606" end="1611" text="Mckee" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P21" start="1619" end="1645" text="Trimont Health Care Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="1980" end="1985" text="10/94" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="2498" end="2502" text="2084" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P24" start="4107" end="4109" text="66" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P25" start="4618" end="4621" text="Yan" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P26" start="4630" end="4636" text="Patton" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P27" start="4739" end="4742" text="Yan" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P28" start="4777" end="4790" text="Cancer Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P29" start="4953" end="4959" text="Sawyer" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P30" start="5052" end="5059" text="Landers" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P31" start="5549" end="5561" text="Scott Koontz" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P32" start="5584" end="5596" text="Scott Koontz" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P33" start="5622" end="5631" text="9-6525022" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P34" start="5655" end="5663" text="12/24/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P35" start="5669" end="5677" text="12/25/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P36" start="5683" end="5691" text="12/24/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>