<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2093-02-28

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

February 28, 2093

 

 

 

Herman Patton, M.D.

Department of Thoracic Surgery

Grafton State Hospital 

39 Pacific Boulevard

Cape Town, OR 67125

 

RE: Michael Ogrady

       MR #631-90-33-7

 

Dear Dr. Patton:

 

I had the pleasure of seeing your patient Michael Ogrady in consultation for 

his coronary artery

disease, before his surgery for esophageal cancer.  As you know, this is a 

63-year-old male with a

long past medical history which includes diabetes, coronary artery disease, 

peripheral vascular

disease, hypertension, smoking history, hypercholesterolemia, DVT and newly 

diagnosed

esophageal carcinoma.  He has been followed by his cardiologist, Yehuda 

Landers, for the last nine

years.  Essentially he has every cardiac risk factor and known coronary 

artery disease which is

documented on cardiac catheterization performed on 1/20/93.  The 

catheterization demonstrated

right dominant system with 100% RCA lesion, a complex 30% diagonal 1 lesion 

and a 30%

marginal 1 lesion.  There was collateral flow noted from the LAD to the right 

PDA and from the

septal 2 branch to the RCA, and from the circumflex artery to the RCA.  The 

procedure was

performed through the right radial artery without complications.  Patient 

also has peripheral

vascular disease and is status post a left femoral posterior tibial saphenous 

vein bypass graft in

2088.  He is also status post atherectomy and dilatation of stenosis in the 

femoral to posterior

tibial graft.  He also had a left leg DVT in 2090.  His activity level is 

limited by his claudication. 

He has a history of hypertension and hypercholesterolemia and diabetes on 

treatment.  

 

At baseline he has dyspnea on exertion after walking half a mile.  He gets 

chest pressure one to

two times a month.  However, his activity is extremely limited.  He reports 

that he has had a

positive stress test.  Further information is not available.  Patient 

understands he has coronary

disease, however does not have amenable disease for angioplasty.  On 

catheterization he had

preserved ejection fraction of 62%.  

 

He is to undergo esophageal cancer surgery in the next one to two months 

after receiving

chemotherapy and radiation therapy preop.  Patient states he will be 

receiving a Hickman

Michael Ogrady

Page 2

March 3, 2093

 

catheter and a jejunostomy tube placement before his chemo and radiation 

therapy. 

 

On physical exam, the patient is obese, weighing 288 pounds.  His blood 

pressure is 100/72,

heart rate is 57 bpm.  HEENT: oropharynx benign.  Neck: carotids intact 

bilaterally without

audible bruits.  Lungs: distant breath sounds.  Cor: without obvious jugular 

venous distention. 

Heart sounds distant.  Normal S1 and S2.  No appreciable murmurs.  Abdomen: 

unable to palpate

firm masses or aortic aneurysm.  Bowel sounds present.  Extremities: status 

post surgery to the

left flank with 1 to 2+ edema to the knee.  Distal pulses are absent.  Neuro: 

intact.

 

EKG: Sinus brady with first degree AV block.  IMI with age undetermined.  

Nonspecific STT

wave abnormalities present.  No previous EKG for comparison.

 

Impression: 63-year-old diabetic, hypertensive male with known coronary 

artery disease and

peripheral vascular disease who has preserved left ventricular function.  He 

clearly has ischemia

on a positive stress test.  I would recommend dobutamine echocardiogram to 

check ischemic

threshold.  He is clearly at intermediate risk for a perioperative cardiac 

event.  However, given

his life-threatening esophageal carcinoma, patient wants to proceed with 

surgery even

understanding possible complications.

 

Plan:

1.   Dobutamine echocardiogram to check ischemic threshold.

2.   Recommend intravenous beta-blockers during the surgery with fairly tight 

control of

     blood pressure and heart rate, utilizing the information determined on 

dobutamine

     echocardiography.

 

Thank you for allowing me to participate in the care of your patient, Michael 

Ogrady.  Please do

not hesitate to contact me if you have any questions.

 

Sincerely yours, 

 

 

Susan Ximena Elias, M.D., M.M.S.C.

 

/alvarado

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2093-02-28" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="52" end="69" text="February 28, 2093" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="80" end="93" text="Herman Patton" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="133" end="155" text="Grafton State Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="158" end="178" text="39 Pacific Boulevard" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="180" end="189" text="Cape Town" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="191" end="193" text="OR" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="194" end="199" text="67125" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="208" end="222" text="Michael Ogrady" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P9" start="235" end="246" text="631-90-33-7" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="260" end="266" text="Patton" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="314" end="328" text="Michael Ogrady" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="449" end="451" text="63" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<PHI id="P13" start="727" end="743" text="Yehuda 

Landers" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="914" end="921" text="1/20/93" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="1439" end="1443" text="2088" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="1584" end="1588" text="2090" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="2358" end="2372" text="Michael Ogrady" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="2382" end="2395" text="March 3, 2093" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P19" start="3237" end="3239" text="63" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<PHI id="P20" start="4092" end="4108" text="Michael 

Ogrady" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P21" start="4205" end="4223" text="Susan Ximena Elias" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P22" start="4245" end="4253" text="alvarado" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>