<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2095-01-31

EDVISIT^65219816^HALL, NICK^01/31/95^PENN, GINO

The patient was seen and examined in the Emergency Department on

01/31/2095.  The patient was seen by Dr. Ibarra.  I have discussed

the management with her.  I have also seen the patient personally

and reviewed the ED record.  This is an addendum to the record. 

I have also reviewed the old medical record and discussed the

management with Dr. Gil, who will be speaking with Dr. Gomez

about accepting this patient to the Cardiology Service.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 54-year-old gentleman who

has a history of stent placements as he had a cardiac arrest

status post lobectomy for squamous cell carcinoma.  This occurred

in 02/2094, where the patient was taken to the Cath Lab after His

postoperative rest.  Stents were placed and the patient says he

has been doing well.  In the meantime, he has had no chest pain

or shortness of breath until one week prior, he was on a

treadmill and felt unwell with shortness of breath and chest

discomfort.  He stopped and felt better.  Last night, he was in

bed watching TV, he felt some chest discomfort and took

nitroglycerin with relief of pain, and this morning he was

walking and walked about 100 yards, felt short of breath and

chest pain at rest and took nitroglycerin with relieve and now

has no chest pain or shortness of breath at this time.  His chest

pain he describes it as pressure with exertion and he feels well

now.  No fevers, chills, or cough.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As indicated and otherwise negative.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As indicated and also includes

hypertension and increased cholesterol.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He is a nonsmoker.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is pleasant, well appearing,

and in no acute distress.  Normocephalic and atraumatic.  Chest

is clear.  Heart is regular.  Abdomen is soft and nontender. 

Extremities are nontender.  Rectal exam is heme-negative.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  This is a gentleman with a history of

coronary artery disease and cardiac arrest, who has a very

typical symptoms concerning for coronary artery disease and

angina including components at rest.  We have started heparin on

the patient medicated with cardiologist for the possibility of

early catheterization.  Laboratory was pending at the time of

this dictation.

DISPOSITION:  The patient will be admitted to Cardiology in fair

condition.

______________________________

PENN, GINO M.D.

D: 01/31/95

T: 01/31/95

Dictated By: PENN, GINO

eScription document:2-5902888 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2095-01-31" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="65219816" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="55" text="HALL, NICK" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="56" end="64" text="01/31/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="65" end="75" text="PENN, GINO" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="143" end="153" text="01/31/2095" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="184" end="190" text="Ibarra" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="427" end="430" text="Gil" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="462" end="467" text="Gomez" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P9" start="565" end="567" text="54" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="724" end="731" text="02/2094" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2460" end="2470" text="PENN, GINO" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2480" end="2488" text="01/31/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2493" end="2501" text="01/31/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="2516" end="2526" text="PENN, GINO" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P15" start="2548" end="2557" text="2-5902888" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>