<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2095-03-12


3/12/2095


Youssef Null
Ludlow Medical Center
87 Manatee Street
Post, IN 86454


Dear Dr. Null, 


I had the pleasure of seeing Nick Hall in WSH cardiology clinic today in follow-up for his known coronary artery disease and recent admission to Wytheville South with a non-ST elevation myocardial infarction.  As I'm sure you recall, he is a lovely 54 year old gentleman whose history of Hodgkins disease status-post mantle radiation in the early 70's, squamous cell lung cancer status post left upper lobectomy 1/94, and coronary artery disease, status post-PCI to the LAD and RCA in '90 and '87, respectively, and perioperative VT/VF arrest at the time of his LUL resection 1/94.  At that time, emergent catheterization revealed massive volume of thrombus extending throughout his RCA, managed with extensive suction catheter use and POBA, with a good angiographic result.  No stents were placed given the thrombus burden.  Remarkably, subsequent echocardiogram revealed normal LV systolic function, with basal inferoposterior HK noted.  His peak TnI was 33.6, his peak CK was 1710, and his peak MB was 87.2.  He had a relatively unremarkable course post-catheterization; plavix initiation was delayed until his chest tube was removed, after which it was started without incident.  He was discharged 2/11/94, and had done well until 1/31/2095, when he presented to WSH with unstable angina, having noted new sudden onset angina and dyspnea while making his daily walk.  He had a positive troponin, and was taken urgently to cardiac catheterization, which revealed a proximal LAD lesion (felt to be the culprit) and ostial RCA lesion, both of which were stented with CYPHER stents.  At that time the decision was made to increase his plavix from 75 to 150 as an attempt to maximize his medical management, given his history and disease burden.  


Since that admission, he has done exceedingly well, and presents today without complaints.  He continues to walk 2 miles ~4 times/week without exertional symptoms.  He specifically denies chest pain, dyspnea, orthopnea, PND, or lower extremity edema.  He has had no palpitations, dizziness/presyncope, or claudication.  He has significantly modified his diet to eliminate dairy and hydrogenated products/snacks, with a 5# weight loss, and is motivated to further reduce his weight.  He states that he feels "great" and isdoing quite well.  He does not that occasionally at this work, when he is frustrated/upset, he will take his pressure and find his systolic to be ~150, but this comes down within minutes if he relaxes, and his pressures are great at home.  He has had no GI symptoms on the aggressive antiplatelet regimen, despite not being on a PPI.


Regarding his squamous cell lung cancer, it is my understanding that he had no evidence of metastatic disease and that margins were negative; he is not currently planned for any adjuvant therapy, but will be closely followed.  His most recent imaging was 11/94, which was negative for evidence of metastasis by repor.  Regarding his remote history of Hodgkins, he is followed at RFPC on an annual basis.  


His past medical history includes:
  CAD s/p IMI '88 (totally occluded RCA with good collaterals, revascularized with 3 stents to the RCA), MI '90 (LAD stent), inferior STEMI 2/94 as above s/p POBA
  VF arrest in setting of STEMI
  Hodgkin's '81 - splenectomy, XRT
  LUL squamous cell cancer s/p L upper lobectomy 2/94
  hyperlipidemia (low HDL and high LDL - tried niaspan in the past without much benefit)
  hypothyroid
  basal cell skin CA
  nephrolithiasis


His medications include:
  Lipitor 80 mg
  Plavix 150 mg
  ASA 325 mg po QD
  Toprol 200 mg po BID
  Levoxyl
  Omega-3-fatty acids
  Multivitamin


He has a history of intolerance (dizziness) with lisinopril.


His family history is notable for hyperlipidemia and hypertension, but negative for CAD.


He works in consulting, and travels around the midwest as part of his job.  He also works a few days a week at the local supermarket cashiering , and works as a museum docent a few times a week.  He is married, and lives in Lincoln City.  He and his wife have 4 children, ages 15 / 17 / 20 / 24; they have no pets.  He has never smoked cigarettes.  He drinks 1 glass of wine a night.


On physical exam today, he has a heart rate of 75 and a blood pressure of 129/81, with a weight of 220#.  He is a well developed well nourished gentleman in no apparent distress.  His JVP is ~7-8 cm; he has no carotid bruits.  His lungs are clear to auscultation bilaterally.  He has a regular rate and rhythm with a normal S1 and a physiologically split S2, and no murmurs, rubs, or gallups.  His abdomen is benign.  He is warm and well perfused peripherally without significant edema, and with 2+ PT pulses bilaterally.


His EKG in clinic today is NSR at 75 with possible left atrial abnormality, a nonspeciifc IVCD, and inferior Q waves in III/F, consistent with an inferior MI. 


In summary, this is a 54 year old man who had a VF arrest in the setting of perioperative inferior STEMI, status post extensive angiojet and POBA of acute in-stent thrombosis of presumed bare metal stents in his RCA, who represented 1 year later (1/95) with NSTEMI now s/p PCI to his RCA and LAD.  He is now asymptomatic status post this intervention  Given his history, we agree with antiplatelet therapy, with a plan for lifelong plavix and aspirin.  Should he require future invasive diagnostic procedures, it would be reasonable to decrease doses to 75 plavix/81 ASA, but we would not favor DC of either of these medications altogether.  His blood pressure and heart rate are well controlled on his current regimen, as demonstrated by his home records.  His LDL is near goal, with a low HDL that was unaffected by high-dose niaspan in the past.  I share his hope that with further diet/weight loss and exercise, these will both improve to goal.  


As I have discussed with he and his wife, given his history of Hodgkin's, as well as his known CAD, he is clearly at risk for future events, including the possibility of bypass surgery in the future.  We will be guided by his symptoms, and he knows to call me if he has any problems/symptoms.  It was a pleasure to see Mr. Hall in cardiology clinic today.  I will plan to see him in follow-up in 6 months time, but he knows to call sooner should he have any problems or concerns. 


Regards,
_____________________________________________
Florence Heather Gil, M.D., Ph.D.


CC: Dr. Nick Golden
         Thoracic Surgery 
         Wytheville South Hospital


         Dr. Paul Reilly
         Riverside Family Practice Center





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2095-03-12" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="29" end="38" text="3/12/2095" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="41" end="53" text="Youssef Null" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="54" end="75" text="Ludlow Medical Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="76" end="93" text="87 Manatee Street" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="94" end="98" text="Post" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="100" end="102" text="IN" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="103" end="108" text="86454" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="120" end="124" text="Null" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="158" end="167" text="Nick Hall" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="171" end="174" text="WSH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P11" start="274" end="290" text="Wytheville South" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="378" end="380" text="54" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="476" end="480" text="70's" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="541" end="545" text="1/94" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="614" end="617" text="'90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="622" end="625" text="'87" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="705" end="709" text="1/94" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="1331" end="1338" text="2/11/94" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="1364" end="1373" text="1/31/2095" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P20" start="1396" end="1399" text="WSH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="2990" end="2995" text="11/94" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P22" start="3114" end="3118" text="RFPC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="3192" end="3195" text="'88" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="3286" end="3289" text="'90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="3318" end="3322" text="2/94" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="3385" end="3388" text="'81" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P27" start="3457" end="3461" text="2/94" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P28" start="3920" end="3930" text="consulting" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P29" start="3951" end="3962" text="the midwest" TYPE="LOCATION-OTHER" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P30" start="4029" end="4040" text="supermarket" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P31" start="4041" end="4052" text="cashiering " TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P32" start="4069" end="4082" text="museum docent" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P33" start="4132" end="4144" text="Lincoln City" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<AGE id="P34" start="4185" end="4187" text="15" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P35" start="4190" end="4192" text="17" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P36" start="4195" end="4197" text="20" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P37" start="4200" end="4202" text="24" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P38" start="5002" end="5004" text="54" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P39" start="5227" end="5231" text="1/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P40" start="6256" end="6260" text="Hall" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P41" start="6471" end="6491" text="Florence Heather Gil" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P42" start="6515" end="6526" text="Nick Golden" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P43" start="6563" end="6588" text="Wytheville South Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P44" start="6604" end="6615" text="Paul Reilly" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P45" start="6625" end="6657" text="Riverside Family Practice Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>