<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2093-03-07

MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
593 Will St                           Vicente, Kadeem
Sandpoint, MI 58543                             CK759182
(033) 250-1408                                3-6-93
 
 
 
HPI:  Kadeem Vicente comes in today for follow up office visit.  The patient 
is seen primarily for follow up regarding his history of hypertension, 
coronary artery disease (the patient is status post inferior wall MI), 
benign prostatic hypertrophy and to a much lesser extent osteoarthritis.  
The patient is also followed GERD-like symptoms.  With regard to the 
latter, the patient notes that since he has been off the Zantac, he 
initially saw no change in his ability to handle foods; however, he now 
notes that he is starting to get some reflux and feels slightly 
uncomfortable with this.  He denies chest pain per se and any symptoms 
pertinent to cardiovascular disease, such as chest heaviness, shortness 
of breath, diaphoresis, nausea.  The patient knows the foods that give 
him this type of reaction, such as tomato based sauces and tries to 
avoid them as much as possible.  The patient is asking me about Prilosec 
which he recently read in the Journal and was wandering whether this 
would be a suitable alternative to H2 blockers (Patient had been on H2 
blockers for many years without a trial off of them, which a reason that 
we stopped his H2 blocker therapy recently).  
 
With regard to the patient's symptoms of benign prostatic hypertrophy, 
the patient says that these have almost completely resolved on the 4 mg 
of Hytrin and which he will continue taking.  The patient does remain on 
Zestril for his hypertension as well as the Hytrin and the blood 
pressure gotten by the nurse today was 150/80 and repeated by me 20 
minutes later was 130/74. 
 
The patient reports being otherwise well, no new symptoms.  No positive 
review of systems.  
 
PHYSICAL EXAM:  Was not performed.  Vitals:  Blood pressure taken by me 
was 130/74 in the right, 130/74 in the left, temperature was 98.8, 
respirations 20, unlabored and pulse was 80.  
 
ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  75 year old man with multiple medical concerns 
comes in for follow up.
1.   Hypertension.  The patient will stay on his Zestril, once a day as 
     well as his Hytrin, which he uses also for BPH.  His blood pressure 
     appears to be well controlled on this regimen.  One of the issues 
     would be whether or not the patient should be on a beta-blocker.  
     The patient verbally has a history of "a silent heart attack"  and 
     there is evidence of an inferior wall MI and this is certainly an 
     option we will consider in the future, although I would not add a 
     third anti-hypertensive regimen and would most likely replace his 
     Zestril with a beta-blocker.
2.   GERD.  The patient will be given a prescription for Prilosec 20 mg 
     to be taken at bedtime.  The patient was told that this would not 
     MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
004 Will St                           Vicente, Kadeem
Sandpoint, MI 58543                             CK759182
(033) 250-1408                                3-6-93
Page 2
 
 
     be long term therapy but that we can do this for the next 2-3 
     months, although he should be able to experience relief almost 
     immediately.  The patient does have a known hiatal hernia, which 
     may also contribute to his symptoms of chronic reflux.
3.   BPH - The patient will stay on his 4 mg of Hytrin, which appears to 
     be working quite well.  The patient notes that there is less 
     dribbling, less nocturnal urination.  The patient does take Lasix 
     20 mg once a day for congestive heart failure and did not have any 
     difficulty with urination after he takes the diuretic.  
4.   Insomnia.  The patient will stay on his Ambien 10 mg which he takes 
     on a q.h.s. basis.  The patient was formerly on Amitriptyline but 
     was told that the secondary side effects which can include EKG 
     changes and at this point tells me that the Ambien works and he 
     would like to stay on this.  Patient has enough to last until I see 
     him next time.
 
I will thus see the patient in 3 months for a fasting lipid (The 
patient's lipid profile thus far has been acceptable.   The cholesterol 
is 190 and an acceptable triglyceride; however, I do want to assess the 
patient's LDL and HDL before making any decisions with regard to 
treatment.  
 
 
 
______________________________
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
 
JG:WQ:6672
DD:3-7-93 
DT:3-7-93 
DV:3-6-93
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2093-03-07" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="28" end="53" text="MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="54" end="76" text="Stephen A.N. Xayachack" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="83" end="94" text="593 Will St" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="121" end="136" text="Vicente, Kadeem" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="137" end="146" text="Sandpoint" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="148" end="150" text="MI" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="151" end="156" text="58543" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="185" end="193" text="CK759182" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P9" start="194" end="208" text="(033) 250-1408" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="240" end="246" text="3-6-93" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="259" end="273" text="Kadeem Vicente" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="2143" end="2145" text="75" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P13" start="2979" end="3004" text="MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="3005" end="3027" text="Stephen A.N. Xayachack" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P15" start="3034" end="3045" text="004 Will St" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="3072" end="3087" text="Vicente, Kadeem" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P17" start="3088" end="3097" text="Sandpoint" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P18" start="3099" end="3101" text="MI" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P19" start="3102" end="3107" text="58543" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<ID id="P20" start="3136" end="3144" text="CK759182" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P21" start="3145" end="3159" text="(033) 250-1408" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="3191" end="3197" text="3-6-93" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P23" start="4534" end="4556" text="Stephen A.N. Xayachack" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P24" start="4565" end="4575" text="JG:WQ:6672" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="4579" end="4585" text="3-7-93" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="4590" end="4596" text="3-7-93" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P27" start="4601" end="4607" text="3-6-93" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>