<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2092-12-27

MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
039 Will St                           Vicente, Kadeem
Sandpoint, MI 58543                             CK759182
(033) 250-1408                                12-27-92
 
 
HPI: Kadeem Vicente comes in today for a follow-up office visit.  The 
patient was seen by me approximately one month ago as a new patient and 
whose primary medical concerns a history of coronary artery disease, for 
which he suffered a "silent heart attack" many years ago, a history of 
benign prostatic hypertrophy, as well as hypertension and GERD.  As it 
turns out, the patient had been on Zantac for many, many years, the 
beneficial effects of which were unknown.  We had decided as of our last 
meeting to stop this drug and find out if he became symptomatic.  The 
patient reports today that he is not symptomatic, and thus we will 
continue to discontinue this medicine.  At this point, the patient does 
not need the addition of a proton pump inhibitor, such as Prilosec.  
With regard to the patient's symptoms of benign prostatic hypertrophy, 
the patient said that he only has taken one dose of the Hytrin, since he 
wanted to use up all his Minipress, which he tool up until 2 nights ago.  
Thus it is too early to assess the efficacy of this medication.  It is 
noted that his blood pressure was 152/74, which is better than it was 
the last time he was here, which the systolic range was 160-170 and 
diastolic was 80-90.  The patient reports no new symptomatology other 
than occasional fatigue, from which he will have to rest.  The patient 
has no symptoms of congestive heart failure, no shortness of breath, no 
ankle edema, no JVD by observation, and his laboratory results are 
remarkably normal, given his medical complaints.  The patient's 
cholesterol is 190 with a slightly above average triglycerides.  Review 
of systems otherwise negative.
 
Physical exam is not performed at this time.  Blood pressure was 152/76 
on the right, 152/76 on the left, temperature was 96.8, respirations 20 
and unlabored, and pulse was 70.
 
ASSESSMENT/PLAN: This is a 75 year old man with multiple medical 
problems coming in for follow-up.
1.   Hypertension - the patient will stay on his Zestril and will use 
     Hytrin now, both for his hypertension, as well as benign prostatic 
     hypertrophy.  The patient does speak of some nocturnal dribbling, 
     and he said he also has urge incontinence, particularly while 
     standing.  The patient was told that after a trial of Hytrin, which 
     hopefully can help with his symptoms of benign prostatic 
     hypertrophy, that this urge incontinency will also be helped.  If 
     the patient's symptoms continue beyond this, he will be referred to 
     Urology for possible TUNA procedure.
 
2.   BPH - please see above.  The patient will stay on Hytrin for now.
 
3.   ? coronary artery disease - the patient's cholesterol is 190 with a 
     slightly above average triglycerides, which is more than acceptable 
     for this gentleman.  I do not have an HDL in which to judge his 
     ratio, but I was by the patient before that it runs in the high 40s 
     MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
476 Will St                           Vicente, Kadeem
Sandpoint, MI 58543                             CK759182
(033) 250-1408                                12-27-92
PAGE 2
 
     or low 50s.  Therefore this will be an acceptable ratio without 
     therapy.  I will get a fasting lipid on the patient probably in 
     about 6 months, and if there is any derangement in his profile, he 
     will be put on an antilipid drug.
 
4.   GI - at this point his GERD symptoms have not returned, and what I 
     will attempt to do is to keep him off his H2 blockers at this 
     point.  Should his symptoms return, the patient most likely will be 
     placed on Prilosec.
 
I will seen him in one month for follow-up, primarily for evaluation of 
his use of Hytrin.
 
 
______________________________
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
 
KT:TR:9254
DD:12-27-92  
DT:01-01-93
DV:12-27-92
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2092-12-27" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="28" end="53" text="MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="54" end="76" text="Stephen A.N. Xayachack" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="83" end="94" text="039 Will St" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="121" end="136" text="Vicente, Kadeem" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="137" end="146" text="Sandpoint" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="148" end="150" text="MI" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="151" end="156" text="58543" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="185" end="193" text="CK759182" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P9" start="194" end="208" text="(033) 250-1408" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="240" end="248" text="12-27-92" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="258" end="272" text="Kadeem Vicente" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="2136" end="2138" text="75" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P13" start="3190" end="3215" text="MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="3216" end="3238" text="Stephen A.N. Xayachack" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P15" start="3245" end="3256" text="476 Will St" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="3283" end="3298" text="Vicente, Kadeem" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P17" start="3299" end="3308" text="Sandpoint" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P18" start="3310" end="3312" text="MI" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P19" start="3313" end="3318" text="58543" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<ID id="P20" start="3347" end="3355" text="CK759182" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P21" start="3356" end="3370" text="(033) 250-1408" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="3402" end="3410" text="12-27-92" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P23" start="4043" end="4065" text="Stephen A.N. Xayachack" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P24" start="4074" end="4084" text="KT:TR:9254" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="4088" end="4096" text="12-27-92" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="4102" end="4110" text="01-01-93" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P27" start="4114" end="4122" text="12-27-92" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>