<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2095-09-30

                     SPENCER EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

VICENTE,KADEEM FRANCIS   948-59-58-0              VISIT DATE: 09/30/95

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest discomfort. 

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 78-year-old gentleman 

who had a stuttering course of chest discomfort throughout the 

night, last night, and into today.  He finally took nitroglycerin 

tablets at about 9 or 10:00 a.m. and this abated his chest 

discomfort.  The patient has known history of coronary artery 

disease and recently had gone back on his coronary rehab program, 

however, yesterday after a workout, he became extremely tired, more 

tire than usual.  He thought he might have pushed it a bit and he 

rested throughout the rest of the day.  Then last night, he had 

some chest discomfort, which he initially did not think much of. 

Then was then associated with some shortness of breath in the early 

morning hours.  He felt he was wheezing.  This resolved after he 

got up and walked around.  He took the nitroglycerin tablets this 

morning.  These were fresh nitroglycerin tablets he had just 

obtained and this, in fact, resolved his symptoms.  He then came in 

to see Dr. Echeverria, his physician, in clinic and was sent to the 

emergency department for evaluation.  Please see the handwritten 

emergency department record for additional details. 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Coronary artery disease 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  See handwritten emergency 

department record. 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is presently comfortable, not 

tachypneic.  His blood pressure is 160/80.  His heart rate is in 

the 50s.  There is no evidence of congestive heart failure on 

examination.  There is no jugular venous distention and his lungs 

are clear to auscultation.  His heart examination is distant, with 

no murmurs or gallops appreciated.  His extremities have trace 

edema.  Abdomen in soft and non-tender.  Pulses are equal. 

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  His electrocardiogram shows a left bundle 

branch pattern with no change in configuration from previous 

tracings.  His other laboratory studies are pending. 

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The case was discussed with his 

physician, Dr. Echeverria.  We both agree that the patient has 

probably had a progression of his coronary syndrome with possible 

unstable plaque, given his episode of shortness of breath and 

paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea.  It is possible that he has silent 

ischemia, which is not evident because of the left bundle branch 

pattern.  Pending the other evaluation and studies, which are being 

sent at this time, the patient will require hospitalization for 

further medical management. 

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Acute coronary insufficiency, coronary artery 

disease. 

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 

admitted to the hospital in stable condition. 

___________________________________                    BR445/05178 

STEPHEN HENDERSON, M.D.   SH44                             D:09/30/95 

                                                       T:09/30/95 

Dictated by:  STEPHEN HENDERSON, M.D.   SH44 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2095-09-30" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="56" text="SPENCER" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="82" end="104" text="VICENTE,KADEEM FRANCIS" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="107" end="118" text="948-59-58-0" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="144" end="152" text="09/30/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="241" end="243" text="78" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="1211" end="1221" text="Echeverria" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="2253" end="2263" text="Echeverria" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="2984" end="2995" text="BR445/05178" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2998" end="3015" text="STEPHEN HENDERSON" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="3024" end="3028" text="SH44" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3059" end="3067" text="09/30/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="3127" end="3135" text="09/30/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="3152" end="3169" text="STEPHEN HENDERSON" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="3178" end="3182" text="SH44" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>