<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2064-07-17







Name:  Xochilt Vuong

MRN:  6398353





REASON FOR VISIT:  Xochilt Vuong is a 74-year-old patient of Dr. Wanda Yeomans, and is sent because of rising serum creatinine.



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Vuong has a history of diabetes mellitus 

going back more than 10 years.  She also has had hypertension and elevated lipids 

over approximately the same period of time.  She has a complicated history 

including lung cancer and colon cancer, both treated and in remission.  Her 

creatinine has been rising gradually over recent years with a value of 1.0 in 2062, 

1.2 in May 2063, 2.1 and 1.8 in early 2064 with 2.3 in May 2064, and recently 3.1 

obtained on July 06, 2064.



She has been quite anemic in the recent months with a hematocrit level of 24.9.  

Her serum folate, B12, and iron and are not particularly low, and MCV is normal 

at 81.  Urinalysis showed 3+ albumin in September 2062 and persisting 

proteinuria since that time.  Dr. Yeomans obtained an ultrasound examination in 

March, which showed diffusely thinned renal cortices, but no evidence of 

obstruction, stones, or masses.



She has visited an ophthalmologist regularly for macular degeneration.  She does 

not know whether signs of diabetes are present, but she has had no laser treatment 

for any proliferative retinopathy.



Recently, she has been feeling unusually fatigued with diminished appetite and 

almost constant nausea.  She vomits rarely.  Her weight has fallen by about 20 

pounds.  She is slightly constipated.  She is moderately dyspneic on exertion.  She 

is not troubled by muscle cramps or by unusual itching of her skin.



Her medications continue as listed with ACE inhibitors, "statins," and a rather 

large dose of Lasix at 80 mg twice a day.



Medications

Paxil 20.0 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Synthroid 0.05 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Multivitamins 1 TAB QD

One Touch Test Strips : As directed.

LORAZEPAM 0.5 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Accupril (QUINAPRIL) 10 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Calcium Gluconate 500MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO BID

Serevent (SALMETEROL) 2 PUFFS NAS BID

Atrovent Inhaler (IPRATROPIUM Inhaler) 2 PUFFS NAS BID

Ecasa (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated) 81MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO 1 TAQD

Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 80MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO BID

Lopressor (METOPROLOL Tartrate) 50MG, 0.5 Tablet(s) PO BID

Fe Gluconate (FERROUS Gluconate) 325MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO TID

Glucophage (METFORMIN) 500MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO : 2 tabs po qam, 2 tabs po qpm.

Caltrate 600 1 TAB PO BID

Avandia (ROSIGLITAZONE) 4MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

Ocuvite (MULTIVITAMINS) 1 TAB PO QD

Fosamax (ALENDRONATE) 70MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QWEEK

Prilosec (OMEPRAZOLE) 20MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO BID

Lipitor 40 MG PO 1 TAB QD 





PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On examination today, she looks tired but 

reasonably comfortable.  She speaks in a high-pitched somewhat hoarse voice, 

which has persisted since one of her surgical procedures.  Her blood pressure in 

the right arm, sitting, is 148/60 with regular pulse 72.  Her chest has a few basal 

crackles but in general is clear and air moves comfortably.  JVP fills below the 

sternal angle heart shows a grade 2 systolic murmur, loudest at the upper left 

sternal border.  Abdomen is soft and nontender.  There is no renal tenderness.  

Extremities have no edema.



IMPRESSION:  Progressive renal failure in a 74-year-old woman with more than 

10 years' history of diabetes as well has hypertension and hyperlipidemia.  The 

proteinuria, if confirmed, would support the diagnosis of diabetic nephropathy but 

this would be unusual in the absence of retinopathy.  It would be useful to know 

from her ophthalmologist whether retinopathy is present.  It is, of course, also 

possible that she has vascular disease involving the kidneys.  Their symmetry and 

the presence of proteinuria would argue against this possibility.  The ACE 

inhibitor in the presence of vascular disease might of course raise her serum 

creatinine by reducing renal blood flow somewhat.  Her loss of appetite and 

nausea may well be related to the degree of renal failure.



RECOMMENDATION:  I would suggest that she see Filomena Xia, RD, a renal 

dietitian, to learn a diet appropriate for renal failure as well as for her diabetes and 

hyperlipidemia.  This might succeed in reducing some of her nausea.  It think it 

would be worthwhile as an experiment to reduce or discontinue her Accupril and 

perhaps  her Lasix temporarily to see whether serum creatinine falls with 

less ACE inhibition and somewhat more fluid volume.  If, of course, shortness of 

breath worsens or edema appears, then returning to the Lasix would be 

reasonable.  It might be that a longer acting, milder diuretic, such as 5 mg of 

metolazone might help to control edema (and potassium) and reduce the 

requirement for Lasix.  If serum creatinine fell appreciably with less ACE and 

diuresis, it would reassure us that the damage was not all structural, and it might 

be then possible to return to these medicines with less worry.



Her anemia is no doubt related to lack of erythropoietin and would likely benefit 

from instituting therapy with Epogen (such as 4000 units twice a week) or 

Aranesp).



PLAN:  We will send a urine today for total protein to creatinine ratio, which may 

help us decide whether the problem is mainly diabetic nephropathy.  If so, the 

measures proposed would be appropriate.  We discussed the eventual probable 

need for dialysis (assuming no other intercurrent medical catastrophes).  It would 

be useful for her to visit the DCGH Renal Department (located here on our 

floor at 592G, along with Ms. Xia's office) to learn about modes of dialysis.  

We discussed construction of a forearm fistula, which should be done well before 

a need for it arises.  I would, in fact, recommend that she proceed to have this 

done in the next few months.  This could be arranged through Dr. Xaysana's office 

or perhaps by speaking with Dr. Najee Yuan.  I will, of course, help with any of 

these measures as necessary.









Xander Xie, M.D.





Wanda

Urine total protein/creatinine ratio is only 0.11 (corresponding to about 0.1 g/day or proteinuria).  This is a very small amount for diabetic nephropathy, and argues in favor of vascular disease.  I would suggest getting a MRA of renal arteries to look for any main artery obstruction.  If present it would account for the sensitivity of her creatinine to ACE or changes in hydration.



Kyle



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2064-07-17" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="41" end="54" text="Xochilt Vuong" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="62" end="69" text="6398353" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="94" end="107" text="Xochilt Vuong" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P4" start="113" end="115" text="74" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="140" end="153" text="Wanda Yeomans" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="239" end="244" text="Vuong" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="599" end="603" text="2062" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="614" end="622" text="May 2063" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="645" end="649" text="2064" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="662" end="670" text="May 2064" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="703" end="716" text="July 06, 2064" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="926" end="940" text="September 2062" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="992" end="999" text="Yeomans" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="1040" end="1045" text="March" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P15" start="3327" end="3329" text="74" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="4122" end="4134" text="Filomena Xia" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P17" start="5556" end="5560" text="DCGH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="5631" end="5634" text="Xia" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P21" start="5913" end="5920" text="Xaysana" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P22" start="5964" end="5974" text="Najee Yuan" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P23" start="6053" end="6063" text="Xander Xie" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P24" start="6075" end="6080" text="Wanda" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P25" start="6471" end="6475" text="Kyle" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>