<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2077-02-01

             				

 Critical care					 





TRANSPLANT FELLOW ADMIT NOTE





HPI: 42 year old man s/p bilateral lung transplantation for bronchiectasis in 7/73 transferred from Burlington Obstetrics Gynecology Center for further evaluation of N/V/D, fever and hypoxia.  Over the past six weeks he had reported a slow decline in respiratory function  prompting a recent admission here 1/23 -25/77 for elective bronchoscopy to rule out rejection.  He noted a slight spontaneous improvement a few days before that admission.  Bronchoscopy showed no rejection but washings did grow M. catarrhalis -levaquin was begun on 1/25/77.  Pt reports continued slow improvement in dyspnea following discharge.  Yesterday morning he developed watery diarrhea (no blood or mucus) soon followed by nausea and vomiting (no blood or coffee grounds).  He went to BOGC and describes feeling increased dyspnea.  Found to be febrile to 101F and hypoxic (SpO2 94%, PaO2 53) and started on supplemental oxygen.  GI symptoms have since improved and pt is tolerating PO.  Denies chest pain, palpitations, cough, rash, HA, rhinorrhea, sore throat at any point during this illness.  Currently no dyspnea at rest.  



PMH: OSA, obesity, osteoporosis, gout, HTN, CRI, avascular necrosis of R hip/knee, depression, psoriasis



Current Meds: 

Imm: neoral 125 mg po bid, cellcept 500 mg po bid, prednisone 30 mg po qd

Abx: levaquin 500 mg po qd (1/25), bactrim ss 1 po tiw, acyclovir 200 mg po tid

Other: atenolol 25 mg po qd, norvasc 5 mg po qd, nexium 20 mg po qd, MgGlu 500 mg po tid, Kdur 20 mEq po qd, lipitor 40 mg po qd, Ca citrate/vit D/MVI, lasix 40 mg po qd, cozaar 100 mg po qd



SH: Lives in Florida with wife.  Works at ion media networks.



FH: noncontributory



Objective:

Vitals:  Tm 96.5  HR 71  BP 145/91  RR 22  SpO2  97% on 2L NC

Gen: NAD, obese

HEENT/neck: OP clear, MMM

Lungs/chest: CTA bilat, reduced breath sounds

Heart: RRR w/o m/r/g

Abd: SNTND +BS

Extr: no c/c/e, 2+ pulses



Lab: significant for

BUN 36, Cr 2.1

WBC 3.4, Hct 39, Plt 115



Micro: 

Nasal swab 1/31/77 - negative viral panel

Lung washings 1/23/77 - moderate M. catarrhalis



Path: Transbrochial biopsy 1/23 - negative for tissue rejection



CXR 1/31: Unremarkable 



Impression: 

42 year old man s/p bilateral lung transplant 7/73 for bronchiectasis developed acute GI illness in setting of levaquin tx for recent respiratory infection.  Now afebrile and with resolution of GI symptoms.  Remains somewhat dyspneic with normal BP and HR.  Azotemia possibly attributable to dehydration though concern for other etiologies as per Dr. Reilly's note.  WBCs reduced from recent levels.



Recommendations: 

GI illness: Mostly asymptomatic now though some concerning abnormalities remain (O2 requirement, low plt, low WBC, high Cr).  Remains hemodynamically stable.  Await results of panculture including stool studies (including C diff, E coli, Camphylobacter) when available.  

Transplant: Continue current immunosuppression and prophylactic abx.  Will consider holding cellcept, valcyte if leukopenia persists/worsens.  Follow daily cyclosporin troughs.  No evidence of rejection on recent biopsy.

Dyspnea: Consider aspiration though CXR negative, will follow.  Hold abx for now.

Renal: Azotemia of unclear etiology, follow up labs pending.  Renal consult per Dr. Reilly.









 

___________________

Oscar B. Stanley, M.D.

Pulmonary Fellow

Pager: 34348







]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2077-02-01" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P2" start="112" end="114" text="42" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="185" end="189" text="7/73" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="207" end="246" text="Burlington Obstetrics Gynecology Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="414" end="425" text="1/23 -25/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="646" end="653" text="1/25/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="873" end="877" text="BOGC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="1446" end="1450" text="1/25" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P9" start="1706" end="1713" text="Florida" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="1735" end="1753" text="ion media networks" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2100" end="2107" text="1/31/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2146" end="2153" text="1/23/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2210" end="2214" text="1/23" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="2254" end="2258" text="1/31" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P15" start="2291" end="2293" text="42" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="2337" end="2341" text="7/73" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="2642" end="2648" text="Reilly" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="3375" end="3381" text="Reilly" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="3416" end="3432" text="Oscar B. Stanley" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P20" start="3465" end="3470" text="34348" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>