<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2083-04-03


Beaumont Hospital Physician Group
090 Crowley Avenue                                    Rhodes, Yajaira
Rutland, FL 94265                            97627182
(153) 636-7011                                           04/03/83
(584) 728-8734

SUBJECTIVE:  The patient returns having been in Maine for
the winter in the past five months.  Her husband visited
ever three weeks or so.  She is walking somewhat better with
less pain but moves very slowly.  She says that for the past
two weeks she first had some substernal pressure which moved
down into her abdomen and now instead of having one bowel
movement every one or two weeks she is having a bowel
movement three times a week which is formed and not bloody. 
 She put herself on Pepto-Bismol and is gradually getting
better.

She has not had any chest pain, tachycardia, palpitations,
cough or hemoptysis.  She has no visual signs.  She has not
been seen by the ophthalmologist recently.  Her hearing is
good.  She has mammograms yearly.  She sees her gynecologist
on a yearly basis, Dr. Giles, having changed from Dr. Godfrey.
 She is not sexually active.  

She is not dieting and has not lost any weight.  Her back
pain is somewhat better.  

MEDICATIONS:  She is on the following medications:  
1.  Lipitor 20 mg q.d. 
2.  Glynase 1.5 mg b.i.d. 
3.  Avandia 4 mg q.a.m. 
4.  Trandate 100 mg q.d. 
5.  Tegretol 300 mg in the a.m. and 200 the evening (changed
to 200 mg b.i.d.).  
6.  Neurontin 200 mg b.i.d. 
7.  Premarin 0.625 mg 30 days a month.  
8.  Provera 5 mg 12 days a month.  
9.  Enteric coated aspirin 81 mg q.d.
10. Calcium 1200 mg q.d. 

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Her diabetes has been poorly regulated
and hopefully the Avandia will make her feel better.  She
states that she takes the Avandia in the morning and she
feels very weak at lunchtime such that she has to get an
orange juice.  She says that her blood sugar has dropped but
when she checks it, it has been around 100 mg%  and I
explained to her that it is a normal blood sugar but it may
be that the drop causes her to have symptoms.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: She weighs 192 lbs stripped which is a
weight gain for her.  Her blood pressure is 122/76 in the
right arm sitting with a wide cuff.  She appears as a well
developed, pleasant white female, grossly overweight, moving
slowly and can only get up on the examining table with help
because of her back pain.  There is no icterus, cyanosis or
edema.  The pupils are round, reactive and equal and react
equally to light and accommodation.  Nose and throat
examination is unremarkable.  Neck veins are flat.  Carotids
are 2+ and equal and without bruit.  Lungs are clear to P&A.
 Breasts reveal no masses or discharge.  The heart is not
enlarged.  There is a regular sinus rhythm and no
significant murmurs.  S1 and S2 are of normal intensity. 
Liver and spleen are not felt.  Bowel sounds are normal. 
There are no abdominal masses or tenderness.  This is a
female escutcheon.  Rectal was deferred.  She has fair
peripheral pulses and decreased vibration sense in her feet.

IMPRESSION:
1.  Diabetes mellitus, poorly regulated.  Will check
glycohemoglobin today.  
2.  Diabetic neuropathy.  
3.  L2-L3 disk with fusion.  
4.  Hypercholesterolemia on Lipitor.
5.  Weight management problem.


______________________________
Brett F. Rutherford, M.D.


eScription document:6-015285 DOeScription

DD: 04/03/83
DT: 04/03/83
DV: 04/03/83



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2083-04-03" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="29" end="46" text="Beaumont Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P2" start="63" end="81" text="090 Crowley Avenue" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="117" end="132" text="Rhodes, Yajaira" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="133" end="140" text="Rutland" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="142" end="144" text="FL" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="145" end="150" text="94265" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<ID id="P7" start="178" end="186" text="97627182" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P8" start="187" end="201" text="(153) 636-7011" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="244" end="252" text="04/03/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P10" start="253" end="267" text="(584) 728-8734" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P11" start="317" end="322" text="Maine" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="1069" end="1074" text="Giles" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="1100" end="1107" text="Godfrey" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="3326" end="3345" text="Brett F. Rutherford" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P15" start="3374" end="3382" text="6-015285" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="3401" end="3409" text="04/03/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="3414" end="3422" text="04/03/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="3427" end="3435" text="04/03/83" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>