<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2059-08-09

EDVISIT^43471375^KIMBROUGH, AMELIA^08/09/59^STEELE, SHAYLYN

This patient was seen with resident, Dr. Penn, whose note was

reviewed and confirmed by me.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 46-year-old woman with

end-stage renal disease secondary to minimal chain disease, on

hemodialysis, presenting with severe hypertension, headache,

nausea, and vomiting in the setting of blood pressures in the

200s/100s today.

Please review resident's note for full details of past medical

history, social history, review of systems, medications, and

allergies.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  I confirm the physical exam is as

documented.  The patient is awake, alert, and appears to be in

mild to moderate discomfort.  Vital signs reveal pulse of 108,

respirations 22, blood pressure 226/129, and oximetry is 96% on

room air.  The patient is afebrile.  HEENT exam reveals well

visualized disks bilaterally on funduscopic exam.  There is no

papilledema noted.  Posterior pharynx is clear.  Lungs are clear

to auscultation with good air movement throughout.  Heart is

regular.  Abdomen is soft.  Extremity exam reveals no cyanosis,

clubbing, or edema.  Neurologic:  The patient is intact.  There

is a left brachiocephalic shunt noted with a good thrill easily

palpable.

LABORATORY DATA:  White count is 5.4, hematocrit 45, BUN and

creatinine 31 and 6.0, potassium is noted at 5.3%, cardiac

enzymes flat, and coags are unremarkable.

IMAGING STUDIES:  EKG is sinus rhythm without any ST or T-wave

changes concerning for ischemia.  Head CT shows no acute

processes.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient was given IV fluids and

treated with Zofran for her nausea, labetalol 200 mg p.o.

followed by 10 mg intravenously, which brought her pressure down

very nicely to 168/86.  After fluids, Zofran, and blood pressure

control, her symptoms improved dramatically.  She was admitted to

the Observation Unit to monitor her blood pressure overnight with

anticipated discharge in the morning.

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

DIAGNOSIS:  Hypertensive urgency.

______________________________

STEELE, SHAYLYN 

D: 08/12/59

T: 08/12/59

Dictated By: STEELE, SHAYLYN

eScription document:2-5546221 BFFocus





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2059-08-09" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="43471375" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="62" text="KIMBROUGH, AMELIA" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="63" end="71" text="08/09/59" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="72" end="87" text="STEELE, SHAYLYN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="130" end="134" text="Penn" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="222" end="224" text="46" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="2155" end="2170" text="STEELE, SHAYLYN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="2176" end="2184" text="08/12/59" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2189" end="2197" text="08/12/59" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2212" end="2227" text="STEELE, SHAYLYN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P11" start="2249" end="2258" text="2-5546221" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>