<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2059-01-10

EDVISIT^43471375^Kimbrough, Amelia^01/10/59^KRIEGER, STEVEN

I confirm that I have interviewed and examined the patient,

reviewed the resident's documentation on the patient's chart, and

discussed the evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the

patient and the resident, Dr. Frantz.  Please see his note for

full details.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 46-year-old female who

complains of shortness of breath and productive cough.  She has

had a history of diabetes, high cholesterol, depression, renal

disease, GERD, of nephrotic hypothyroidism, and history of

nephrotic syndrome secondary to minimal change disease and

nephropathy.  She presents with 3 weeks of productive cough with

shortness of breath began about 3 weeks prior to presentation

while in the Denmark, 2 days later she began having a

productive cough with sputum that was green, copious and

malodorous at this time.  She states that she is having fever,

chills, shortness of breath, epistaxis, neck and back pain, and

edema.  No nausea or diarrhea and no headache.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  She has had a thyroidectomy.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She denies tobacco, ETOH, or IV drugs.  She

lives with her family.

MEDICATIONS:  She is on multiple medications.  Please see

resident's and nurse's note for those.

ALLERGIES:  She has an ACE inhibitor allergy.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is awake, alert, and in

mild-to-moderate distress.  Temperature is 97, pulse is 109,

respiratory rate 24, blood pressure 139/81, and saturations are

100%.  Pharynx is normal.  Her neck is supple and nontender.  She

has decreased air movement with some wheezing bilaterally.  Her

heart is tachycardic without a murmur.  Her abdomen is distended

and nontender.  Skin is intact.  She has pedal edema.  She is

oriented x3 with normal neuro exam.

LABORATORY DATA:  Her white count is 6, her platelets are

377,000, and hematocrit is 29.  Sodium is 135 and potassium is

2.9.  BUN is 27, creatinine is 4.7, and glucose 79.  Her calcium

is 6.3.  Urine is pending.  Her chest x-ray shows no pneumonia

with an elevated left hemidiaphragm.

PLAN:  At this time, the plan is for her to receive further

laboratory analysis, UA, and EKG.  We are going to contact her

PCP and Renal and going to admit her.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSES:

1.  Shortness of breath.

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

3.  Acute renal failure, chronic renal insufficiency.

4.  Hypokalemia.

5.  Hypocalcemia.

DISPOSITION:  She should be admitted.

CONDITION:  She is in satisfactory condition.

______________________________

KRIEGER, STEVEN M.D.

D: 02/02/59

T: 02/02/59

Dictated By: KRIEGER, STEVEN

eScription document:3-9490927 BFFocus





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2059-01-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="43471375" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="62" text="Kimbrough, Amelia" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="63" end="71" text="01/10/59" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="72" end="87" text="KRIEGER, STEVEN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="313" end="319" text="Frantz" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="401" end="403" text="46" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="816" end="823" text="Denmark" TYPE="COUNTRY" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="2623" end="2638" text="KRIEGER, STEVEN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2648" end="2656" text="02/02/59" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2661" end="2669" text="02/02/59" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2684" end="2699" text="KRIEGER, STEVEN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P12" start="2721" end="2730" text="3-9490927" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>