<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2093-10-18

NAME:     Wilson, Gabriel

MRN:     8514931



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Gabriel Wilson is a 72-year-old Croatian

female, referred by Dr. Fraser for evaluation of complaints of dizziness. Her daughter,

who is a Library Manager here, accompanies her mother today. Apparently, for

many years, perhaps as many as five, her mother has complained of "feeling pulled"

when she walks. This never occurs when lying down or sitting. It is only when she is

walking that she feels she is being pulled, either to the right, left, forward or

backward. At times, she does visibly veer when she walks. She has had one fall a

number of months ago when she broke her wrist. She has not had any subsequent

falls. There is no associated true spinning vertigo, no associated visual change,

numbness, weakness, change in gait, change in speech and no headache. She actually

feels that over the past few weeks, it has been a little better, though prior to that, it

was a little more severe. Unable to associate this with any clear intervention.

Unaware of any precipitating or alleviating symptoms. 



Review of other systems notable for general fatigue. Otherwise unremarkable. No

chest pain, shortness of breath or abdominal pain. 



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: Hepatitis B, diabetes, hypertension, GE reflux,

hyperlipidemia, depression, cataracts. 



MEDICATIONS:  Aspirin, Colace, Cozaar, Flonase, Fosamax, hydrochlorothiazide,

Lopid, meclizine p.r.n., Protonix, Prozac, Vioxx. 



FAMILY HISTORY: Negative for neurologic disease. 



SOCIAL HISTORY:  She is widowed and lives with her niece. She neither drinks nor

smokes. 



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: On exam, she is a pleasant, quiet, soft-spoken,

72-year-old female. BP 140/84. Cranial nerves II through XII intact to detailed exam,

except for decreased hearing on the left. On motor exam, no rigidity, no drift. Good

power throughout upper and lower extremities. She does, however, seem mildly

bradykinetic diffusely. Finger tapping was slow bilaterally and symmetric. Amplitude

is normal for finger tapping. Power in the lower extremities 5/5. Sensory exam with

mild vibratory loss in the toes. Finger-to-nose testing intact. Foot-tapping decreased

bilaterally. Romberg sway. Her gait is slightly wide-based, with occasional veering to

either side. She is unable to perform tandem. DTR's 2+ throughout, except for 1+

ankle jerks. Babinski flexor bilaterally. 



DATA: MRI/MRA of the brain 8/30 shows mild to moderate white matter

hyperintensity in the corona radiata, centrum semiovale and moderate bilateral

pontine involvement and multifocal lacunar infarcts of the lentiform nuclei, right

internal capsule and bilateral thalami. Intracranial atherosclerosis is seen involving the

anterior middle cerebral arteries with a greater degree of involvement of the

posterior cerebral arteries and intermittent development of moderate mid-segment

stenosis of the basilar artery. Bloodwork 2/27: SMA7 normal, except glucose 134. 8/30

bili, total protein, albumin, globulin within normal limits. LFT's normal except SGOT

elevated at 46. 



IMPRESSION: 72-year-old female with diabetes, chronic hepatitis C and

hypertension, complaining of basically veering of her gait and feeling unsteady. She is

symptomatic only when she walks. Her exam is notable for mild vibratory loss in the

toes, likely due to diabetic neuropathy, bilateral lower-extremity dysmetria and the

wide-based, at times veering gait. It appears that her gait difficulties with veering  are

multifactorial, due to history of multiple lacunar infarcts and peripheral neuropathy.

It does not appear that these episodes are due to transient ischemic attacks, given

that she veered in the office while walking and stated that this was the symptom she

is concerned about.  However, given her mid-segment basilar stenosis seen on MRI,

she certainly could become symptomatic from this down the road, particularly if she

became hypotensive. As she was unable to tolerate Aggrenox, will try adding

Persantine at a lower dose at 25 mg b.i.d., along with an aspirin per day, to see if she

can tolerate gradually increased doses of Persantine. I will see her in follow up in two

months to see how she is doing. May also consider checking CBC, given her

symptoms of fatigue and other bloodwork should these symptoms persist. 



Hope Kincaid, M.D.



CC: Julie Fraser, M.D.



HK/crane/kang



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2093-10-18" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="38" end="53" text="Wilson, Gabriel" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="64" end="71" text="8514931" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="104" end="118" text="Gabriel Wilson" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P4" start="124" end="126" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="136" end="144" text="Croatian" TYPE="COUNTRY" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="170" end="176" text="Fraser" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P7" start="244" end="259" text="Library Manager" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="1725" end="1727" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2478" end="2482" text="8/30" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2979" end="2983" text="2/27" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3018" end="3022" text="8/30" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="3143" end="3145" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="4388" end="4400" text="Hope Kincaid" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="4414" end="4426" text="Julie Fraser" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="4436" end="4438" text="HK" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="4439" end="4444" text="crane" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="4445" end="4449" text="kang" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>