<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2076-08-30

EDVISIT^24490460^VAUGHN, FRANK^08/30/76^JABLONSKI, SHIRLEY

The patient was interviewed and examined by myself, Dr. Jablonski,

as well as the resident, Dr. Ortiz for visit on 08/30/2076. 

Please see note for details reviewed in full.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is an obese 32-year-old

gentleman with history of high cholesterol, hypertension, and

diabetes who comes in after trying to increase his exercise over

the last couple of weeks with shortness of breath and fatigue and

difficulty breathing since his walking yesterday.  He went to bed

and woke up today with continued symptoms.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Besides his past medical history, he has a

significant CAD in his grandfather with CHF.  His father died at

early age of 19 of a traumatic accident.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She does not drink and does not smoke.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  He himself has had no surgeries except a

cholecystectomy.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Shortness of breath, no chest pain, no

lightheadedness, no leg swelling, no palpitations, and came in

acutely diaphoretic with shortness of breath.

MEDICATIONS:  Lantus, glipizide, Zocor, atenolol, and was

recently started insulin as above a week ago.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Mildly obese gentleman with a pulse of

100, respiratory rate 28, O2 saturation 97 on 4 L, blood pressure

132/69, and temperature 98.1.  HEENT is anicteric.  Neck is

supple.  Heart is regular rate and rhythm although distant heart

sounds.  He is tachypneic but no obvious wheezes.  He has soft

abdomen.  Extremities showed no cyanosis, clubbing, or edema, no

calf tenderness.  Neurologic:  Oriented x3.  No obvious cranial,

motor, or sensory deficits.

Differential can be acute coronary syndrome versus PE.  His

weight is 330 pounds, went ahead and got a d-dimer, which was

negative.  We went ahead and got an EKG, which is normal.  Normal

chest x-ray.  Normal CKs, troponins, and SMA-7.  His magnesium is

slightly therapeutic at 1.7, which was repleted.  His hematocrit

and white count were normal.

DIAGNOSIS:  Shortness of breath, concern for ischemic equivalent.

DISPOSITION:  Admitted to the Medicine Service in stable

condition.

______________________________

JABLONSKI, SHIRLEY M.D.

D: 08/30/76

T: 08/30/76

Dictated By: JABLONSKI, SHIRLEY

eScription document:2-3735520 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2076-08-30" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="24490460" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="58" text="VAUGHN, FRANK" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="59" end="67" text="08/30/76" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="68" end="86" text="JABLONSKI, SHIRLEY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="144" end="153" text="Jablonski" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="185" end="190" text="Ortiz" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="204" end="214" text="08/30/2076" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="311" end="313" text="32" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P9" start="771" end="773" text="19" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2261" end="2279" text="JABLONSKI, SHIRLEY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2289" end="2297" text="08/30/76" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2302" end="2310" text="08/30/76" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2325" end="2343" text="JABLONSKI, SHIRLEY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P14" start="2365" end="2374" text="2-3735520" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>