<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2065-12-19
EDVISIT^60244986^XIAN, BROOKLYN^12/19/65^QUAGLIA, BRONSON

I confirm that I have interviewed and examined the patient and

reviewed the PA's documentation.  Please see her note for full

details.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Xian is a 70-year-old female

with a history of non-insulin-dependent diabetes, history of

cholecystectomy, and Lap-Band in 2062 who presents with right

upper quadrant abdominal pain, nausea but no vomiting, and

decreased p.o. intake.  Denies any fevers.  She reports that it

is 8/10 and 12/10 at its worst.  She also on review of systems

reports some chest pain on the left side radiating down her left

arm and left shoulder.  No previous episodes.  No trauma, no

urinary symptoms, no vomiting, and no diarrhea.  She saw her PCP

earlier this week on 12/17/2065 and had a CT scan, which was

reportedly normal and it is in our system and we have confirmed

this reading.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Noncontributory.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Normal.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise, negative.  LMR notes on 12/17/2065

from her PCP reveals same steady mild waxing and waning right

upper quadrant abdominal pain radiating to the back, not

pleuritic.  No shortness of breath.  No fevers, cough, or chills.

 No changes in her stools.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  She has a history of sleep apnea, atypical

chest pain, diabetes, obesity, gastric banding, and some

dementia.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Here, heart rate 76, respiratory rate 18,

blood pressure 118/77, saturations 97%, and temperature 96.6. 

She is obese.  Dry Mucous membranes.  Slightly pale.  Neck is

supple.  No respiratory distress.  Normal breath sounds.  Heart: 

Regular rate and rhythm without a murmur.  Abdomen with right

upper quadrant tenderness.  Negative Murphy's.  No

hepatosplenomegaly and no CVA tenderness.

IMPRESSION:  This 70-year-old female with abdominal pain.

LABORATORY DATA:  White count of 15.6, hematocrit 42.  The rest

of her labs are pending.  Chest x-ray and right upper quadrant

ultrasound pending.  Otherwise, we have given IV fluids and

morphine.  She is on telemetry.

Diagnoses at this time, abdominal pain and chest pain.  Abdominal

pain.  With a negative CT scan, labs and ultrasound that are

reassuring.  We will proceed with pain control at that time. 

Chest pain.  We will ____ check a troponin and EKG and keep her

in telemetry.  She will get ____ and if there has been a negative

recent nuclear stress test, we will go ahead and proceed with ED

Observation admission in the morning for a MIBI stress test.

DIAGNOSES:

1.  Abdominal pain.

2.  Chest pain.

______________________________

QUAGLIA, BRONSON M.D.

D: 12/19/65

T: 12/19/65

Dictated By: QUAGLIA, BRONSON

eScription document:0-75166654 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2065-12-19" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="35" end="43" text="60244986" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="44" end="58" text="XIAN, BROOKLYN" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="59" end="67" text="12/19/65" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="68" end="84" text="QUAGLIA, BRONSON" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="257" end="261" text="Xian" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="267" end="269" text="70" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="382" end="386" text="2062" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="816" end="826" text="12/17/2065" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="1053" end="1063" text="12/17/2065" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P10" start="1853" end="1855" text="70" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2651" end="2667" text="QUAGLIA, BRONSON" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2677" end="2685" text="12/19/65" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="2690" end="2698" text="12/19/65" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="2713" end="2729" text="QUAGLIA, BRONSON" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P15" start="2751" end="2761" text="0-75166654" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>