<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2061-07-15



Reason for Visit

This is a  65 year old  female referred to the diabetes management service for poorly  controlled diabetes



Chief Complaint

This patient is admitted to the hospital for lap gastric banding



History of Present Illness

The patient has  history of Type 2 diabetes.  Currently the patient is treated with NPH 40 units sc bid and lispro 15-25 units pre breakfast and dinner.  The control has been fair with recent A1c of 7.2. She is followed at Loudes Hospital for her diabetes care.  The patient tests her blood sugar  at least tid  .Her diabetes has been complicated by symptomatic neuropathy and retinopathy requiring laser therapy.

   

She was admitted yesterday for her banding procedure.  She received NPH 22 units sc last night but not today.While in the hospital glucose levels have been elevated over 200    and the patient has been started on  D5W at 125/hour.  The patient is not yet being fed .



Past Medical History

Concurrent medical problems include:htn, hyperlipidemia, hypothyriodism



Family History

Family history is positive for diabetes       



Social History

The patient is married       .



Habits

The patient is not a smoker.



Review of Systems

ROS: 

Feels well in general. No polyuria, dysuria, polydipsia, change in bowel habits or GI distress. Denies symptoms of skin, bladder upper respiratory infections. Energy appropriate, sleep unremarkable, mood stable. No palpitations or dizziness, headaches or visual symptoms.



Medications

      Quinine (QUININE Sulfate)   324MG CAPSULE  PO QHS PRN  

      Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid)   81MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

      Insulin Nph Human   40 UNITS SC BID BEFORE BREAKFAST AND BEFORE SUPPER 

      Humalog (INSULIN Lispro)   15-25  SC BID BEFORE BREAKFAST AND BEFORE SUPPER PRN sliding scale 

      Levothyroxine Sodium   150 MCG (150MCG TABLET take 1) PO  

      Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE)   25MG TABLET take 1-2 PO QD as directed x 30 days

      Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN)   20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

      Celebrex (CELECOXIB)   200 MG (200MG CAPSULE take 1) PO BID 

      Flonase (FLUTICASONE Nasal Spray)   1-2 SPRAY INH QD PRN as directed , 1-2 sprays each nostril QD as directed

      Alocril 2% (NEDOCROMIL Sodium)   1 DROP OU BID PRN  

      TEMAZEPAM   30 MG (30MG CAPSULE take 1) PO QHS prn 

      ATENOLOL   50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

      LISINOPRIL   40MG TABLET  PO QD 



Laboratory Data

Relevant lab data:

HgA1c 7.2

Creatinine .9



Physical Exam

Vitals Bp120/60  P 70  Wt.281

Skin no acanthosis, no diabetic dermopathy

Heent no asymmetry, no lid lag

Neck no bruits heard no thyromegaly 

Chest clear

Cor S1, S2 normal, no murmurs

Abd obese,  no masses

Extremities no edema, no ulcers ,dorsalis pedis pulses intact 

Neuro    Vibratory sense intact  Monofilament testing intact



Impression

My impression is that her type 2 diabetes requires basal insulin administration while she is NPO and on iv D5W. She should have regular insulin for coverage q 6 hours rather than Novolog while NPO because this will provide 'smoother" coverage



Recommendation

My recommendations are:

1.Please administer NPH 20 units q 12 hours while NPO

2.Change ss to regular insulin q6hours while NPO

3.When taking po and iv D5W has been stopped start Novolog 5 units plus scale pre-meals( liquids to start) and dc regular insulin scale





___________________

Misty U Alston, M.D.





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2061-07-15" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P1" start="59" end="61" text="65" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P2" start="494" end="509" text="Loudes Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="3450" end="3464" text="Misty U Alston" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>