<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2068-12-01

                     MEDIQUIK EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

RUTLEDGE,XAVIER W.   539-54-14-3

I was the patient's doctor during this emergency department stay.

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Infection in the left foot. 

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 59-year-old man 

with multiple medical problems including insulin-requiring diabetes 

who has a chronic, nonhealing ulcer on the plantar surface of his 

left foot.  He now complains of two days of increasing pain and 

redness and systemic malaise.  He denies chest pain, abdominal 

pain, streaking redness up to the thigh, nausea, vomiting, 

diarrhea, and dysuria.  

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Negative except as given above. 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypercholesterolemia, gout, hypertension, 

insulin-requiring diabetes mellitus, chronic renal insufficiency, 

nephrotic syndrome, status post kidney transplant in 2059, on 

cyclosporine, thrombocytopenia, CMV, and hypomagnesemia 

intermittently.  Kidney transplant as noted above.

MEDICATIONS:  Levaquin, cyclosporine, magnesium, Lipitor, Coumadin, 

prednisone, Allopurinol, lisinopril, metoprolol, Lasix, and others 

as noted on the nurses' notes.  

ALLERGIES:  Codeine which caused a rash. 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Social history noncontributory. 

Family history noncontributory.  

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  Awake, alert, spontaneous and 

appropriate, in no distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Normal.  HEENT:  There 

was no evidence of head trauma, conjunctivae clear.  NECK:  Supple 

with no lymphadenopathy and no jugulovenous distention.  CHEST:  

Notable for babasilar rales with normal respiratory excursion.  

HEART:  Regular with no murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, 

nontender, no masses, no organomegaly.  SKIN/EXTREMITIES:  Other 

than the left foot and ankle, the skin and extremities were normal 

with no clubbing, cyanosis, lesions or rashes, although there was 

bilateral 1+ pitting edema in the lower extremities.  The left foot 

had an approximately 1 cm ulcer on the plantar surface and the 

entire left foot and ankle were quite erythematous with increased 

edema relative to the remainder of the lower extremities.  He also 

had tenderness on palpation of the ankle though there was no 

tenderness on passive motion of the toes.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Pending at this time.  The patient is being 

seen by the Surgery Department.  

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Infected diabetic foot ulcer.  

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient will 

be admitted to the Surgery Department for surgical management 

and inpatient medical management.  Condition fair.  

___________________________________                    OO280/953 

QUINTON OSWALD, M.D.   QO05                              D:12/01/68 

                                                       T:12/01/68 

Dictated by:  QUINTON OSWALD, M.D.   QO05 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2068-12-01" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="49" end="57" text="MEDIQUIK" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="83" end="100" text="RUTLEDGE,XAVIER W" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="104" end="115" text="539-54-14-3" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<AGE id="P4" start="288" end="290" text="59" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="904" end="908" text="2059" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="2735" end="2744" text="OO280/953" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2747" end="2761" text="QUINTON OSWALD" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2770" end="2774" text="QO05" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2806" end="2814" text="12/01/68" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2874" end="2882" text="12/01/68" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2899" end="2913" text="QUINTON OSWALD" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="2922" end="2926" text="QO05" TYPE="USERNAME" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>