<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2078-07-30



Reason for Visit

Follow-up



Chief Complaint

L post-auricular pain



History of Present Illness

Developed mild pain in L ear and postauricular area the last two weeks.  No trauma, no hearing loss, no vertigo, no URI symptoms



Problems

      Hypertension

Tolerating Zestril without problems. BP still elevated on Zestril 20mg.

      Obesity

She was started on Xenical by Internal Medicine.  She is taking it only Qd instead of AC, since it is giving her too much loose stool.  She feels increase flatulence, bloating sensation on Xenical.

      Depression

Stable on Prozac.  No adverse side effects.  No SI or HI.

      Knee pain

from medial meniscal tear.  No edema, erythema. Celebrex effective initially but now not.  She is taking on top of Celebrex also Motrin.  She is going for return visit with Dr. Vogel to discuss surgery.

      Anemia

Fe studies, vitamin B12, folate levels all normal. Asymptomatic without CP, SOB, or lightheadedness.  No abnormal vaginal bleeding.



Medications

      Zestril (LISINOPRIL)    20MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Prozac (FLUOXETINE Hcl)    20MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Xenical (ORLISTAT)    120MG,  1 Capsule(s)  PO TID

      IBUPROFEN   800MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO TID

      Vaseretic 10-25 (ENALAPRIL 10mg + Hctz 25mg)    .5 TABLET PO QD



Allergies

      NKDA



Past Medical History

Reviewed electronic data

Reviewed old records

See problem list



Preventive Health History

See Health Maint.



Review of Systems

CONSTITUTIONAL: Appetite good, nutrition adequate

PAIN: see above

BREASTS: Inconsistent self-exam

RESP.: No cough

CVS: No PND, exertional chest pain, claudication. 

GI: No dyspepsia, constipation 

GU: No dysuria, diminished stream, incontinence



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   160/70 

      PULSE   72 

      WEIGHT   196 lb



Physical Exam

      Chest

clear to auscultation

      Cor/Cardiac

RRR, unchanged 2/6 SEM at RUSB

      Musc Skel

mild tenderness at medial joint line of L knee

      HEENT

L TM clear with good light reflex; L ear canal without worrisome lesion; L auricle and post-auricular area without palpable tenderness or signs of infection, no postauricular lymphadenopathy



Assessment and Plan

Summary: 50yoF with obesity, knee pain, hypertension



1)  hypertension: tolering Zestril. K and Cr are fine. Will increase Zestril to 40mg QD.  Patient also given a prescription for Hctz 12.5mg QD but told not to start it yet until his next BP check and start only if BP > 140/85.



2)  L knee pain: Celebrex not effective anymore. Patient told to stop and continue Ibuprofen 800mg TID with meals.  Patient will see Dr. Vogel and discuss surgery.  No benefit from PT.



3)  obesity:  taking only Xenical once a day. No significant weight change yet, but recently just started on Xenical.  Will follow.



4)  anemia: iron, vitamin B12, folate levels all normal.  Not still menstruating.  Rechecking Hct with reticulocyte count.



5)  cardiac murmur: TTE in 8/78



6)  L ear pain: etiology unclear.  Will follow expectantly.  



7)  h/o GERD and Barrett's esophagitis: EGD in 8/78



8)  hyperlipidemia: will recheck lipid panel at next visit and decide on statin therapy



Health Maintenance

- Breast exam/mammogram: 3/78 mammogram benign

- Pap smear: patient deferred to next visit

- Colonoscopy: will discuss at next visit



RTC: 1-2 months to f/u EGD and TTE results and recheck BP.  Patient will likely need to start Hctz.





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2078-07-30" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="851" end="856" text="Vogel" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P3" start="2264" end="2266" text="50" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="2678" end="2683" text="Vogel" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="3017" end="3021" text="8/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="3137" end="3141" text="8/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="3281" end="3285" text="3/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>