<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2078-11-23

IVORY, LORI

2097545

11/22/78

PCP:Dr. Helen Updike



EDUCARE-PULLMAN TEAM A INTERN

ADMISSION NOTE



CC/ID: 51 yo F with no known h/o CHF or CAD, but with multiple cardiac risk factors, p/w dyspnea



HPI: Pt has had difficulty with bp ctrl due to poor med compliance (SBP 160-190 in clinic). Had been on Atenolol and Zestril but pt self-D/C'd Zestril several wks ago because she thought the Zestril made her feel nauseated. Since then, has had gradually developing DOE   from baseline of walking over 4-5 flights of stairs without difficulty to dyspnea on only a flight of stairs. She underwent L knee arthroscopy for medial meniscal tear on 11/19/78 without immediate complications. At 3 am that night, though, woke up with severe dyspnea, with some relief upon sitting up. Associated with some wheezing; tried some of husband's nebs   only slight relief. Later over the day, dyspnea worsened to the point that only few steps would make short of breath. Some association with non-radiating substernal chest tightness in evening; no N/V, lightheadness, diaphoresis, or pleuritic CP, F/S/C, or cough. Next day, dyspnea persisted so pt came into ED.



In ED, found to have BP of 230's/120's, satting 70's on RA. CTA PE-protocol showing no PE or DVT but with pulm edema and bibasilar atelectasis vs. PNA (unlikely). Given Lasix 40 mg IV x 1    2.7 L diuresis; started on nitropaste, Captopril, Labetalol    BP down to 140's. Also given ASA and Lopressor x 1 and started on Heparin IV. Given Levoflox x 1 for ? PNA on CXR. Had to be on BiPAP for several hrs   transitioned to 3L NC, satting mid-90's. Transferred to floor for further mgmt.



Has had recent 8/78 ECHO   EF 67% with mild MR, TR, and AI; nl LV size and function without WMA.





ROS:

-Has had mild R subscapular dull pain on night before admission; not associated with her chest tightness or dyspnea; resolved on own on day of admission.

-Pt thinks L leg may be more swollen than her R



PMH

1.	Hypertension

2.	Obesity: followed by Internal Medicine

3.	PUD: H.Pylori positive

4.	s/p L knee meniscal repair

5.	Depression 

6.	Anemia

7.	Hypercholesterolemia



MEDS (AT HOME)

Atenolol 25 mg po qd

Zestril 40 mg po qd (has not been taking)

Prozac 20 mg po qd

Ibuprofen 800 mg po tid PRN pain

Percocet PRN pain post-surgery (has not been taking) 



Allergies

NKDA



Social History 

Quit smoking 10 yrs ago (2 ppd x 4-5 yrs_

5-6 beers/night on wkends; last drink last Sunday; no h/o withdrawal or seizures

Railway Transport Operations Supervisor at BI; lives with husband



     

Family History

-No known FH of CAD

-DM in father



PHYS EXAM

GEN: Comfortable, converses appropriately, A+O x 3 

VS: T 98  HR 75  BP 152/92 (R arm, manual BP)  148/82 (L arm, manual BP)  RR 22  96% on 2L

HEENT: NC/AT; PERRL, EOMI. 

NECK: JVP 10 cm; no tracheal deviation. No carotid bruits.

CHEST: Crackles halfway up.

COR: No sternal heaves. Normal S1 and S2 with no loud P2. RRR, no M/R/G  

ABD: Soft, NT, ND, BS+

Ext: 1+ pedal edema. No asymmetric leg edema or palpable cords. Warm, DP 2+ bilaterally and radial pulses 2+ bilaterally and symmetric

Neuro: Moving all ext's without impairment and in symmetric fashion. No decrease in fine-touch in all ext's.



DATA



Sodium (Stat Lab)        138                         (135-145)        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)     3.4                         (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)      104                         (100-108)        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)           27.1                        (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)           15                          (8-25)           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)    0.7                         (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)       171                H        (70-110)         mg/dl



Creatine Kinase Isoenz   5.2                         (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index     4.2                H        (0.0-3.5)        %

Troponin-T               0.08                        (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase          123                         (40-150)         U/L



Creatine Kinase Isoenz   3.7                         (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index                                 (0.0-3.5)        %

     CPK and/or CKMB too low to calculate Relative Index.

Troponin-T               0.03                        (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase          110                         (40-150)         U/L



Creatine Kinase Isoenz   3.5                         (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml

Troponin-T               0.01                        (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml

Transaminase-SGOT        33                 H        (9-32)           U/L

Creatine Kinase          97                          (40-150)         U/L



WBC                      6.9                         (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                      33.6               L        (36.0-46.0)      %

PLT                      294                         (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                      85                          (80-100)         fl

MCH                      29.4                        (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                     34.4                        (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                      13.3                        (11.5-14.5)      %

Superstat PT             12.7                        (11.1-13.1)      sec

Superstat APTT           21.1               L        (22.1-35.1)      sec

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST     RECEIVED

Diff Method              Auto

Poly                     58                          (40-70)          %

Lymphs                   35                          (22-44)          %

Monos                    5                           (4-11)           %

EOS                      2                           (0-8)            %

Basos                    0                           (0-3)            %



Macrocytes               None

Microcytes               None

D-Dimer (ELISA)          1061               H        (<500)           ng/ml



-EKG (ED): NSR, ? STE in V1-2

-EKG (floor) 9 am: NSR with ? STE in V1-2

-EKG (floor) night: NSR with resolved STE in V1, still present in V2



CXR: pulm edema 



A/P

51 yo F with no known CAD or CHF, p/w acute CHF in setting of severe HTN, c/b troponin leak



1.CARDS:  Suspect that pt had flash pulm edema from HTN due to poor med compliance as well as from  fluid re-mobilization post-surgery. Acute ischemic event possible given some EKG changes as well as mildly elevated troponin, but these findings could be also explained as demand ischemia event.



-Serial EKG's

-Cardiac monitor, telemetry

-Troponin elevation likely due to demand ischemia; subsequent level was lower, indicating resolving. Doubt ACS at this time but will continue to follow enz's

-ASA, Lopressor

-BP ctrl with ACE-I & B-blocker, aiming for SBP goal of 140's-160's for overnight  (BP had been as high as 230's)

-Lipitor; Check fasting lipids & glucose, homocysteine

-Lasix as needed, aiming for TBB goal of neg 1-2 L; Strict I/O's, qd wt's

-ECHO and Adenosine-MIBI (when more stable)

 

2. Leg Edema: Doubt DVT, but given recent surgery and lack of mobility, will check LENI's

-Fragmin for DVT prophylaxis

-F/U LENI's



3. Miscellaneous:

  	Nexium

  	MVI, Folate, Thiamine

  	PT consult

  	Nutrition consult



4. Anemia

-Guaiac all stools; Bid Hct's for now

-Check iron studies, hemolysis labs, peripheral smear, retic count





___________

Xiomar Ortega #40179





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2078-11-23" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="28" end="39" text="IVORY, LORI" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="41" end="48" text="2097545" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="50" end="58" text="11/22/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="68" end="80" text="Helen Updike" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="84" end="99" text="EDUCARE-PULLMAN" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="140" end="142" text="51" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="675" end="683" text="11/19/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="1688" end="1692" text="8/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2478" end="2484" text="Sunday" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P11" start="2517" end="2556" text="Railway Transport Operations Supervisor" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P12" start="2560" end="2562" text="BI" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<AGE id="P13" start="6220" end="6222" text="51" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="7493" end="7506" text="Xiomar Ortega" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P15" start="7508" end="7513" text="40179" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>