<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2093-03-28

CC: f/u visit for chest pain



HPI: Mr. Hooper has not had any further episodes of chest pain.  Negative enzymes and normal EKG on 3/12.  I recommended ETT to f/u on this but he misunderstood and didn't think he needed to have it done.  He reports that Dr. Gill in neurology suggested he might be a candidate for bariatric surgery.  He is going to be seeing Naomi Newberry in nutrition, who is now at the Manamana.





Problems

HTN 

HYPERCHOL 

WEIGHT 

H/O GOUT 

DM 





Medications

ALLOPURINOL 300 MG PO QD

Insulin Nph Human 22 UNITS SC QAM : 17 units qpm

Elavil (AMITRIPTYLINE Hcl) 10MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QHS

ATENOLOL 50 MG PO BID

LISINOPRIL 20MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

METFORMIN 500MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Lantus (INSULIN Glargine) 40 UNITS SC QHS

Pravachol (PRAVASTATIN) 40MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QHS 





Allergies

NONE - NONE 



ROS:

CV: no chest pain, orthopnea, PND, LE edema, palps

GI: no abd pain, nausea, vomiting, d/c, heartburn

Musc: occ. cramping in the left calf, no edema, no color change, no coldness



PE: 

130/100 but recheck with large cuff BP 114/78, P 66 RR 14 refused wgt

BMI 35.1 by last weight in the system

General: obese, NAD

CV:

   JVP 5 cm

   PMI normal 

   no thrills

   Regular rate and rhythm. no m/r/g

Carotids:  no bruits

Aorta: no palp enlargement or bruit

Pedal pulses: 2+ DP and PT pulses bil.

Extr: no clubbing, cyanosis, or edema, no calf tenderness

CHEST: Respir effort normal with no use of accessory  muscles. 

The chest is clear to A and P bilaterally. No rales, wheezes, rhonchi





A/P:

1. Chest pain: resolved.  ETT given his risk factors.  Continue asa and beta blocker.

2. DM: HbA1C good.  Continue Metformin and lantus.    Microalbumin next visit.  

3. Hyperlipidemia: reviewed LDL which is a little high at 106.  Continue increased dose of pravachol, recheck 2-3 months.

4. Obesity: BMI 35 with risk factors. Refer to wgt. mgmt program for evaluation, not necessarily for surgery at this time though that may be an option in the future.

5. HTN: under good control today.  Continue current regimen.

6. f/u visit 3 months and prn



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2093-03-28" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="69" end="75" text="Hooper" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P2" start="160" end="164" text="3/12" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="286" end="290" text="Gill" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="387" end="401" text="Naomi Newberry" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="434" end="442" text="Manamana" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>