<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2152-06-26



 
Team 4 admission note


Admission Date/Time: June 26, 2152 at 7:30PM
Patient Name: Yasseen Jacks
MRN#: 8841350
Attending: Uriel Mays MD
Code status: DNR/DNI per discussion with son
Historian: medical record, patient's son Ursula Jacks


Chief Complaint: agitation


HPI: 
Mr. Jacks is an Indonesian-speaking 85M with a history of dementia, lung nodule, CHF who presents with progressively worsening agitation at home.  As patient is currently very somnolent this history is based on phone interview with Ursula Jacks who is the HCP and is very involved with his father's care.  The patient was diagnosed with dementia by his PCP about 3 years ago and has been relatively stable living at home (on 2nd floor) in Keystone Heights with his wife who has been his primary caretaker; their two sons are very involved as well.  Over the last 6 months they have noticed increasing confusion, agitation, and labile emotions.  They noted he has been confused about location, time (recalls distant past but not recent past), and has occasionally not been able to identify his wife.  He has become emotionally labile and sometimes agitated.  His son notes that he recently had to physically force him to sit down and take his medications.  His wife has had to stay up at night to watch the patient to make sure he did not wander.  They are particularly worried about his ability to take the flight of stairs to their home since it takes him about 15 min to get up and appears unsteady. About 1 wk ago, while his wife was out of their home, he wandered out and locked himself out; when she returned he angrily accused her of locking him out.  Their mother has had increasing difficulty caring for him and has called the 2 sons for help daily for the past week.  They called his PCP about these accelerating changes and he was started on lorazepam 0.5-1mg Q4h prn which brought mild improvement.  Out of concern for his father's and mother's safety they brought him to the ED for evaluation and placement which their PCP has already begun to discuss with them.


They have not noticed fever/chills, nausea/vomiting, diarrhea/constipation (on aggressive regimen), complaints of pain, vision changes.  They have noticed recent urinary incontinence in the last few days.  


In the ED:  VS were T: 98.2    P: 71    BP: 169/84    RR: 18    SaO2: 93% RA.  Exam was notable only for rales bilaterally and mild-moderate agitation. CXR was normal. CBC was at baseline.  UA pending. CT brain could not be performed due to agitation.  They spoke to his PCP who felt this was all due to progression of his dementia.  He was given ativan 2mg IV (total) and haldol 5mg IV (total).  Also got labetalol PO 200mg PO x 1.  




Past Medical History: 


Diabetes mellitus (adult onset): diet-controlled. 

Hyperlipidemia

Thyroid nodule: stable for years, on methimazole

Anemia

Benign essential hypertension

Congestive heart failure

Dementia

Lung Nodule: increase in size of lung nodule when CT repeated in Feb (suspicious for BAC) Son Ursula spoke to Dr. Daniel (per son's report) and they discussed observing and not being aggressive with surgery etc as even though it could be cancer, an invasive operation, considering his multiple other problems, could be much worse for him than simple observation. They have an appt with Dr. Daniel in September.








Fall in 2150 with DISH




Medications: reviewed with patient's son over phone
  1. Acetaminophen (Tylenol )  325-650 MG PO Q4H prn  2. Aspirin Enteric Coated (Enteric Coated Aspirin)  81 MG PO QD  3. Cyanocobalamin  1000 MCG PO QD  4. Docusate Sodium  100 MG PO BID  5. Furosemide  60 MG PO QD  6. Kcl Slow Release Tab (K-Dur)  10 MEQ PO QD  7. Labetalol Hcl  200 MG PO BID  8. Lisinopril  40 MG PO QD  9. Lorazepam  0.5-1 mg PO Q4H 10. Memantine  10 MG PO BID 11. Methimazole  5 MG PO QD 12. Multivitamins  1 TAB PO QD 13. Omeprazole  20 MG PO QD 14. Polyethylene Glycol   17 GM PO QD prn Constipation   15. Sennosides (Senna Tablets)  2 TAB PO BID 16. Simvastatin  80 MG PO QD

Allergies: 
AMOXICILLIN/CLAV.ACID 875/125 - reaction: diarrhea







Family History: 
Father had dementia in early 70s.  
Mother had breast cancer. 



Social History: 
Lives with wife in KH.  Sons are very involved.  can get around -but sits at home and does not do muchit is getting harder and harder for him to be at home - his wife is having a harder time caring for him.







Prior smoker - remote 20y ago. 
No etoh. 




Review of Systems: Otherwise negative x 10 systems. 


Physical Examination
Vital Signs: T 96.5F, HR 70, BP 177/84, RR 16, O2sat 93% on RA
General Appearance: elderly somnolent, but arousable and intermittently gives his name. 

HEENT: NC/AT, PERRLA, OP clear with slightly dry mucous membranes but with mouth open. 
Skin: 
No rashes, no petechia. Large scar  on back which son states is from unknown childhood surgery
Neck: Supple, unable to assess JVD
Lymphatics: No palpable cervical LAN
Chest: CTAB
Heart: RRR, normal S1/S2 tones, no M/G/R
Abdomen: 
soft, nontender, nondistended, normal bowel sounds. 
Extremities: warm, no c/c/e
Neuro: somnolent, arousable, moving all extremities.  


Diagnostic Studies: 
06/26/2152 NA 142,  K 3.3 (L),  CL 101,  CO2 32.4 (H),  BUN 14,  CRE 1.16,  EGFR &gt;60 [1],  GLU 118 (H)06/26/2152 ANION 9
06/26/2152 PHOS 2.2 (L),  MG 1.6,  TBILI 0.4,  DBILI 0.1,  TP 6.9,  ALB 4.0,  GLOB 2.906/26/2152 AMY 66,  LIPS 26
06/26/2152 ALT/SGPT 17,  AST/SGOT 19,  ALKP 99,  TBILI 0.4,  DBILI 0.106/26/2152 NT-BNP 688 [1]06/23/2152 LDLDIR PEND
06/23/2152 B12 1036,  FOLATE &gt;20.0 (H)
06/23/2152 TSH 2.78 [1]06/23/2152 HGBA1C PEND,  MEAN-GLU PEND
06/26/2152 WBC 7.6,  RBC 4.04 (L),  HGB 11.7 (L),  HCT 35.1 (L),  MCV 87,  MCH 29.0,  MCHC 33.3,  PLT 130 (L)06/26/2152 RDW 14.006/26/2152 METHOD Auto,  %NEUT 57,  %LYMPH 36,  %MONO 4,  %EOS 2,  %BASO 106/26/2152 PT 12.9,  PT-INR 1.1
06/26/2152 UA-COLOR Yellow,  UA-APP Clear,  UA-GLUC Negative,  UA-BILI Negative,  UA-KET Negative,  UR-SPGR 1.010 [1],  UA-BLD Negative,  UA-PH 6.506/26/2152 UA-PROT Negative,  UA-UROBI Negative,  UA-NIT Negative,  UA-WBC Negative
06/23/2152 IGG 867,  IGA 306,  IGM 174,  SPEP PEND


Radiology
06/26/2152 16:40 RCH RadiologyStudy Name CTBrW/OCAccession # 56286274Status Scheduled


06/26/2152 15:22 RCH RadiologyStudy Name Chest 2 ViewsAccession # 85765721Status Final


Exam Number:  85765721                        Report Status:  FinalType:  Chest 2 Views     IMPRESSION:      No evidence of pneumonia or pulmonary edema.
 
EKG: rate 70,. sinus with PAC, normal axis, left axis, QTC 488. 




Impression/Plan: 
In summary, Mr. Jacks is an 85yo Indonesian-speaking male with a history of dementia, lung nodule, CHF who presents with progressively worsening agitation at home.  His family are unable to continue caring for him. 


# Dementia / Agitation: differential include progression of his dementia as well as NPH (given mental status change, ? gait abnormality, and new urinary incontinence).  Currently, sedated from haldol and ativan given in the ED. B12, folate are wnl.  Metabolic panel shows some mild abnormalities but unlikely to be cause of mental status changes and there is no evidence of an infectious process (UA and CXR negative, no leukocytosis) currently. 
- CT brain pending 
- haldol 2mg PO BID prn (hold for sedation) 
- consider geriatric-psychiatry consult
- PT consult when more awake
- continue memantine
- holding lorazepam for now



# HTN: replacing labetalol with metoprolol 50mg TID and will titrate.  Continue lisinopril.  May need to give IV medications while sedated if BP continues to rise. Continue ASA. 
# CHF: continue lasix. 
# Hyperlipidemia; continue simvastatin
# Constipation: contiue home regimen: docusate, senna, miralax prn
# GERD: continue omeprazole
# B12 dificiency: continue B12, level is wnl. 

# Lung nodule: Noted to be increasing on f/u CXR.  PCP and family have elected to not pursue further surgical workup. 
# THyroid nodule: continue methimazole, TSH is wnl. 
# Pain: continue tylenol prn

# FEN: low salt, low cholesterol diet. continue MVI, Kcl
# Prophylaxis: GI: continue omeprazole; DVT: fragmin; Bowel: home regimen
# Disposition: pending placement
# Code Status: DNR/DNI per discussion with son


&gt; 70 min spent on pt mgmnt incl H/P, orders, notes with &gt; 50% time talking to patient, RN, and his son (Ursula Jacks) about plan and options.




________________________________
Uriel Mays MD (pgr 23190)
Team 4, Internal Medicine





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2152-06-26" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="77" end="90" text="June 26, 2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="115" end="128" text="Yasseen Jacks" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="135" end="142" text="8841350" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="154" end="164" text="Uriel Mays" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="254" end="266" text="Ursula Jacks" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="308" end="313" text="Jacks" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="320" end="330" text="Indonesian" TYPE="COUNTRY" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="340" end="342" text="85" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="536" end="548" text="Ursula Jacks" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="743" end="759" text="Keystone Heights" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3012" end="3015" text="Feb" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="3041" end="3047" text="Ursula" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="3061" end="3067" text="Daniel" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="3337" end="3343" text="Daniel" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="3347" end="3356" text="September" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="3374" end="3378" text="2150" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P17" start="4163" end="4166" text="70s" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P18" start="4236" end="4238" text="KH" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="5190" end="5200" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="5295" end="5305" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="5314" end="5324" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="5400" end="5410" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="5428" end="5438" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="5498" end="5508" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="5523" end="5533" text="06/23/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="5546" end="5556" text="06/23/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P27" start="5588" end="5598" text="06/23/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P28" start="5611" end="5621" text="06/23/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P29" start="5650" end="5660" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P30" start="5759" end="5769" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P31" start="5778" end="5788" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P32" start="5852" end="5862" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P33" start="5884" end="5894" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P34" start="6031" end="6041" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P35" start="6115" end="6125" text="06/23/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P36" start="6178" end="6188" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P37" start="6195" end="6198" text="RCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<ID id="P38" start="6239" end="6247" text="56286274" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P39" start="6266" end="6276" text="06/26/2152" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P40" start="6283" end="6286" text="RCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<ID id="P41" start="6332" end="6340" text="85765721" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<ID id="P42" start="6369" end="6377" text="85765721" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P43" start="6614" end="6619" text="Jacks" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P44" start="6626" end="6628" text="85" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P45" start="6631" end="6641" text="Indonesian" TYPE="COUNTRY" comment="" />
<NAME id="P46" start="8359" end="8371" text="Ursula Jacks" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P47" start="8434" end="8444" text="Uriel Mays" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P48" start="8453" end="8458" text="23190" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>