<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2149-06-08

**The source of this note is the RCH Emergency Dept. Information System. All updates should originate in EDIS.**

Redbud Community Hospital

Emergency Department Record - Observation Unit



EDIS Note Status:  Signed



Patient: JACKS, YASSEEN             MRN: 8841350        DOB:  8/15/2066     Sex: M

Registration Date/Time: 6/08/2149 2:09:00 AM





ED OBS Note





Admission Note

Time Patient Seen

4:18

Chief Complaint

DELTA MS / HYPERTENSION

HPI

82 y.o M w hx HTN, hyperthyroidism, baseline mild dementia p/w change in mental status.  Per pt. son he was unable  to recognize  his wife and wanted to get out of the house, he was agitated but non combative, episode lasted for about 1 hr.  Denies any f/c, no HA, No CP/palpitations, no speech difficulty, no neuromotor deficit, no numbness/ tingling of extremities.

PFSHx/ROS

Past Medical History: See HPI--. Family History non-contributory. Social History: non smoker quit 10 y.o

Allergy

NKA



ROS

Constitutional

(-)Major weight gain. (-)Fatigue. (-)Fever. (-)Chills.

Head/Eyes

(-)Headache. (-)Vision changes.

ENT/Neck

No signficiant findings.

Chest/Respiratory

(-)Shortness of breath. (-)Wheezing. (-)Dyspnea on exertion. (-)Cough.

Cardiovascular

(-)Leg swelling.

GI/Abdominal

(-)Vomiting. (-)Diarrhea.

GU/Flank/CVA/Pelvic

No signficiant findings.

Musculoskeletal/Extr/Back

No signficiant findings.

Skin

No signficiant findings.

Neuro

(-)Paresthesias. (-)Weakness.

Psych

Dementia that began ~ 1 year ago.

Heme/Lymph/Imm

No signficiant findings.

Endo

Hyperthyroidism.



ROS and PFSHx as noted above and in the ED record for this encounter.

All other systems otherwise negative.



PE

Constitutional

Patient is awake. Patient is alert. Patient is oriented x3. Patient is not lethargic.

Head/Eyes

Normal cephalic atramatic. Pupils are equal and reactive to light. Extraocular muscles are intact. Sclera are anicteric.

ENT

Airway Intact. Mucus membranes are moist. Tongue is midline.

Neck

Neck is supple. Full range of motion is present. Neck is non tender.  Carotid bruits are absent.

Chest/Respiratory

The lungs are clear to auscultation bilaterally. Rales are not present.

Cardiovascular

Normal heart sounds are present. Heart is regular rate and rhythm. No murmur is present.

GI/Abdomen

Abdomen is nontender and nondistended. Abdomen is soft. Bowel sounds are present.

Genitourinary

Costovertebral angle tenderness is present.

Musculoskeletal

Patient has normal range of motion. Patient has normal muscle bulk and tone. There is no tremor. There is no muscle rigidity.

Skin

Skin is intact. There is no rash. There are no lesions.

Neurologic

No focal deficit. Patient is alert and oriented x 3. Cranial nerve testing is intact. Motor strength testing is intact.

Psychiatric

Patient is non delusional. Patient is not anxious.

Heme/Lymph/Immun/Endocrine

Patient does not have lymphadenopathy.



Testing Results

EKG

EKG-->SB 50's

X-ray Interpretation

Head CT: neg.

CXR neg

Medical Decision Making/Plan

82 y.o M w hx in HPI p/w mental status change and elevated  BP.  Plan:

Monitor BP

Tele monitoring

Monitor mental status.



This note has been electronically signed by YVONNE WELCH, NP 6/08/2149 6:58:35 AM







Clinical staff documenting in the ED note include:



Attending/Nurse Practitioners(s)



YVONNE WELCH, NP

Attending Note

Attending MD Notes

I have examined the patient and discussed with the Nurse Practitioner the patient's care and agree with the plan.  Pt had episode of delerious speaking (full sentences, non-focal otherwise and was able to take a walk to calm down, has had similar before) and this self-resolved.  In ED, charming and without sx.  However, noted BP elevated.  Exam normal.  Plan:  obs o/n, reduce BP, and have patient f/u Monday for recheck to ensure it is not getting up again.



This note has been electronically signed by Xavier Uber, MD 6/08/2149 10:11:32 AM







Clinical staff documenting in the ED note include:



Attending/Nurse Practitioners(s)



Xavier Uber, MD



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2149-06-08" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="61" end="64" text="RCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P2" start="142" end="167" text="Redbud Community Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="257" end="271" text="JACKS, YASSEEN" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P4" start="289" end="296" text="8841350" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="310" end="319" text="8/15/2066" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="356" end="365" text="6/08/2149" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="487" end="489" text="82" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="3056" end="3058" text="82" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="3227" end="3239" text="YVONNE WELCH" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="3244" end="3253" text="6/08/2149" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="3362" end="3374" text="YVONNE WELCH" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="3820" end="3826" text="Monday" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="3924" end="3935" text="Xavier Uber" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="3940" end="3949" text="6/08/2149" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="4059" end="4070" text="Xavier Uber" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>