<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2079-01-24

Mr. Sparks is a 74 yr. M who was seen by me as a new patient in Nov. 10 and again in Dec. 10. He RTC.



HPI: This visit was supposed to be a preoperative visit prior to his scheduled Feb. 02 right inguinal hernia repair with Dr. Yamaguchi. However, when I saw him in Dec he had inadequate BP control despite Dr. Arias doubling his Lisinopril. I DCed Atenolol and switched him to Labetalol 100 mg BID. Despite some confusion I believe he has done this. He had also been switched from Crestor to Lipitor due to safety concerns. Labs done pre-operatively are notable for:

Creatinine     3.4

LDL          184

nct.           35%



Problems

Adenomatous polyp : May 2078

Gastritis : H. pylori positive

Chronic renal dysfunction 

Diabetes mellitus type 2 

Hypertension 

Hyperlipidemia 

Anemia 

hyperparathyroidism 

Transient ischemic attack 



Medications

Amlodipine 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Glipizide 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 

Pioglitazone 15 MG (15MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Clopidogrel 75 MG (75MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Furosemide 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 

Ferrous GLUCONATE 300 MG PO BID 

Lisinopril 80 MG (40MG TABLET ) PO QD , by Dr. Arias.

Atorvastatin 40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Labetalol HCL 100 MG (100MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 



Allergies

Aspirin - ulcer, : Allergy entered as ASA 

Habits: no cigarettes, drugs or alcohol;



ROS: denies weight change, fever, chills, fatigue, blurry vision, chest pains, palpitations, dyspnea, cough, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, change in bowel/bladder habits, joint pain, dizziness, exanthem, edema. 



PE notable for:

Well nourished well appearing M;

Vital Signs

BP 184/90, P 72, Wt 236 lb

O2 SAT 99 %

HEENT: sclera clear white OU, EOMI, ear canals and TMs wnl AU; oropharynx without lesions.

LN: No palpable neck or SC LN;

Cardiac: RRR, rate 72, no extra sounds

Resp.: good air movement, no accessory muscle use, no adventitious sounds



Plan:

1. Hypertension: continues to be inadequate in a diabetic.We have limited options; increasing Lisinopril did not add much. Switch to Labetalol did not help, but he is also not beta-blocked (HR 72) so I am increasing Labetalol to 200 mg BID.

2. Diabetes: control has been good.

3. Renal insufficiency

4. Hyperlipidemia: we may need to increase Lipitor and/or add Zetia.

5. Right inguinal hernia: RTC one week for hopefully better pre-op. BP





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2079-01-24" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="32" end="38" text="Sparks" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P2" start="44" end="46" text="74" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="92" end="99" text="Nov. 10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="113" end="120" text="Dec. 10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="212" end="219" text="Feb. 02" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="258" end="267" text="Yamaguchi" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="296" end="299" text="Dec" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="341" end="346" text="Arias" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="689" end="697" text="May 2078" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="1207" end="1212" text="Arias" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>