<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2097-12-04

SECTIONS OF THIS NOTE WERE CREATED WITH A 'COPY AND PASTE' ACTION.  THESE SECTIONS MAY NOT HAVE COPIED COMPLETELY.  PLEASE USE CAUTION WHEN RENDERING CLINICAL JUDGMENT BASED ON THE INFORMATION IN THIS NOTE.










Internal Medicine
Medical Student Admission Note


PATIENT: Rojas, Alaina
MRN: 7269058
ADMIT DATE: 12/04/2097
PCP: Dr. Ruba Neil, Dr. William Aquino (onc)
CONTACT: Claire Ortega (daughter, 660-750-9168)
CODE STATUS: Full
SOURCE: Previous notes


CHIEF COMPLAINT: Mechanical Fall


HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:
(Patient was taken to surgery immediately upon arriving to floor)
Per PCP: Ms. Rojas is a 87-year-old woman with a PMH of metastatic pancreatic cancer recently diagnosed s/p 1 dose of gemcitabine (on 11/14), DM, HTN, and CRI who presents s/p mechanical fall at home resulting in a right hip fracture. Patient was in USOH until the day of admission when she got up out of a chair to reach for her glasses, and then went to sit back down and missed the chair and fell to the ground. Per the PCP, the patient had no presyncopal symptoms and did not lose consciousness.


ED COURSE:
T 97.8 P 56   BP: 156/59  RR: 20  97% RA
Foreshortened RLExt
Needs basal insulin 


PMH/PSH:
(1)     Pancreatic cancer
a.        10/30/2097, patient presented to PCP with dark urine and progressively increasing FBSGs (h/o DM). She was admitted for evaluation of hyperglycemia and was noted to be jaundiced with elevated LFTs. RUQ U/S showed CBD dilatation with hypoechoic mass near head of pancreas measuring 4.1x5x5.5cm
b.       11/03/2097, ERCP showed 3cm distal bile duct stricture that was stented. LFTs trended down s/p biliary stenting. Biopsy obtained under EUS guidance showed pancreatic adenocarcinoma. CT scan revealed pulmonary nodules, likely metastatic disease
c.        11/14/2097, treated with 1st dose of 25% dose gemcitabine (given CKD), course s/p chemotx c/b fatigue, rash, worsening renal function and anemia. This resolved with fluids, blood tx, and discontinuation of most of her BP medications. She was scheduled for her second dose of gemcitabine on 12/05
(2)     Diabetes mellitus
a.        Last HgbA1c = 7.2 (10/08/2097)
b.       Was maintained on Glucophage, but this was discontinued 2/2 worsening renal function
c.        Recently placed on insulin with BS&#8217;s to be kept around 200 given CA dx

HTN (TTE on 11/11 showed EF=69%, no LVH)
Chronic renal failure &#8211; baseline creatinine 1.8-2.2
h/o BCC
h/o TIA


MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION:
Vitamin d 1000 units po daily
Novolin R innolet 2-6 units sc bid prn per sliding scale
Novolin N innolet 22 units sc qam
ferrous sulfate 325mg po daily
metoprolol 25mg po bid 2 tabs
furosemide 10mg po daily
Ecotrin 325 mg po daily
Home physical therapy for strengthening and ROM generally.  Additionally L shoulder ROM and strengthening for frozen shoulder.


ALLERGIES:
NKDA


SOCIAL HISTORY:
Continues to get out to the American Senior Center, except on one day. Living independently with supportive family. Three daughters and 2 sons are very involved with her.


FAMILY HISTORY:
She was born in Arroyo Grande.  She had five children; four of them are alive, all living in the area.  Husband died in 2080. Mother had Parkinson's disease.  Sister had breast cancer at the age of 72.


PHYSICAL EXAM: (Exam was deferred because patient was taken immediately to OR)
VITALS (on arrival to floor):
                TEMP: 100.3
                HR: 62
                BP: 171/59
                RR: 18
                O2SAT: 98% on RA 




LABORATORY DATA:


Chemistries
              12/04/97      12/01/97  
              00:08         20:12     


NA            130(L)        138                                                 
K             4.3           4.8                                                 
CL            98(L)         104                                                 
CO2           19.1(L)       22.8(L)                                             
BUN           60(H)         58(H)                                               
CRE           2.1(H)        2.2(H)                                              
GLU           381(H)        362(H)                                              


General Chemistries
Calcium                          8.6                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl
Phosphorus                       3.3                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl
Magnesium                        1.6                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L


Liver Function Tests
Total Protein                    7.1                       (6.0-8.3)      g/dl
Albumin                          3.6                       (3.3-5.0)      g/dl
Globulin                         3.5                       (2.6-4.1)      g/dl
Total Bilirubin                  0.8                       (0.0-1.0)      mg/dl
Alkaline Phosphatase             84                        (30-100)       U/L
Transaminase-SGPT                15                        (7-30)         U/L
Transaminase-SGOT                19                        (9-32)         U/L


CBC:
WBC                              10.8                      (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm
HCT                              27.3             L        (36.0-46.0)    %
HGB                              9.5              L        (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl
RBC                              3.07             L        (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm
PLT                              351              H        (150-350)      th/cumm
MCV                              89                        (80-100)       fl
MCH                              31.0                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc
MCHC                             34.8                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl
RDW                              16.0             H        (11.5-14.5)    %
DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED
Diff Method                      Auto
Poly                             82               H        (40-70)        %
Lymphs                           10               L        (22-44)        %
Monos                            6                         (4-11)         %
EOS                              1                         (0-8)          %
Basos                            1                         (0-3)          %
Absolute Neuts                   8.92             H        (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm
Absolute Lymphs                  1.00                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm
Absolute Monos                   0.63             H        (0.2-0.4)      th/cmm
Absolute EOS                     0.14                      (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm
Absolute Basos                   0.07                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm
Aniso                            1+               H        (None)
Hypo                             None                      (None)
Macrocytes                       None                      (None)
Microcytes                       None                      (None)


Coagulation Studies
Superstat PT                     12.9                      (10.3-13.2)    sec
Superstat PT-INR                 1.1
Superstat APTT                   20.6             L        (22.1-34.0)    sec


STUDIES:
Plain Films:
     FINDINGS:
     Right hip: There is a transverse transcervical fracture through
     the sphenoid.  There is lateral superior displacement of the
     distal segment.  There is no evidence of dislocation.
     
     Pelvis: There is diffuse osteopenia involving the pelvis.  Again
     noted is a transcervical fracture to the right femur.  There is
     superior lateral displacement of the distal fracture segment.  The
     sacrum is not well seen secondary to overlying bowel gas.  Minimal
     degenerative changes of the lumbar spine are noted.
     
     Shoulder: There is no evidence of left shoulder dislocation or
     acute fracture.  The visualized lung fields and ribs are intact.
     There is minimal degenerative change involving the left a.c.
     joint.
     
     Chest: Comparison to 10/31/97.  Multiple pulmonary nodules are
     noted.  There is no evidence of focal consolidation or pulmonary
     edema.  No large pleural effusion or appreciable pneumothorax is
     identified.  The cardiomediastinal silhouette is stable.
     Degenerative changes of the thoracic spine are noted.
     
     IMPRESSION:
     Right transcervical femoral fracture.  No evidence of dislocation.
     
     No evidence of shoulder dislocation.
     
     Multiple pulmonary nodules consistent with metastatic disease.
     
     FINDINGS:
     Previously noted minimally displaced right hip fracture.
     Osteoarthrosis of the knee. Soft tissues swelling along the medial
     aspect of the knee is noted.  There are vascular calcifications.
     Generalized osteopenia.
     
     IMPRESSION:
     Right hip fracture as previously described.  Osteoarthrosis of the
     knee. 
       
EKG: Sinus bradycardia.


ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN:


87yo F with h/o metastatic pancreatic CA s/p 1 dose of gemcitabine and biliary stenting, CKD, DM, and HTN who p/w right hip fracture s/p mechanical fall at home. The plan of care by issue is as follows:


(1)     Right hip fracture: Patient will require post-operative anti-coagulation. Patient is undergoing high-risk procedure and is also at increased risk for VTE given cancer dx. According to guidelines from ACCP:


#UFH 5000 Units SC TID [or LMWH &gt;3400 Units SC QD (her CrCl &lt;30, therefore renally dosed = LMWH 30mg SC QD)] to be started either in PACU or on the floor.
#Compression stockings
#Pneumo-boots
#Plan to continue VTE prophylaxis for 4-6 weeks post-op
#Encourage ambulation as soon as tolerated (per ortho, pt might be ambulatory as soon as tomorrow)


(2)     DM
Patient recently started on insulin at home. Will continue half dose of home insulin with IVF with glucose.
#RISS, until tolerating POs, then restart normal insulin.


(3)     Dispo
Plan to D/C when clinically stable post-op. Per PCP, patient would like to return directly home after surgery without rehab (home rehab). Family notes that patient currently lives at daughter&#8217;s home where there are many steps which would make home rehab difficult.


#Consider rehab placement, follow-up attending recs, discuss with family in AM












_______________________________________
Brandon Hale
EFS III, Internal Medicine
Pager #28913


ADDENDUM:
Case and plan discussed and incorporated into this excellent EFSIII Note.




_______________________________
Fred Allen, M.D.
Medicine PGY1
Pager #80817



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2097-12-04" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="305" end="318" text="Rojas, Alaina" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="324" end="331" text="7269058" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="344" end="354" text="12/04/2097" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="364" end="373" text="Ruba Neil" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="379" end="393" text="William Aquino" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="409" end="422" text="Claire Ortega" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P8" start="434" end="446" text="660-750-9168" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="633" end="638" text="Rojas" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P10" start="644" end="646" text="87" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="754" end="759" text="11/14" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="1262" end="1272" text="10/30/2097" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="1563" end="1573" text="11/03/2097" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="1817" end="1827" text="11/14/2097" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="2107" end="2112" text="12/05" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="2168" end="2178" text="10/08/2097" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="2374" end="2379" text="11/11" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P18" start="2927" end="2949" text="American Senior Center" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P19" start="3104" end="3117" text="Arroyo Grande" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="3208" end="3212" text="2080" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P21" start="3286" end="3288" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="3585" end="3593" text="12/04/97" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="3599" end="3607" text="12/01/97" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="7952" end="7960" text="10/31/97" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P25" start="8892" end="8894" text="87" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P26" start="10265" end="10277" text="Brandon Hale" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P27" start="10278" end="10281" text="EFS" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P29" start="10312" end="10317" text="28913" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P30" start="10391" end="10394" text="EFS" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P31" start="10440" end="10450" text="Fred Allen" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P32" start="10478" end="10483" text="80817" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>