<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2132-11-10


November 10, 2132 




Osiel M. Colon, M.D.
McCaw Family Medicine
84 Grace Drive, Suite 046
Delano, TX 28221


RE:                  Oliver Jain
LEPROSARIUM:              962-85-18


Dear Dr. Colon:


I am writing to inform you that I am seeing Mr. Oliver Jain in followup.  Mr. Jain was admitted to my service in transfer for right lower extremity ischemia and gangrene following atheroembolization from a popliteal aneurysm, as you know.  He was admitted in early September and stayed until early October.  During his hospital stay here his wounds were addressed.  He underwent angiograms to evaluate his arterial anatomy and he underwent reconstruction of the right wherein covered stent graft was used to cover disease in his proximal femoral artery and then he underwent an above knee to below knee popliteal artery bypass using PTFE with ligation of the aneurysm.  He also subsequently underwent angioplasty of his posterior tibial artery.  Given his atheroembolic phenomenon he had very limited vasculature remaining in the foot and I was concerned that the forefoot gangrene would progress and he would wind up losing the right foot.  In the interim since his discharge he appears to be doing quite well.  The gangrene of the right foot has remained stable with clearcut demarcation of the right first, second and third toes.  He also has some heel ulceration that I am hoping to nurse through.  He denies any rest pain or pain in the foot.  He has no evidence of fevers, chills, rigors or shakes in the interim.  He has since been discharged to home and has been walking with a walking shoe.  His left lower extremity aneurysm is yet to be treated and he has not developed any symptoms with regards to the left lower extremity.  He has been taking his Coumadin regularly and has had therapeutic INRs as he reports.  


On exam today he is doing quite well.  He is in good spirits and appears much better than in the hospital.  His head and neck exams were unremarkable.  His lungs were clear.  Heart was regular.  His proximal groin and leg incisions have healed up nicely, however there is some dry eschar on the midportion of the wound.  With regards to the toes he has clearcut demarcation and heel ulceration.  There is no evidence of cellulitis, induration or infection of the right lower extremity.  He continues to have a stable looking foot on the left.  Given his extensive peripheral vascular disease I performed PVRs in the office today, which revealed that he has pulsatile PVRs at the right calf and ankle.  He also has slight pulsatile PVRs at the right transmetatarsal level.  This bodes well with regards to his revascularization as well as his potential to either heal or remain stable with regards to the necrosis on the right foot.  His left calf, ankle and transmetatarsal PVRs were similar.  


In summary, this is an unfortunate gentleman who developed atheroembolic phenomena resulting in digital ischemia as well as heel ischemia with the potential for limb loss in the near future of the right lower extremity.  He does have an untreated aneurysm on the left with potential for atheroembolization of the left lower extremity.  Given this concern, I will proceed next with a left lower extremity revascularization to exclude the popliteal aneurysm so that he does not develop limb-threatening gangrene of the left.  With regards to the right I will try to initiate some hyperbaric oxygen therapy and will probably re-evaluate his distal circulation with an angiogram at the time of his next admission or some time thereafter.  I am hoping to facilitate healing of the heel wound with the final outcome of a transmetatarsal amputation of the right lower extremity but will see how it goes.  My thanks again for this referral.  I apologize for not sending you correspondence earlier.  With this correspondence I will send you his operative diagram as well as his most recent discharge summary.


Sincerely,




Quincy T. Uselton, M.D.


Enclosure:  Operative Note, Operative Drawing, Discharge Summary 


QU/xayasane                     36-33387396.doc



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2132-11-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="29" end="46" text="November 10, 2132" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="52" end="66" text="Osiel M. Colon" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="73" end="94" text="McCaw Family Medicine" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="95" end="109" text="84 Grace Drive" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="121" end="127" text="Delano" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="129" end="131" text="TX" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="132" end="137" text="28221" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="161" end="172" text="Oliver Jain" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="173" end="184" text="LEPROSARIUM" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<ID id="P11" start="199" end="208" text="962-85-18" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="220" end="225" text="Colon" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="277" end="288" text="Oliver Jain" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="307" end="311" text="Jain" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="494" end="503" text="September" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="527" end="534" text="October" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="3970" end="3987" text="Quincy T. Uselton" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="4064" end="4066" text="QU" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="4067" end="4075" text="xayasane" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P20" start="4096" end="4107" text="36-33387396" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>