<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2102-05-19





Pulmonary Consult Note


Name:    Dalila Haynes
MR#:     78361343
Date of admit:      5/18/02
Date of consult:   5/19/02 
 


Reason for consult: Sarcoidosis


History of Present Illness:  Mrs Haynes is a very pleasant 67 yo female pmh significant for a diagnosis of sarcoidosis from a nodule biopsies on her left eye back in October.  She subsequently underwent a mediastinoscopy in April of this year for bulky adenopathy which the pathology was also consistent with sarcoidosis.  She present for evaluation of abdominal pain that has been present for months but became unbearable prompting a visit to the emergency room.  Mrs. Haynes reports that over the past few months she has been experiencing weight loss, early satiety, night sweats and fatigue.  He abdominal pain is described as a sharp to achy pain that started in her right side, progressed to her epigastric and suprapubic are and then her left side.  Currently it is diffuse associated with nausea and vomiting.  She denies bowel problems has had some difficulty with urination and some frequency since admission but this is generally not a problem.  ROS is also pertinet for HA which are chronic and palpations both of which are hard to describe.
 
ROS: In detail otherwise unremarkable.


Past Medical History:  

HTN, Hyperlipidemia (h/o normal stress test in past), palpitations, GERD, thyroid nodules, lichen sclerosis, bilateral adrenal adenomas, diabetes mellitus type II, sarcoidosis


Past Surgical History:  
 s/p uterine fibroid resection 2096, s/p left facial biopsy 10/01




 

Medications (current):  
 

Ciprofloxacin 500 mg q 12 hr
Lovenox 40 mg SC day
Lisinopril 40 mg Po day
Simvastatin 40 mg QHS
Nifedipine 60 mg Po day
Omeprazole 40 mg Po day
NPH/Insulin Aspart
Mag Sulfate
CA Carbonate
Colace




Allergies:              sulfa causes GI intolerance




Family History:   Sister x 2 w/MI, Sister w/DM type II, Niece w/DM type II, Brother w/prostate CA, Brother w/possible leukemia, Mother w CVA. No Hx of sarcoid or TB in the family.




Social History:  The patient is a lifelong nonsmoker with a 20 year exposure to secondhand smoke.  The patient has no known asbestos exposure.  The patient is widowed with four children and is retired from her former job at Lowe's.  She was born in Georgia moved to Chelsea in the 50's and the only place she has visited was Augusta.  No TB exposures or risk factors.  States she had been tested for TB in the past years ago.  No beryllium exposure.




Physical Examination:
Vital Signs:    97.6  P 93  BP 110/60  RR 18  Sat 99%RA
General Appearance:NAD
HEENT:  PERRL, EOMI, visual fields grossly intact
Skin:  warm and dry
Neck: Supple
Lungs:  CTA bilaterally
Heart:  RRR s1s2 no m/r/g
Abdomen:  +BS, soft, diffuse tenderness no r/g
Musculoskeletal:  wnl
Extremities:  No c/c/e
Neuro:  A+O x 3 no gross motor or sensory deficits.


Diagnostic Testing:  
 
WBC 4.5 Hg 11 Hct 33 Plt 331  P 57  L 31  M 9.2  Na 138  K 4.1  Cl 103  Co2 27  BUN 11 Cr 0.73  Glu 243  Ca 9.0  Mg 1.2  ESR 20  D-Dimer 529
 
Ace Pending
 
Urine Cx 5/18 negative from 10am mixed flora 10K 3 colonies
 
PFTs 3/02- FVC 2.6 85%  FEV1 1.93  82% Ratio 74
 
TTE 2/02-The left ventricle is small and/or underfilled. There isborderline concentric left ventricular hypertrophy. Overall left ventricularfunction is normal. The estimated ejection fraction is 60%. There are noregional wall motion abnormalities.  Otherwise unremarkable.
 
CT abdomen Pelvis-  5/18/02   
 
IMPRESSION:           1. Urothelial thickening involving renal pelvises, ureters, and     bladder. Findings consistent with infection versus less likely     inflammation.     2. Bladder calculus.     3. Abdominal lymphadenopathy, increased since prior study, may be     consistent with progression of known sarcoid, versus malignancy.     4. Adrenal nodules, unchanged.
 
CT Chest 3/16
 
IMPRESSION:     1. Mediastinal, bilateral hilar, supraclavicular,     retroperitoneal, and gastrohepatic adenopathy likely represents     lymphoma rather than sarcoidosis given the patient age and     abdominal involvement.     2. Bilateral adrenal nodules.
 
Path: 04/10/2102 PATHOLOGIC DIAGNOSIS:A. SPECIMEN DESIGNATED "4R LYMPH NODES, BIOPSY" (including FSA):     Lymph node with non-necrotizing granulomata (see NOTE).B. SPECIMEN DESIGNATED "4R LYMPH NODES, BIOPSY":     Lymph node with non-necrotizing granulomata (see NOTE).


Impression:  Mrs. Haynes is a pleasant 67 yo female with biopsy demonstrating non-caesating granululoma in a left eye nodule and mediastinal lymph nodes.  Cx data was not obtained.  However, hx is not suggestive of past tuberculosis risk factors.  Clinical picture very suggestive of systemic sarcoidosis.  At this time she does not have an absolute indication for sarcoid treatment but she may benefit symptomatically from low dose steroids.  At this time she is reluctant to start steroids without discussing it with her family and Dr. Villalpando.


Recommendations:  
 
-Would consider Cardiac MRI given her hx of palpitations as cardiac sarcoid is an absolute indication for treatment.
-Would recommend checking PPD
-Would recommend starting prednisone 30mg po qday.  Will discuss this further with patient and family tomorrow.  There is no rush for treatment at this time and we could waite until Dr. Villalpando is available to speak with Mrs. Haynes.
-Would also recommend Bactrim prophylaxis while she is on greater than 15 mg Po prednisone.  1 DS M/W/F.
-Will follow.




Thank you for this interesting consult. Please call with questions.
 
Patient seen examine and case discussed with Dr. Layton.
 
__________________________________
Hayden Lawrence, MD
Pulmonary Fellow
Department of Pulmonary care
Beeper #51549




 



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2102-05-19" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="66" end="79" text="Dalila Haynes" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="89" end="97" text="78361343" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="118" end="125" text="5/18/02" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="145" end="152" text="5/19/02" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="225" end="231" text="Haynes" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="251" end="253" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="358" end="365" text="October" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="416" end="421" text="April" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="662" end="668" text="Haynes" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1547" end="1551" text="2096" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1576" end="1581" text="10/01" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P12" start="2280" end="2286" text="Lowe's" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P13" start="2305" end="2312" text="Georgia" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P14" start="2322" end="2329" text="Chelsea" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="2337" end="2341" text="50's" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P16" start="2381" end="2388" text="Augusta" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="3080" end="3084" text="5/18" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="3138" end="3142" text="3/02" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="3187" end="3191" text="2/02" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="3479" end="3486" text="5/18/02" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="3873" end="3877" text="3/16" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="4146" end="4156" text="04/10/2102" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P23" start="4431" end="4437" text="Haynes" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P24" start="4452" end="4454" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P25" start="4951" end="4962" text="Villalpando" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P26" start="5320" end="5331" text="Villalpando" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P27" start="5364" end="5370" text="Haynes" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P28" start="5470" end="5471" text="M" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P29" start="5472" end="5473" text="W" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P30" start="5474" end="5475" text="F" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P31" start="5614" end="5620" text="Layton" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P32" start="5659" end="5674" text="Hayden Lawrence" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P34" start="5733" end="5738" text="51549" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>