<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2080-03-28







Deaconess Hospital
9576 Foundation Street
Cardiology, Suite 5381              RAY, PATRICIA
Richgrove, MD  65169                    90495403
(167) 785-7949                     03/28/2080




PRIMARY CARE PHYSICIAN:  Opal Lanier, MD


HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a complicated 72-year-old woman who has a history significant for porcine aortic valve replacement in January of 2080 at Madison Medical Center for aortic stenosis.  She also has a history of interstitial lung disease, maintained on prednisone slow taper.  She also has hypertension and hyperlipidemia.  She had been residing at a nursing home and complained of chest pain, jaw pain and bilateral shoulder pain for approximately 1 week.  Eventually, the patient was transferred to Wheeling Clinic.  Here in the Emergency Department, the patient was found to be hypotensive with a systolic blood pressure in the 70s, which improved to the 90s with volume and blood resuscitation.  She also found to be tachycardic and have a hematocrit of 25%.  The patient was also found to be guaiac positive on stool occult blood.  Her troponin was mildly elevated.  The patient was transfused with several units of packed red blood cells and her chest discomfort has improved.  She also underwent echocardiography on 03/26/80, which was a fair quality study with a mildly dilated left ventricle, mild LVH, septal flattening consistent with RV pressure overload and an estimated ejection fraction of 35% to 40%.  Diastolic dysfunction was also noted.  There was dilatation of both atria and the right ventricle with mildly reduced RV systolic function.  The aortic valve could not be well visualized.  There was reduced cusp excursion with severe aortic stenosis.  There was mild tricuspid regurgitation and estimated PASP of 60 to 65 mmHg plus RA pressure.  There was mild-to-moderate mitral regurgitation with a posteriorly directed jet.  The aortic valve peak gradient was 115.6 mmHg and mean gradient was 77.05 mmHg.  Valve area was not calculated.


The patient was transferred to Madison Medical Center for treatment of her symptoms.  She notes that her chest pain has improved.  She notes that she had worsening of her baseline dyspnea on exertion and shortness of breath at rest starting in September that has been gradually progressing.  She denies trouble breathing at night.  She also notes peripheral edema that seems worse now than it did back in September.  She denies any fevers, chills or cough.


PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for porcine aortic valve replacement in 2078, BOOP, hypertension, hyperlipidemia and congestive heart failure.


MEDICATIONS:  Her discharge medications from Wheeling Clinic were prednisone 25 mg p.o. once daily, Humalog insulin sliding scale, metoprolol 6.25 mg p.o. b.i.d., lisinopril 10 mg p.o. once daily, Lasix 40 mg p.o. once daily, metolazone 5 mg p.o. once daily, simvastatin 20 mg p.o. once daily, omeprazole 20 mg p.o. once daily, Ativan 0.5 mg p.o. q.8 h. p.r.n., aspirin 81 mg p.o. once daily, vitamin D 400 units once daily, oxybutynin 5 mg p.o. once daily, Milk of magnesium p.r.n. and MiraLax p.r.n.


ALLERGIES:  Penicillin and sulfa.


SOCIAL HISTORY:  The patient lives in a nursing home.  She typically ambulates with a walker, though she has become dyspneic even ambulating a few feet.  She quit smoking 40 years ago.  There is no alcohol use.  She has 6 children, all in good health, one of whom is accompanying her and is studying to be a lawyer.


PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient appears comfortable and is sitting upright in a chair.  Her heart rate is 82 to 96 and regular, blood pressure 150/98, repeat is 126/86, repeat is 110/72, respiratory rate is 20, oxygen saturation 98% on 2 L nasal cannula and temperature 97.6.  JVP is difficult to assess given body habitus.  Lungs exhibit bibasilar crackles one-third of the way up, worse on the left than the right.  Air movement is fair.  There are no carotid bruits.  Carotid upstrokes are markedly diminished and mildly delayed.  On heart exam, PMI could not be felt.  There is a regular rate and rhythm with a 3/6 crescendo-decrescendo early to mid systolic peaking murmur heard best at the right upper sternal border radiating across the precordium.  There are no rubs or gallops.  Extremities show no clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  There is moderate pedal edema bilaterally going up to the ankles.


EKG shows sinus rhythm at a rate of 87 beats per minute, left atrial enlargement, LVH by voltage with secondary ST and T-wave changes, but what appeared to be primary T-wave inversions in leads V3 to V6 consistent with ischemia and these changes are more dramatic than they were back on 03/03/78 EKG.


Lab testing reveals normal sodium, potassium, chloride, carbon dioxide, BUN, creatinine and glucose.  Magnesium and calcium were normal.  Albumin is low at 2.6.  Liver function tests are normal.  Creatinine kinase is 15, troponin is 0.7 and B-natriuretic peptide is 2510.  Thyroid studies are pending.  Hemoglobin A1c is 5.7.  CBC shows mild anemia with hematocrit of 35.8% with normal hemoglobin of 12.2, elevated white count at 13.32 and platelet count of 305,000.  Coagulation studies are normal.


IMPRESSION:  A 72-year-old woman with congestive heart failure, recent echocardiogram suggesting severe aortic stenosis and her bioprosthetic aortic valve replacement for AS back in 2080 and GI bleed with significant anemia, now transfused and improved.  The patient also has chronic interstitial lung disease for which she is on chronic steroid therapy.


I think the main issue is to determine whether there is significant aortic stenosis that may require re-intervention.  On exam, most features are not consistent with severe aortic stenosis, so we will repeat the echocardiogram here and determine if there is severe aortic stenosis in the bioprosthetic valve, and if so, what is the pathology.  Depending on this, we will determine whether the patient needs surgical reoperation.  If so, she will need to have her GI tract looked that first for the source of GI bleeding in order to treat this in preparation for repeat cardiac surgery.


In addition, the patient will be treated for congestive heart failure with increased diuretics, following her inputs and outputs, daily weights, basal metabolic panel, exam and chest x-ray.  Her beta-blocker will be increased due to her recent myocardial event, keeping an eye on her CHF in order to not worsen it.  Beta-blocker will be gradually increased given the lung disease and congestive heart failure. Endocarditis will be ruled out with serial blood cultures.




______________________________
Ray Downing, MD










eScription document:1-2235241 CSSten Tel






DD: 03/28/80
DT: 03/28/80
DV: 03/28/80



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2080-03-28" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="34" end="52" text="Deaconess Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P2" start="53" end="75" text="9576 Foundation Street" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="112" end="125" text="RAY, PATRICIA" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="126" end="135" text="Richgrove" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="137" end="139" text="MD" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="141" end="146" text="65169" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="166" end="174" text="90495403" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P9" start="175" end="189" text="(167) 785-7949" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="210" end="220" text="03/28/2080" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="250" end="261" text="Opal Lanier" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="326" end="328" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="414" end="429" text="January of 2080" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P14" start="433" end="455" text="Madison Medical Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P15" start="793" end="808" text="Wheeling Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="1315" end="1323" text="03/26/80" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P17" start="2083" end="2105" text="Madison Medical Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="2296" end="2305" text="September" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="2457" end="2466" text="September" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="2586" end="2590" text="2078" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P21" start="2704" end="2719" text="Wheeling Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P22" start="3507" end="3513" text="lawyer" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="4713" end="4721" text="03/03/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P24" start="5246" end="5248" text="72" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="5413" end="5417" text="2080" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P26" start="6680" end="6691" text="Ray Downing" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P27" start="6726" end="6735" text="1-2235241" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P28" start="6757" end="6765" text="03/28/80" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P29" start="6770" end="6778" text="03/28/80" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P30" start="6783" end="6791" text="03/28/80" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>