<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2085-08-31

EDVISIT^78865189^GILLIS, BETTY^08/31/85^GUEVARA, ELIZABETH

The patient was seen with Dr. Izaguirre.  Resident's note was

reviewed.  The patient was seen and examined by me.  Please see

the resident's note for details of the patient's past medical,

social, family history, review of systems, and physical exam.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  EKG changes.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 73-year-old woman with a

history of 2 ischemic strokes in the past, hypertension and high

cholesterol who presents with 1-2 weeks of feeling tired after

breakfast.  She went into Copley Hospital with this complaint today,

is a somewhat difficult historian but denies any chest pain,

shortness of breath, diaphoresis, nausea, vomiting, arm pain,

diarrhea, constipation, dyspnea on exertion, recent change in her

medications or any other complaints.  Today, she had the symptoms

and was seen at the outside office.  An EKG was performed there

for which she was sent here with a reading of a T-wave inversion

in V2 and V3.  There seems to be lead placement problem V1 and

V3.  Leads appeared ____, but there is a slight T-wave inversion

in what would be V1 and V2, which seems to be new from prior EKG.

 Placement of leads could not be confirmed at CH.  The patient

was sent in here and arrived chest pain free and otherwise

asymptomatic.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypertension, high cholesterol, COPD,

arthritis, ischemic strokes x2, GI bleed in the past,

osteoporosis, and colon polyps.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Bilateral total knee replacements.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She is a past smoker, never used drugs.  Lives

alone.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Unclear as the patient is adopted.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise, negative except for some ____.

MEDICATIONS:  The patient takes PPIs, Prilosec, calcium,

atenolol, Aggrenox, iron, doxepin, Detrol, and simvastatin.

ALLERGIES:  None.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is afebrile, normal and stable vital

signs.  Pulse 73 and blood pressure 129/80.  Awake, alert, in no

distress.  Her exam is essentially unremarkable including clear

and equal breath sounds, normal JVD and regular rate and rhythm. 

No murmurs on cardiac examination.  Abdomen is soft and

nontender.  Skin is warm, dry, and intact except for some

psoriatic lesions that are old.  She has no pedal edema and the

rest of her examination is essentially unremarkable.  EKG in the

Emergency Department shows sinus rhythm at 65 with an upgoing

T-waves in all the precordial leads.  Laboratory examination

reveals negative cardiac enzymes and is otherwise unremarkable. 

PTT 21 and INR 1.  Chest x-ray shows no acute changes.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  She was seen by the CH

cardiologist, Dr. Brock.  In the Emergency Department, given

the patient's vascular disease, the plan is to admit for 2 sets

of enzymes and a stress in the morning.  She is well appearing at

the time of admission.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  EKG changes.

______________________________

GUEVARA, ELIZABETH M.D.

D: 08/31/85

T: 08/31/85

Dictated By: GUEVARA, ELIZABETH

eScription document:9-9287507 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2085-08-31" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="78865189" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="58" text="GILLIS, BETTY" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="59" end="67" text="08/31/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="68" end="86" text="GUEVARA, ELIZABETH" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="118" end="127" text="Izaguirre" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="414" end="416" text="73" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="596" end="611" text="Copley Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="1273" end="1275" text="CH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P9" start="2710" end="2712" text="CH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2732" end="2737" text="Brock" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="2998" end="3016" text="GUEVARA, ELIZABETH" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="3026" end="3034" text="08/31/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="3039" end="3047" text="08/31/85" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="3062" end="3080" text="GUEVARA, ELIZABETH" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P15" start="3102" end="3111" text="9-9287507" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>