<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2095-04-24

EDVISIT^97198841^HOLDEN, MATIAS^04/24/95^XIE, LORI

The patient was seen primarily by the PA.  I confirm that I have

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed evaluation,

plan of care, and disposition with the patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 41-year-old male

with diabetes and high blood pressure who presents to the

Emergency Room complaining of some sore throat symptoms for 3

days also reporting some chest discomfort that has been on and

off since Friday.  Denies any association with cough or

movement.  I guess it is at rest and also with activity and

noticing also increasing shortness of breath with activity.  No

lower extremity swelling and no PND.  Has been having off and on

chest discomfort.  However, in the past four months, had negative

ETT at Smithers Albany Center per his report.  Denies any

headache, fevers or chills or recent travel.  Did have a negative

ETT by his report at an outside hospital four months ago.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for hypertension, diabetes

insulin requiring, and hypercholesterolemia.

ALLERGIES:  He has no known allergies.

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Insulin, lisinopril, metformin, and

anticholesterol medications.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  The patient is a current smoker, denies any

alcohol or IV drug use.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Hernia repair in the past.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Sore throat, cough, shortness of breath, and

chest discomfort.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Afebrile, normal vital signs. He is

otherwise an overweight male in no acute distress.  Sclerae

nonicteric.  Lungs are clear to auscultation.  Cardiac exam S1,

S2, regular rhythm with no gallops, rubs, or murmurs.  Abdomen is

very soft and nontender.  No JVD on exam.  Back on head and neck

exam, TMs are clear bilaterally.  Oropharynx is clear.  Neck is

supple.

LABORATORY DATA:  Currently, still pending.

EKG normal sinus rhythm with no ST-T segment changes or evidence

of ischemia or infarct.

IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  A 41-year-old male, diabetic, hypertensive,

presents with URI symptoms.  No evidence of exam or indication

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

chest discomfort at any time as he has had for a few months,

worsening recently.  Does not appear to be exertional related,

however, given his significant risk factors and no documented

stress studies in our system we will place in Observation for a

rule out an ETT in the morning.

______________________________

XIE, LORI M.D.

D: 04/25/95

T: 04/25/95

Dictated By: XIE, LORI

eScription document:2-6202967 BF





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2095-04-24" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="97198841" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="59" text="HOLDEN, MATIAS" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="60" end="68" text="04/24/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="69" end="78" text="XIE, LORI" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="369" end="371" text="41" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="583" end="589" text="Friday" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="896" end="918" text="Smithers Albany Center" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="2089" end="2091" text="41" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2571" end="2580" text="XIE, LORI" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2590" end="2598" text="04/25/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2603" end="2611" text="04/25/95" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="2626" end="2635" text="XIE, LORI" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P13" start="2657" end="2666" text="2-6202967" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>