<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2069-10-22

EDVISIT^63107921^RILEY, MARY^10/22/2069^VOLLMER, NATHAN

Seen by Dr. Thrasher and seen and examined by me.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Shortness of breath.

Currently, being admitted to Internal Medicine.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This 66-year-old woman with a

significant medical history including hypothyroidism, history of

high cholesterol, diabetes type 1, hypertension and history of

myocardial infarction in the past and status post cholecystectomy

who presents now with palpitations and shortness of breath.  Her

complaint is that for the last 5 days, she has had this bilateral

neck pain with shortness of breath.  She had no significant chest

pain, but complaining of dull achy pain and dull achy sensation

throughout her throat.  She felt some sensation of her heart

racing with her neck pain.  Mild headache.  No fevers however. 

She has had no diaphoresis or nausea and vomiting.  Blood

pressure initially was 212/76.  Her blood pressure has since then

came down nicely, now is 161/72 and the rest of her vital signs

are normal.

MEDICATIONS:  As would be expected, she is on multiple

medications, which includes captopril, levothyroxine, clonidine

and aspirin as well as nitrates and insulin as well as albuterol

and Lipitor.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  She has had no recent pneumonia or fevers. 

Her shortness of breath is both at rest and with some exertion. 

Again, she had no significant or definitive chest pain per se but

gives history of some neck pain for the last 5 days with some

nausea.  Her palpitations have been intermittent.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is comfortable.  Her HEENT exam is

normal.  Her neck is supple without any JVP.  No bruits heard on

neck exam.  Clear lungs with normal breath sounds.  No signs of

failure, no rales.  Cardiac exam:  Regular rate and rhythm.  No

murmurs and no rubs.  Benign abdomen with normal bowel sounds. 

Soft, without any tenderness.  Extremities are normal without any

pedal edema.  Rest of her exam is benign.

LABORATORY DATA:  Chest x-ray was normal without any evidence of

failure or any acute process.  EKG, some nonspecific T-wave

changes when compared with previous EKGs, there are no new

changes.  Her urinalysis is negative.  Troponin and CK are

normal.  The rest of her labs are all benign.

ASSESSMENT:  A 66-year-old female with shortness of breath,

palpitations and 5-day history of neck pain.  Initially

hypertensive but blood pressure has normalized nicely.  No

widened mediastinum on chest x-ray.  No discrepancy in terms of

her blood pressure in both upper extremities.  Cardiac markers

are flat and EKG is unremarkable.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  Treated with aspirin, nitroglycerin

and beta-blocker in the ED.  She is currently symptom free.  She

was also given some morphine sulfate for her pain.  She needs to

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

DIAGNOSIS:  Palpitations with shortness of breath or neck pain,

possible angina.

DISPOSITION:  The patient admitted in stable condition.

______________________________

VOLLMER, NATHAN M.D.

D: 10/22/69

T: 10/22/69

Dictated By: VOLLMER, NATHAN

eScription document:1-3286211 BFFocus





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2069-10-22" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="63107921" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="56" text="RILEY, MARY" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="57" end="67" text="10/22/2069" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="68" end="83" text="VOLLMER, NATHAN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="97" end="105" text="Thrasher" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="259" end="261" text="66" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="2334" end="2336" text="66" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="3088" end="3103" text="VOLLMER, NATHAN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="3113" end="3121" text="10/22/69" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3126" end="3134" text="10/22/69" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="3149" end="3164" text="VOLLMER, NATHAN" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P13" start="3186" end="3195" text="1-3286211" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>