<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2078-10-25

 

 

 

October 25, 2078

 

Office Visit

 

Re: Larry Lockwood

MPC# 590-33-20-3

 

 

This is a 56 year old morbidly obese male who was discharged recently from 

the 

Marshalltown Pond Clinic who is here for follow up of his newly diagnosed 

diabetes mellitus. He was seen in the emergency room on 10/21 with the 

complaint of urinary frequency, hesitancy, and generally not feeling well. 

Prior to that, he had been treated with antibiotics by his primary care 

physician for a urinary tract infection with Bactrim and then ampicillin but 

he did not get better. He went to the emergency room and was admitted to the 

hospital because his blood sugar was in the 400s and he was diagnosed with 

diabetes at that time. He was discharged on 10/22/78 on insulin NPH 30 units 

in 

the morning and 15 units in the PM and was advised to follow up in the 

outpatient clinic today. Since discharge, his blood sugars have been in the 

200s. This afternoon, it is 242 2 hours after his last meal.

 

Past Medical History: He has a history of benign prostatic hypertrophy. He 

sees a urologist and they are discussing a new procedure for the same. He 

cannot have ______ because of his morbid obesity, he cannot be positioned on 

the table for the same. He also gives a history of sleep apnea. No 

hypertension. He does have a history of gastric reflux and obesity.

 

Past Surgical History: He has had bilateral hip surgery for slipped ______ as 

an adolescent.

 

Review of Systems: No chest pain. Positive review of systems for UTI symptoms 

with increased frequency and hesitancy. Other review of systems-he has 

arthritis generalized with more pain in the hip. Also has acid reflux.

 

Family History: Family history of obesity and hypertension but no diabetes or 

coronary artery disease.

 

Social History: He is a smoker but is trying to quit. He smokes less than one 

pack a day. He is a manager and is on disability. He has 2 children and is 

separated.

 

Physical Examination: He is morbidly obese and weighs about 405 pounds. Blood 

pressure 110/88. Pulse 84. Skin exam-there is evidence of acanthosis 

nigricans. He has gynecomastia. Head and neck exam-atraumatic, normocephalic. 

Extraocular movements are intact. Pupils equal, round and reactive to light. 

Cardiovascular system exam-S1, S2 heard. No S3, S4. Respiratory system-clear 

to auscultation and percussion. No added sounds. Abdomen-obese, very 

difficult 

to examine for masses or hepatosplenomegaly. On limited exam, there are no 

masses palpable. CNS-cranial nerves II-XII intact. Examination of feet with 

monofilament is negative as he is not able to feel the monofilament in both 

feet. This impairment is greater on the right foot than left.

 

Labs done so far:  hemoglobin A1c of 14, glucose on 10/21 422, creatinine 1.7, 

BUN 22, sodium 132, potassium 4.5, chloride 97, liver function tests with ALT 

10, AST 10, alkaline phosphatase 126, bilirubin 0.4, total protein 8.1, 

albumin 3.6, globulin 4.5, calcium 9.5, hemoglobin 15.

 

Assessment and Plan: 1. New onset diabetes mellitus. The patient is morbidly 

obese, has features of insulin resistance. His blood sugars today are better 

since admission. He is on insulin twice a day. He checks his blood sugars 3 

times a day and since discharge, they have been around 240 to 300. The 

patient 

is not a good candidate for metformin with his last creatinine of 1.7. He may 

be a candidate for Avandia. At the present time, his alkaline phosphatase is 

mildly elevated but his ALT and AST are normal. He has difficulty coming to 

the clinic and would prefer to have his visiting nurse and nutritionist 

communicate with the clinic physicians to adjust the dose of his insulin and 

also have his blood tests done locally rather than here in the clinic. We 

will 

increase his NPH to 40 units in the morning and 26 units in the PM. We will 

work with the visiting nurse and nutritionist to adjust the insulin dose and 

also order lab tests. We will repeat his hemoglobin A1c in a month and also 

repeat his creatinine and liver function tests at that time to see if he may 

be a candidate for Avandia. I advised the patient to return to the clinic in 

6 

months and also for him to send the blood sugar results every week until his 

blood sugars are under better control.

 

____________________________

Dr. Xan Dunn
 

XD:ullmann

 

DD: 10.25.78/Rec=d 11.04.78
DT: 12.03.78

DV: 10.25.78

 

 

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2078-10-25" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="37" end="53" text="October 25, 2078" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="79" end="93" text="Larry Lockwood" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="95" end="98" text="MPC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<ID id="P4" start="100" end="111" text="590-33-20-3" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<AGE id="P5" start="129" end="131" text="56" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="202" end="226" text="Marshalltown Pond Clinic" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="334" end="339" text="10/21" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="781" end="789" text="10/22/78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P9" start="1946" end="1953" text="manager" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2841" end="2846" text="10/21" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="4428" end="4436" text="Xan Dunn" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="4440" end="4442" text="XD" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="4443" end="4450" text="ullmann" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="4459" end="4467" text="10.25.78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="4474" end="4482" text="11.04.78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="4487" end="4495" text="12.03.78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="4501" end="4509" text="10.25.78" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>