<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2096-09-17

 Medicine Admission Note


Patient Name:  Fay, Brook
MRN: 11289501
Date: 9/16/96
Admitting Staff: Tellez
Location:  59H

Reason for Admission:  Dysphagia

HPI: Ms. Fay is a 69 year-old woman with diabetes who presented from home with an approximately 2 month history of progressive dysphagia, solid and liquid. About that time she was prescribed Amoxicillin and Metronidazole, presumably for H. pylori eradication (not confirmed); she reports an adverse reaction to amoxicillin with rash and facial swelling. The meds were discontinued and she started a course of oral methylprednisolone. She stopped this several weeks ago because it made her jittery. Approximately the same time she began to notice that food and pills would feel stuck in the throat; on further questioning, she also may have noted the presence of white spots in the mouth around this time as well. No fevers, chills, night sweats, nausea, vomiting, chest pain, palpitations, headache, lightheadedness, vertigo, rash or new joint pain; no recent travel. She does note that her blood sugars at home have been consistently elevated to the 200-300 range.

In the ED, Ms. Fay was afebrile and hemodynamically stable. She was evaluated by the GI department. A screening HIV test was negative. She was found to have mild hyponatremia and mild hyperkalemia, as well as a question of subtle ECG changes. The above findings prompted admission for further workup.

ROS: Pertinent positives and negatives above.

PMH/PSH:   
Diabetes mellitus
Hypertension
Hyperlipidemia
Obesity
GERD
Osteoarthritis and low back pain
H/o AVNRT (2094)

ALLERGIES: Reported rash and facial swelling with Amoxicillin

MEDICATIONS: 
Atenolol 50mg daily
Diclofenac 75 mg Q8 prn
Metformin 500mg PO BID
Pantoprazole 40 mg daily
Loratadine
Albuterol MDI
Meclizine 25mg PRN
Aledronate 70mg weekly

FAMILY HISTORY: Noncontributory

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Lives alone; family heavily involved in her care and assist with secondary ADLs. No alcohol, tobacco or drug use. Born in Peru, last visit about one year ago.

PHYSICAL EXAM:	
Gen: Alert, NAD
VS:  Afebrile   82   100/54   18   100% RA
HEENT:  Conjunctivae clear, anicteric, NP clear, OP with mild thrush, upper dentures; no sinus tenderness
Neck:  Supple, no adenopathy; no palpable thyromegaly
Heart: RRR, s1s2 without murmur
Lungs: CTA bilaterally without wheeze/rales
ABD: Soft, nontender, nondistended, nabs, no mass
EXT:  Warm, no edema
Skin: No rash or petechiae
Neuro: A&Ox3, no focal deficits
       
LABORATORY:
15.6 > 42.3 < 487   (77 poly, 17 lymph)
130 / 5.3 / 99 / 21 / 38 / 1.1 < 375   eGFR 48
ALT/AST normal
CK/MG/Troponin normal x 2 sets
UA: 3+ glucose, otherwise negative

MICROBIOLOGY: Urine culture pending

RADIOLOGY: None

ECG: NSR, incomplete RBBB; T wave flattening/inversion in V2-V3 that was not noted on 2094 ECG

IMPRESSION and PLAN: 66 year-old woman with solid/liquid dysphagia, oral candidiasis, and poorly controlled diabetes mellitus. The presence of thrush raises suspicion for esophageal candidiasis, though she does not report odynophagia. Mechanical obstruction should be ruled out. The presence of mild hyponatremia and hyperkalemia is likely attributable to the fact that she abruptly discontinued exogenous corticosteroids after a several week course; she is hemodynamically stable. Finally, there is little here to suggest acute coronary syndrome, though she falls into a subgroup of patients more likely to present with minimal symptoms. ECG warrants following. Diabetes is poorly controlled and may require initiation of insulin therapy; though sugars here may have been confounded by the dose of steroids given in ED.

CV: CR monitor overnight; cycle ECG and cardiac biomarkers; aspirin, continue beta blocker
Pulm: No issues; albuterol prn
GI: Upper endoscopy tentatively planned for the morning; NPO after midnight; continue home ppi
Endocrine: Sliding scale insulin, metformin; consider diabetes education, and discuss with PCP whether initiation of insulin is warranted. Check HbA1c, TFTs
FEN: Monitor lytes; lowfat ADA diet
Infectious Disease: Following EGD, fluconazole for candidiasis; leukocytosis is unexplained, but not focal evidence of infection
PPx: Enoxaparin may be started after EGD
Social work consult to assess support network and assist with discharge planning

Terry Iyer will assume care in the morning. Please page Dr. Iyer directly at 00450 with questions arising after 8:00am.


________________________________
Paul Gardner, MD
Pager 48272




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2096-09-17" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="70" end="80" text="Fay, Brook" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="86" end="94" text="11289501" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="101" end="108" text="9/16/96" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="126" end="132" text="Tellez" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="192" end="195" text="Fay" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="201" end="203" text="69" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="1165" end="1168" text="Fay" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1614" end="1618" text="2094" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P11" start="2030" end="2034" text="Peru" TYPE="COUNTRY" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2838" end="2842" text="2094" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P13" start="2869" end="2871" text="66" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="4332" end="4342" text="Terry Iyer" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="4392" end="4396" text="Iyer" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P16" start="4409" end="4414" text="00450" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="4487" end="4499" text="Paul Gardner" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P18" start="4510" end="4515" text="48272" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>