<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2096-09-05






Stonybrook Team 2 
Admission Note



PATIENT:  Dalley, Wade

MRN:  5694653

ADMIT DATE: 09/05/96  

PCP:  Dr. Xavier

CONTACT:  Dr. Xavier



CC: Diarrhea and cough



HPI: This is a 61 y.o male w/ h.o of aspiration PNA (says he has had many bouts over past 2 yrs and though due to dyskienisa and all studies in past negative), PE, Promyel. Leukemia in remission since 2090, TIA (on coumadin 7.5mg), dyskinesia, DM2 who presents with non productive cough x2 days w/ diarrhea and mild nausea. Diarrhea began at 1:00am night before he was seen by PCP. Had hamburger and hot dog the night before. No history of C. Diff in past, was not on abx at the time, and only sick contact was wife who had bronchitis that began 2 days prior but she did not have any GI symptoms. He was seen by PCP dr. xavier the next day who though he had a PNA and felt GI symptoms were food or PNA related. He was started on augmentin 875/125 which did not help him. The diarrhea worsened but denied BRPR, melena, Hematoschezia. Colonsocopy in past only significant for diverticulosis. He took his temp at home and was 102.8 and had episode of chills but no CP, SOB, Ab Pain, or other symptoms. No recent travel, sputum was clear and minimal, and no hemoptysis. No recent hospitalizations. Was advised to come to ED by PCP. 





ED COURSE:  In the ED his Vs were 98.8, 88-109, 112-145/63-77, 22-24, 93% on 2L and 94% on 2L. He as given fluids, Levofloxacin 750mg x1, Mg and K was repleted as it was 1.5 and 3.3 respectively. CXR showed LLL PNA . Bcx sent. 



OTHER ROS:  Negative except per history





MEDICAL HISTORY

Promyelocytic Leukemia in remission for since 08/2090

Dyskinesia likely 2/2 to perphenazine exposure during last chemo

HTN now resolved

PE in 3/93 s/p thyroid nodule removal and was on 6mo course of coumadin

TIA at PCH in 7/93 and on coumadin since. Past coag work-up negative

PNA- h/o of aspiration pneumonia

DM2

s/p subtotal thyroidectomy (no cancer) on levo for hypthroid 

Spondylosis

DM2



Colonoscopy in 2094 showed divertiuclosis but no polyps

Echo in 2093 was nml w/ EF of 60%

Barium swallow in 2093 normal



FAMILY HISTORY

Mother died of breast Ca at 76 and father of MI at 67

2 daughters are healthy




SOCIAL HISTORY

1ppd for 15yrs and stopped 15yrs ago

Rare EtOH

Works at dupont



ALLERGIES:  Perphenazine, caused dyskinesia



MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION

  1. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)   PO QD 81MG form: TABLET CHEWABLE take: 1  Tablet(s)

  2. Albuterol Inhaler Hfa (Proair Hfa)  2 PUFF INH QID prn wheeze/cough

  3. Tessalon Perles (Benzonatate)   PO TID prn cough 100MG form: CAPSULE LF take: 1  Capsule(s)

  4. Clozapine  125 MG PO QD

  5. Levothyroxine Sodium  125 MCG PO QD

  6. Metformin  850 MG PO TID with meals

  7. Multivitamins  1 CAPSULE PO QD

  8. Prilosec (Omeprazole)   PO BID 20MG form: CAPSULE CR take: 1  Capsule(s)

  9. Reserpine  1.5 MG PO QD


10. Simvastatin  20 MG PO QHS


11. Sitagliptin (Januvia)  100 MG PO QD


12. Venlafaxine Extended Release (Effexor Xr)  150 MG PO QD


13. Warfarin Sodium  7.5 MG PO QPM adjusted to maintain INR 2-3.





PHYSICAL EXAM

VITALS:  99.1, 89, 121/71, 20, 96% on 4L

Gen: NAD, A&amp;Ox3

HEENT: oral mucosa clear, no lymphadenopathy, PERLA, EOMI

Neck: no JVP, no nodules, no tenderness

Chest: Rhonci most pronounced on left and e-a changes on LL base

CVS: RRR, no MRG

Ab: soft, NT, ND, No rebound, no HSM





Labs

CBC: 8.6/38.5/198     Electrolytes: Na 137, K 3.3, Cl 103, CO2 24,5, BUN/Cr 12/1.30   Ca 9.4, Mg 1.3, Phos 2.5

INR 3.5, UA -, Bcx in past negative



Radiology

CXR: LLL PNA



ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN: This is a 61 y.o male w/ h.o of aspiration PNA, PE, Promyel. Leukemia in remission since 2090, TIA (on coumadin 7.5mg), dyskinesia, DM2 who presents with non productive cough x2 days w/ diarrhea and mild nausea. The diarrhea seems to have been present before the abx and like worsened by it. Considering its sudden nature after meal likely a gastroenteritis and it is now worsened with augmenting. His PNA is either 2/2 to aspiration or CAP.





ISSUE #1: PNA- will tx with levo 750mg po x5-7 days. Remains afebrile and BP stable

- BCX, UCx, Urine Legionella


ISSUE #2: Combination of gastroenteritis and worsened by augmentin

-         Stop augmentin
-         Send C. Diff and dydrate




ISSUE #3: Cr increase- likely pre-renal and will give fluids. If does not resolve will send urine studies



ISSUE #4: DM2- will hold metformin and juanivia and start sliding scale while he is in the hospital



ISSUE #5: h/o of TIA and supratherapeutic INR- will hold coumadin today and recheck INR tommarow and adjust accordingly



Otherwise for all other PMHx issues will maintain on home medications as they are not active issues at this point 



FEN: Regular diabetic diet. Fluids of NS at 125cc/hr





PROPHYLAXIS

GI: Colace, senna. Continue PPI

DVT: Already on coumadin



CODE:  Full

__________________________________

Jonnie Vue, Pager 36407




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2096-09-05" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="33" end="43" text="Stonybrook" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="80" end="92" text="Dalley, Wade" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="100" end="107" text="5694653" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="121" end="129" text="09/05/96" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="143" end="149" text="Xavier" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="165" end="171" text="Xavier" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="216" end="218" text="61" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="402" end="406" text="2090" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="821" end="827" text="xavier" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="1674" end="1681" text="08/2090" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1773" end="1777" text="3/93" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P12" start="1847" end="1850" text="PCH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="1854" end="1858" text="7/93" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="2047" end="2051" text="2094" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="2097" end="2101" text="2093" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="2142" end="2146" text="2093" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P17" start="2201" end="2203" text="76" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P18" start="2224" end="2226" text="67" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P19" start="2330" end="2336" text="dupont" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<AGE id="P20" start="3664" end="3666" text="61" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="3743" end="3747" text="2090" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P22" start="4983" end="4993" text="Jonnie Vue" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P23" start="5001" end="5006" text="36407" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>