<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2154-05-15


Team 3 Admission Note
 



PATIENT: Nathan Ishida 

MRN: 8792076 

ADMIT DATE: May 15, 2154

PCP: Norman Jewett, MD

ATTENDING PHYSICIAN: 

CONTACT: Alice Zacharias
, (582)157-6993

CODE STATUS: Full




CHIEF COMPLAINT

Dizziness and change in mental status



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS

Mr. Ishida is a 78 y/o, who p/w dizziness that began 2 to 3 weeks ago. The pt says the dizziness was worsened when he stood up to walk around; noting that it was particularly bad when he was standing and concentrating on a particular task such as shaving. The dizziness was alleviated by him lying down. He added that he began feeling dizzy during the storm last week when his drinking water was contaminated.  He drank tap water until he was told it was undrinkable, then he stopped. He later developed diarrhea while not drinking any water and only having occasional Coca-cola beverages. During these 2 weeks of dizziness, Mr. Ishida notes he felt that he lost 3-4 days of his life, saying that he was either knocked out or unconscious. He came to this conclusion b/c his medication box was still full for the previous 3 days; supporting his reflection by saying he rarely ever misses his medication. Mr. Ishida states that the room was not spinning and said that his dizziness was more like &#8220;lightheadness.&#8221; He feels that his problems began when taking Tylenol- 2 weeks ago and cannot identify any other medication that is associated with his symptoms. Mr. Ishida says he&#8217;s never experienced any dizziness before, and hoped his symptoms would subside if he just stayed in bed. Mr. Ishida also described an increased pressure in his head, saying, &#8220;it felt as if my eyes and ears were going to explode.&#8221; Pt denies head trauma/falls, syncope, intoxication (from drugs or ETOH), or CP.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS

General- No fatigue, lack of sleep, change in appetite, or weight gain/loss

Skin- No rashes, pruritus, bruising, or swelling

Head- No trauma, headache or syncope

Eyes- No change in vision, blurring, diplopia, irritation, photophobia, discharge, or spots/flashes

Ears- No change in hearing, pain, itching, buzzing, or ringing

Nose- No nasal congestion, runny nose, or epistaxis

Mouth/Throat- No oral ulcers, pain, dry mouth, dysphagia, sore throat, or swollen glands

Neck- No pain, discomfort

Breast- No pain, masses, or discharge

Lungs- No cough, SOB, DOE, orthopnea, PND, or pain

Cardiac- No CP or pressure or palpitations

Abdomen- Mild occasional constipation (resolved with laxative or stool softener). No pain, cramping, bloating, indigestion, or heartburn.

GU- No dysuria, polyuria, or nocturia. No discharge or pain in penis or groin.

MSK/Circulatory: No arthralgias, arthritis, cramps, stiffness, myalgias, tingling/numbness, or claudications

Endo- No heat/cold intolerance

Neuro- No shaking/tremors, memory changes, confusion, trouble reading, or speech changes. No paresthesias, numbness, or weakness.

Psych- No depression or sad mood.



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY

Major Illness/Surgeries- DM, CKD, HTN, Psoriasis, BPH, GERD/Barrett&#8217;s Esophagitis (1/2151), Gout, Sleep Apnea,  s/p knee replacement surgery, cholecystectomy, appendectomy, tonsillectomy.



Medications 

1. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin) 81 MG PO QD

2. Allopurinol 300 MG PO QD

3. Ammonium Lactate 12% Cream (Amlactin 12%)  1 APPLICATION TOP BID

4. Atenolol 25 MG PO QD

5. Dovonex (Calcipotriene 0.005%)   TOP BID prn

6. Darifenacin Extended Release (Enablex) 15 MG PO QD

7. Docusate Sodium (Colace) 100 MG PO TID

8. Finasteride (Alopecia) (Proscar) 5 MG PO QD

9. Furosemide (Lasix) 40 MG PO QD

10. Lactulose 30 ML PO qD

11. Lisinopril 40 MG PO QD

12. Metformin 500 MG PO BID

13. Naproxen 375 MG PO BID prn toe pain

14. Omeprazole 20 MG PO BID

15. Sennosides (Senna Tablets) 2 TAB PO BID

16. Simvastatin 20 MG PO QHS

17. Valsartan (Diovan) 320 MG PO QD



Allergies- NKDA



Immunizations- Up-to-date



FAMILY HISTORY

Mr. Ishida&#8217;s mother died at 90 y/o and his father at 64 y/o due to a myocardial infarction. The Pt has 4 brothers, 3 daughters, and 2 sons; all in good health according to the pt.

SOCIAL HISTORY

Mr. Ishidas is an Visual Artist and former Exhibit Designer. He served in the government as a consultant, and denies any hazardous environmental exposures. His wife died 10 years ago of ovarian cancer and dearly misses her.

Diet- Mr. Ishidas describes his diet as &#8220;not as good as it should be.&#8221; He said he generally eats what he wants, eats out a lot and says he can eat a lot of &#8220;junk food.&#8221; He also said the only time he eats &#8220;well&#8221; is when he eat at his son&#8217;s or daughter&#8217;s house.

Smoking- Non-smoker

Alcohol- 2-3 bottles of beer per month. Pt doesn&#8217;t feel he needs to cut back.

Drugs- According to the pt he has used cocaine and crack as recent 5-6 years ago.

Sexual Hx- Mr. Ishidas is not currently sexually active.







PHYSICAL EXAM

Pt is an obese man with noticeable skin lesions (psoriasis) and alopecia. He looks well and jovial aside from his labored breathing.

VS: T: 97.8 BP: 122/60 HR: 92 RR: 18 SpO2: 97 on Room Air

General- No Acute Distress

HEENT - normocephalic, atraumatic; PERR, EOMI, sclerae anicteric, no conjunctival injection; poor dentition, oropharynx pink and moist w/o erythema, exudates, or lesions

Neck - no lymphadenopathy, normal thyroid without masses; JVP flat; carotid pulses 2+ bilaterally; no carotid bruits; the trachea is midline

Pulmonary &#8211; Symmetrical expansion. Normal percussion w/ no change in fremitus. Ronchi and wheezes bilaterally. No egophony or pectoriloquy.

Cardiac &#8211; irregularly irregular rhythm and rate; S1 and S2 normal; no murmurs, rubs or gallops; 2+ pulses in the extremities bilaterally

Abdomen - soft, non-distended; slight tenderness upon palpation of posterior abdomen; normal bowel sounds; no masses or hepatosplenomegaly

Extremity - warm and well-perfused; no clubbing, cyanosis, or edema

Neurology - CN II-XII grossly intact, good strength bilaterally, normal sensation bilaterally. Normal gait.

Skin &#8211; psoriatic lesions on elbows and thorax(anterior and posterior). 

Mental status - alert and oriented to self, time, and place




LABORATORIES



142  113   58

-------------- 115

5.3        20.6 3.03



CA 9.2                                  

PHOS 3.1                                

MG 2.3(H)                               

TBILI 0.4                               

DBILI 0.1                               

TP 7.1                                  

ALB 4.1                                 

GLOB 3.0(T)                             

AMY 83                                  

LIPS 115(H)                             



WBC 5.5                                             

RBC 4.11(L)                                         

HGB 12.2(L)                                         

HCT 38.3(L)

PLT 149(L)                                          

MCV 93        



ALT/SGPT    7(L)                                                      

AST/SGOT    9(L)                                                      

ALKP        70                                        



CK-MB       Negative                
                                 

TROP-I      Negative            



MICROBIOLOGY

N/A



RADIOLOGICAL STUDIES

CXR: No pneumonia or other significant change from 11/26/52.

Head CT: No acute intracranial hemorrhage, mass lesion or territorial infarction identified. Chronic infarctions of the pons and right frontal operculum, unchanged.



EKG

Irregularly irregular rhythm, RBBB, abnormal ECG. PR&lt; 200 ms, QRS&lt; 110 ms, QTc&gt;470



ASSESSMENT

Mr. Ishida is a 78 y/o M with h/o CKD, HTN, and NIDDM p/w sustained dizziness and altered mental status. Mr. Ishida is most likely currently in a volume depleted stated. He had diarrhea induced by the contaminated water from the storm and only maintained his hydration with a meager 2 or 3 bottles of Coca-cola over several days. This in combination with his output of fluid from diarrhea, his diuretic medication, and possible osmotic diuresis (increased serum glucose level from soda intake in a diabetic) could have shifted him into hypovolemia. Thus Mr. Ishida might have decrease effective arterial volume causing his BUN/Cr ratio to be elevated, indicating a prerenal process. Although BUN/Cr ratio is not &gt;20, we can still assume that he has prerenal ARF considering his use of diuretics and h/o CKD which can decrease the sensitivity of BUN/Cr rations and FENa for assessing etiologies of renal failure. Mr. Ishida additionally uses NSAIDs (e.g. Naproxen), an ARB and an ACEI, all of which are associated with decreased intraglomerular pressure and renal vasoconstriction which can lead to prerenal ARF.

Intrinsic ARF is less likely considering he is not using any overtly nephrotoxic drugs (e.g. amphotericin, cisplatin, or aminoglycosides. Conversely, he is at an increased risk of cholesterol emboli given his h/o of hypercholesterolemia and vasculopathy.

      Lastly, Mr. Ishida my have a postrenal ARF etiology considering his h/o BPH which could lead to obstruction of the outflow tract leading to increased pressures in the ureters flowing back up into the kidneys.

      Mr. Ishida&#8217;s dizziness and altered mental status are both explained by ARF. Additional explanations of altered mental status are ruled out via the history and physical including intoxication, brain hemorrhagic, brain tumor, etc.

PLAN

#) Acture Renal Failure

-Continue fluids and hydration: 1L of IV saline over the next 24 hrs

-D/c naproxen use.

-Rule out Post-renal etiology: use ultrasound to assess the size of the bladder and ureters. If enlarged bladder and ureters are found the diagnosis is more likely postrenal ARF due to an enlarged prostate. Thus the patient should be assessed by Urology of possible partial prostatectomy.



#) DM

-Discontinue metformin due to possibility of metabolic acidosis and hospital drug interactions.

#) CAD

      -Switch Atenlol to metoprolol given ARF

#) HTN

-Discontinue lisinopril, valsartan, furosemide until pt&#8217;s renal condition improves.

#) Gout

      -D/C allopurinol until pt&#8217;s renal condition improves

#)Hypercholesterolemia

-Continue simvastatin as previously prescribed (Simvastatin  20 MG PO QHS)

#) Psoriasis

-Continue Ammonium Lactate 12% Cream and Calcipotriene 0.005%   TOP BID prn

#)Benign Prostate Hypertrophy

      -Continue Finasteride and darifenacin as previously prescribed.

_________________________

William Yates, MSIII

Pager #66612




]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2154-05-15" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="65" end="78" text="Nathan Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="86" end="93" text="8792076" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="108" end="120" text="May 15, 2154" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="127" end="140" text="Norman Jewett" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="178" end="193" text="Alice Zacharias" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P6" start="196" end="209" text="(582)157-6993" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="323" end="329" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="335" end="337" text="78" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="948" end="954" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="1226" end="1232" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="1491" end="1497" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="1621" end="1627" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="3131" end="3137" text="1/2151" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="3989" end="3995" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P16" start="4019" end="4021" text="90" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P17" start="4044" end="4046" text="64" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="4192" end="4198" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P19" start="4206" end="4219" text="Visual Artist" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P20" start="4231" end="4247" text="Exhibit Designer" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P21" start="4262" end="4276" text="the government" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P22" start="4282" end="4292" text="consultant" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<NAME id="P23" start="4423" end="4429" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P24" start="4926" end="4932" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="7424" end="7432" text="11/26/52" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P26" start="7719" end="7725" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P27" start="7731" end="7733" text="78" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P28" start="7824" end="7830" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P30" start="8273" end="8279" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P31" start="8634" end="8640" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P32" start="9105" end="9111" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P33" start="9313" end="9319" text="Ishida" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P34" start="10611" end="10624" text="William Yates" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P35" start="10640" end="10645" text="66612" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>