<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2079-03-13


HMH
null                                      GEIGER, XANDER
Rayne, MI null                                      01729440
null                                           03/13/79


HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient has a known history of
hypopituitarism and hypertension who comes in today for routine
annual exam.  He states that he has been feeling exceptionally
well.  No history of chest pain, angina, dyspnea on exertion,
shortness of breath, abdominal complaints.  No difficulties in
bowel habits, melena, BRBPR.  No prostatic symptoms of urinary
hesitancy or slow stream.  He states that he has been carefully
taking his prednisone and testosterone as prescribed, as well as
his blood pressure medicines including lisinopril 40 q.d.,
atenolol 75 q.d., and his cholesterol medicine 10 of Lipitor q.d.
 He is no longer taking the hydrochlorothiazide that was
prescribed to him in the past.  He also states that he has run
out of Synthroid and has not been taking that for the past
several weeks.

The patient states that he is staying active, getting some
exercise, continues to abstain from smoking or drinking, and has
an appropriate diet.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  On full review of systems, he denies any
current concerns except for occasional difficulty maintaining an
erection, which he states is not a significant problem for him.

MEDICATIONS:  Lipitor 10 q.d., testosterone q.3. weeks,
prednisone 5 mg q.a.m. 2.5 mg q.p.m., lisinopril 40 mg q.d., and 
atenolol 75 mg q.d.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Panhypopituitarism secondary to
macroadenoma resection and hypertension.

HEALTH MAINTENANCE:  Last cholesterol level 06/2077, total 171
with an HDL of 57 and LDL of 86.  The patient has not had a prior
colonoscopy.  Last PSA was less than assay 1 year ago.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Well appearing, in no acute distress. 
Blood pressure elevated at 170/84, heart rate 60.  HEENT:  Pupils
equal, round, reactive to light.  Extraocular movements are
intact.  Fundi are benign.  Oropharynx is clear.  Tympanic
membranes are clear.  Neck:  Shows no lymphadenopathy, no
thyromegaly.  He does have a 3 x 3 cm cyst on his posterior neck
that seems to be a lipoma.  JVP is flat.  Carotids are 2+ without
bruits.  Lungs:  Clear to auscultation bilaterally.  Cardiac: 
Regular rate and rhythm, S1, S2 normal, positive S4, 1/6 systolic
murmur at the apex.  Abdomen:  Midline scar status post some type
of cord resection.  Positive bowel sounds, soft, nontender,
nondistended, no hepatosplenomegaly.  Aorta is nonpalpable. 
There are no renal bruits.  Femoral arteries are without bruits. 
GU:  Testicles appear normal.  Penis appears normal.  Rectal: 
Guaiac negative brown stool.  Prostate is smooth and nonenlarged.
 Extremities:  No clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  Normal sensation
to vibratory in the feet.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  The patient is a very pleasant 77-year-old
man who is overall doing extremely well except for his
hypertension which is poorly controlled.  I am unclear as to why
he stopped his hydrochlorothiazide, but I think that this should
be restarted as we do not have any further room with his
lisinopril or atenolol.  He will begin at 25 mg q.d.  I will have
his electrolytes checked today and come back and see me in 2
weeks' time for a repeat electrolyte check as well as blood
pressure check, and further medication adjustment if necessary. 
We will also check urinalysis for protein as well as an EKG at
this time given his hypertension.

Hyperlipidemia, on Lipitor.  We will recheck cholesterol today.

Panhypopituitarism.  He seems to be doing well on his medications
except that he stopped his TSH dose for unclear reasons.  I have
instructed him to restart his Synthroid and given him new
prescriptions.  We will recheck thyroid panel at this time.

Health maintenance.  We will check a PSA and schedule a
colonoscopy today.

He will return to clinic in 2 weeks' time for a BP check.


______________________________
NATHAN WHALEY, M.D.

eScription document:6-3377872

DD: 03/13/79
DT: 03/14/79
DV: 03/13/79

========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================





========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================



77 yo man here for fu pmhx of htn, panhypopit . no complaints today. he is taking all his meds except for his hctz. bp is high today. p of 60. plan to resume his hctz, check chol, tsh, psa, colonscopy. pt seen, discussed with resident, plan as above. 



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2079-03-13" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="29" end="32" text="HMH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="75" end="89" text="GEIGER, XANDER" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="90" end="95" text="Rayne" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="97" end="99" text="MI" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P5" start="142" end="150" text="01729440" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P6" start="198" end="206" text="03/13/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="1658" end="1665" text="06/2077" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="2891" end="2893" text="77" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="3977" end="3990" text="NATHAN WHALEY" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P10" start="4018" end="4027" text="6-3377872" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="4033" end="4041" text="03/13/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="4046" end="4054" text="03/14/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="4059" end="4067" text="03/13/79" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P14" start="4219" end="4221" text="77" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>