<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2092-11-19



Reason for Visit

Nancy is a 74 y/o womanhere for evaluationof TH and DM treatment. Also, c/o pain in right knnee with weight bearing.  Hashad for about 11 months.  Naproxen helped in past. No swell red or hot. With AM stiffness. NO other joint complaints. 



Problems

      Glaucoma

      Diabetes mellitus type 2

      Hypertension

      Osteoarthritis

      Polyarteritis    : 20 years ago.



Medications

      Dyazide  (TRIAMTERENE 37.5 Mg/hydrochlorthiazide 25 Mg)    1 CAPSULE PO QD 

      LISINOPRIL   10MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

      GLYBURIDE   5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 

      Prevacid (LANSOPRAZOLE)    30 MG (30MG CAPSULE DR take 1) PO QD 

      Alphagan (BRIMONIDINE Tartrate)    1 DROP OU BID 

      METFORMIN   850 MG (850MG TABLET take 1) PO TID 

      PHENOBARBITAL   32.5 MG PO QD 

      ATENOLOL   25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 



Allergies

      Penicillins    - Unknown



Narrative History

Takes meds. No SEs.  Nocturia x 2 ; polys-uria  ;  

Eyes- no complaints. Last exam - 10/92.  Feet- no pain, numbness, burning. 

Cor- No chest pain.  No SOB.  No  palpitations.  No lighthead.  No PND.  No orthopnea.  No claudicatioin.  No edema.  No  nausea

GI- No nausea.  No  vomitting. No  dyspepsia.  No  reflux.  No abdo pain.  No diarrhea but has loose stool.  No constipation.  No melena.  No BRBPR.

Neuro- No headache.  No vision change.  NO  hearing change.  No numbness.  Hands, feet with tingling.  No loss of strength. No seizures.  No loss of balance.

ETOH/drugs-   no

Cigs- no

Diet-no

Exercise-no

Home glu-100's

Hypoglycemia-no

Other complaints-no 



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   134/64

      PULSE   88

      TEMPERATURE   98.8

      WEIGHT   219



Exam

NAD,WD,WN

Eyes- conj & sclera not injected; EOMI,PERLA

M&T- lips and gums unremarkable. Good dentition. Moist; no erythema; no exudate; no lesions

Neck- supple.  No JVD.  No bruit.  No LAN.  No thyromegaly

Cor- reg rhyhm. S1S2 normal. No gallop.  No rub.  NO murmer.

Pulm-  NO accessory muscle use. Percussion- normal.  Palpation-normal. Auscultation-clear. 

Abdo- normal BS;soft with no HSM.  No mass.  No tenderness

Ext/ feet:  no edema; pulses intact and symmetric. Skin intact. Monofilament intact but less right foot.

Right knee- FROM with minimal crepitus. RIght thich <leeft.



Assessment

Good BP. DM. OA but had CVA affecting right side so right side is weak. 



Disposition and Plans

PT_ strengthening RLE. BMP,HgB AIC. Try Celebrex 100mg BID. RTC 4 month orPRN.

______________________________

Nicholas Curtis Judd, M.D.



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2092-11-19" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="48" end="53" text="Nancy" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P2" start="59" end="61" text="74" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="1066" end="1071" text="10/92" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="2589" end="2609" text="Nicholas Curtis Judd" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>