<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2097-11-02

EDOBS^14477347^BENNETT, NANCY^11/02/97^OAKLEY, ALBERT

This is a shared visit with resident, Dr. Cantrell.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Briefly, this is a 79-year-old

female with a past history of insulin-dependent diabetes,

bronchitis, congestive heart failure with an ejection fraction of

65%, COPD, and polyarteritis presenting here with some

generalized weakness since yesterday.  She has no focal deficits.

 She had no fall, no fevers, no chest pain, no shortness of

breath, no abdominal pain, no nausea, no vomiting, and no

diarrhea.  She is able to ambulate with a walker.  She denies

headache.  She was feeling well until yesterday.  She had no

recent medication changes.  She has chronic lower extremity

edema, left greater than right.  She has stable 2-pillow

orthopnea.  She is followed by Dr. Whitman of Cardiology.  She

takes Lasix 80 mg twice daily among other medications and the

status was stable.  She had a normal cardiac stress test

approximately 4 months ago.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She presents with a heart rate of 84,

respiratory rate of 16, blood pressure initially of 220/90,

systolic pressure decreased to 175 without treatment shortly

after arrival, and oxygen saturation of 99% on room air with

temperature of 98.5.  She is awake and alert.  She is in no acute

distress.  She has moist mucous membranes.  Her neck is supple

with full range of motion.  She has mild left-sided facial droop,

which she states is old.  She has clear and equal breath sounds

bilaterally and no respiratory distress.  Heart is regular

without murmurs.  She has soft, nontender belly.  She has

asymmetric lower extremity edema with 2-3+ pitting edema to the

left and 1+ pitting edema to the right, which she states is

chronic and unchanged from baseline.  She has 5/5 strength

throughout.  She has no pronator drift.  She is able to ambulate

with a walker.

LABORATORY DATA:  Basic laboratory testing shows an unremarkable

CBC and Chem-7.  A set of cardiac marker shows a troponin of

0.06, which is decreased from her most recent baseline, which has

been elevated over the past several months.  Her BNP was 112. 

Her urinalysis was unremarkable.  Her EKG was a paced rhythm. 

Chest x-ray was unremarkable.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient was discussed with Dr.

Whitman who recommended the patient be admitted to the

Observation Unit for another set of cardiac markers to ____

troponin as well as observation.  He will see the patient in the

morning.  If the patient's ____ set of cardiac markers are not

increasing and she feels well enough to go home, she will likely

be discharged after Dr. Whitman sees her and makes any

medication adjustments that are necessary.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  Hypertension.

SECONDARY DIAGNOSIS:  Generalized weakness.

DISPOSITION:  Observation Unit.

______________________________

OAKLEY, ALBERT M.D.

D: 11/02/97

T: 11/02/97

Dictated By: OAKLEY, ALBERT

eScription document:1-98167165 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2097-11-02" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="34" end="42" text="14477347" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="43" end="57" text="BENNETT, NANCY" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="58" end="66" text="11/02/97" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="67" end="81" text="OAKLEY, ALBERT" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="125" end="133" text="Cantrell" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="184" end="186" text="79" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="845" end="852" text="Whitman" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="2341" end="2348" text="Whitman" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2678" end="2685" text="Whitman" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="2899" end="2913" text="OAKLEY, ALBERT" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2923" end="2931" text="11/02/97" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="2936" end="2944" text="11/02/97" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="2959" end="2973" text="OAKLEY, ALBERT" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P14" start="2995" end="3005" text="1-98167165" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>