<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2118-07-04

INTERN ADMIT NOTE

DATE: 7/03/18

TEAM: Internal Medicine

CATHY TURK 24555



PT NAME: Uribe, Walter

RECORD NUMBER: 4067033

PCP: none



CODE STATUS: unknown



CC/ID:  50yo man with DM and a 7-8 y h/o leg ulcers a/w venous stasis, p/w exacerbation of R calf ulcer.



HPI: This 50 yo man with DM and venous stasis has had chronic leg ulcers for 7-8 yrs.  The shallow ulcer on his right calf has been present for 5 months.  In the past 2 weeks, the patient has noticed increased pain and malodorous drainage from the site.  In the past he has been treated with antibiotics nad unaboots, but he cannot remember which antibiotics have been used in the past.  He denies fevers, chills, n/v/d/c, sweats, dysuria, weightloss or abd pain.

He also mentions that he has a red rash on his right forearm, across his abdomen, on the anterior chest, and in the groin.  Antifungal cream has been helpful for this in the past. 

Upon questioning, he reveals that he has had some mild left sided chest pain for 2 hours, which feels like a "pressure," non-radiating, and associated with shortness of breath.  He sleeps on 4 pillows (but that has been stable for 10 yrs), has occasional palpitations, no diaphoresis, no n/v.



PMH/PSH: 

Obstructive sleep apnea

Copd

Pulmonary hypertension

02 at 2L NC at night at home

htn

NIDDM

Venous stasis

Chronic leg ulcers

Morbid obesity

Peripheral neuropathy

Pneumonia x2





MEDS: 

Verapamil 40 tid

Glyburide 5 qd

Asa 325 qd

Lasix 40 bid





ALLERGIES: nkda



FAMILY HX: noncontrib



SOCIAL HX:  Tobacco: 44 pack years, quit 1 y ago

		  EtOH: denies

		  IVDA: denies

		   Living situation: with wife in a single-level apt.

		  Work: disabled by sleep apnea x2 yrs.  Used to drive a lot for work.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: As per HPI.  All other systems negative in detail.	



PHYSICAL EXAM:



Vital Signs:  T 98.5	BP 110/70	P 88	RR	22	SaO2 91%RA

Wt. 431.7 lbs.

General: alert and oriented obese white male, NAD, grunts with minimal exertion.

HEENT: MMM.  PERRL.  EOMI.

Neck: obese, no JVD appreciated.

Lymphatics: no LAD appreciated

Chest: CTAB

CVS: overall regular rate and rhythm with ectopy, II/VI syst murmur.

Abd: obese, pos bowel sounds, soft, nontender.

Extremities: lower extremities with skin discoloration c/w venous stasis dermatitis.  On the right calf there is a 5cm diameter surface erosion, which appears macerated and is weepy and foul-smelling.

Neuro: nonfocal.

Skin:  Light pink rash on right forearm, bilat pectoral patches, and a band across abdomen.  Groin skin folds moist and mildly erythematous.



LAB DATA: Chemistry Detail for URIBE, WALTER F


   HBH  BLOOD          04-Jul-2118 04:42  Accession# 1977U39928



Test Description        Result   Flags           Ref. Range     Ref. Units



Plasma Sodium          136                       135-145        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium       3.9                       3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride        98         L              100-108        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide  31.5                      23.0-31.9      mmol/L

Calcium                8.8                       8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus             3.0                       2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium              1.5                       1.4-2.0        meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen   10                        8-25           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine      0.8                       0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose         110                       70-110         mg/dl

Total Protein          8.8        H              6.0-8.3        g/dl

Albumin                3.6                       3.3-5.0        g/dl

Globulin               5.2        H              2.6-4.1        g/dl

Creatine Kinase Isoenz 1.8                       0.0-6.9        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index                             0.0-3.5        %

  Result Text:

     CPK and/or CKMB too low to calculate Relative Index.

Troponin-T             <0.01                     0.00-0.09      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase        160                       60-400         U/L





    Hematology Detail for URIBE, WALTER F


   HBH  BLOOD          04-Jul-2118 04:08  Accession# 8187Y34368



Test Description        Result   Flags           Ref. Range     Ref. Units



WBC                    9.2                       4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                    40.7       L              41.0-53.0      %

HGB                    13.7                      13.5-17.5      gm/dl

RBC                    4.75                      4.50-5.90      mil/cmm

PLT                    235                       150-350        th/cumm

MCV                    86                        80-100         fl

MCH                    28.8                      26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                   33.6                      31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                    14.6       H              11.5-14.5      %

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST   RECEIVED

Diff Method            Auto

Poly                   70         H              40-70          %

Lymphs                 19         L              22-44          %

Monos                  7                         4-11           %

EOS                    3                         0-8            %

Basos                  1                         0-3            %

Absolute Neuts         6.46                      1.8-7.7        th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs        1.74                      1.0-4.8        th/cmm

Absolute Monos         0.66       H              0.2-0.4        th/cmm

Absolute EOS           0.26                      0.1-0.3        th/cmm

Absolute Basos         0.05                      0.0-0.3        th/cmm

Aniso                  None                      NORMAL

Hypo                   None                      NORMAL

Macrocytes             None

Microcytes             None





    Confidential Material Please Handle Appropriately.

U/A neg.



DIAGNOSTIC TESTS / CARDIOLOGY DATA:

No acute ischemic changes, no signif change from previous.  Pos. PVC.  Pos. PVC and bigeminy on telemetry.



RADIOLOGY:

Lower extremity dopplers neg. for DVT.

Plain films of lower extremities neg. for gas or osteal elevation.





IMPRESSION: 50 yo man with chronic venous stasis and exacerbation of RLE skin breakdown, left shift in WBCs, and chest pain with dysrhythmia.



PLAN:

1.	Cellulitis:  Despite DM and venous stasis, lesion that the patient has is very superficial, and therefore need not be treated as a diabetic ulcer, requiring coverage for pseudomonas and anaerobes.  This is rather a simple cellulitis, and may be treated with Ancef.  Consult wound care nurse to recommend appropriate dressings and care of wound.  Consider c/s surgery for unaboots.  No debridement necessary.  Send blood cx - monitor for bloodstream seeding.  Consider MRI of LE to r/o osteomyelitis, however, doubt such a shallow ulceration could cause it.

2.	Chest pain with bigeminy and PVCs:  Rule out for MI by enzymes x3, as ?new dysrhythmia may signify ?myocardial irritation/damage.  Monitor EKG and telemetry.  If ruled out, consider inpt vs. outpt adenoside mibi.  Check lipid panel to further elucidate CAD risk, possibly start a statin.

3.	Deconditioning/SOB:  Consult PT/OT to assist with mobility and exercise tolerance.  

4.	Prophylaxis:  Fragmin.  Counsel re: weight loss.



Signed Cathy T. Turk, MD 24555



		   





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2118-07-04" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="53" end="60" text="7/03/18" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="87" end="97" text="CATHY TURK" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P4" start="98" end="103" text="24555" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="116" end="129" text="Uribe, Walter" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P6" start="146" end="153" text="4067033" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<AGE id="P7" start="200" end="202" text="50" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P8" start="310" end="312" text="50" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="2642" end="2657" text="URIBE, WALTER F" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="2663" end="2666" text="HBH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="2683" end="2694" text="04-Jul-2118" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P12" start="2713" end="2723" text="1977U39928" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="4112" end="4127" text="URIBE, WALTER F" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P14" start="4133" end="4136" text="HBH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="4153" end="4164" text="04-Jul-2118" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P16" start="4183" end="4193" text="8187Y34368" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<AGE id="P17" start="6192" end="6194" text="50" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="7336" end="7349" text="Cathy T. Turk" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P19" start="7354" end="7359" text="24555" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>