<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2123-12-10




 
December 10, 2123






Irvin S. Joshua Morgan, M.D.
Veterans Administration Roseburg Healthcare System
81 Goldfinch Lane
Dothan, VT 74727



RE:                   Walter Uribe
HBH: 
            406-70-33
DOB:               3/22/68



Dear Dr. Joshua Morgan:



I am seeing this 55-year-old gentleman in the office today for evaluation of lymphedema and chronic venous stasis in both lower extremities.  The patient has had innumerable episodes of ulceration, which heal with TubiGrip and Profore dressings ultimately to break down again.  The patient has been discharged from the TNA and as I understand it the question is put to me today is whether the patient is a candidate for a Lymphapress.  The patient has had chronic bilateral lower extremity discoloration and swelling for over ten years.  He has never worn compression stockings.  He has had multiple episodes of recurrent ulcers.  To the best of his knowledge he has never had phlebitis but has had Unna boots in the past.  The patient denies any prolonged hospitalization, long bone fractures or prior history of DVT. 
There is no family history of varicose veins or DVT.  He has no personal history of cancer or trauma.  He has not been involved in any prolonged travel, does not take any hormone medication and is unemployed.  



The patient's past medical history is notable for coronary artery disease, congestive heart failure, sleep apnea, peripheral neuropathy, morbid obesity, hypertension and pulmonary hypertension. 



His current medications include lisinopril, verapamil, metformin, furosemide, aspirin, vitamin C, Spiriva and Advair.  



The patient denies any family history of cancer, thrombocytosis, thrombocytopenia or bleeding.  



The patient was raised in Dothan and lives in Galion.  He does not work, denies alcohol abuse and quit tobacco eight years ago.



His review of systems is notable for right upper quadrant pain, dyspnea, glasses, diabetes and hyperlipidemia.



On physical exam he is a morbidly obese gentleman with intertriginous rashes question fungal origin in the axilla on the right.  He has distant breath sounds with fine expiratory wheezes.  He has some tenderness in the right upper quadrant to palpation.  He has a huge protuberant abdomen.  There is no tenderness in the right upper quadrant.  He has bounding carotid, brachial and radial pulses.  His femoral pulses are not palpable likely due to his body habitus.  On the left his dorsalis pedis is 1+ and on the right his posterior tibial was 2+.  He has huge legs with evidence of stasis dermatitis and lipodermatosclerosis, which is greater on the left than the right.  He has prominent varices on his right thigh near the takeoff of what appears to be an anterolateral accessory branch.  He has severe brawny induration, discoloration and superficial ulcers on the right with none on the left.  The patient seems somewhat reserved but is quite communicative when prompted.



The results of his noninvasive vascular lab studies showed bilateral greater saphenous vein reflux.  The reflux is confined to the first accessory saphenous vein in the right leg and the saphenopopliteal junction in the proximal thigh.  It should be noted that the reflux in the saphenopopliteal junction on the right is 0, in the anterolateral saphenous vein on the right it is 3 seconds and in the small saphenous vein on the right the reflux is 3 seconds.  In the deep femoral vein, common femoral and superficial femoral vein there is no reflux.  In contrast on the left there is reflux at the saphenopopliteal junction of a mere 3 seconds, in the proximal greater saphenous vein 3 seconds, midthigh 3 seconds and distal thigh 3 seconds.  In the popliteal vein there is no reflux and the small saphenous vein there is 3 seconds.  Due to the patient's size it was difficult to identify perforators.  



In summary, we have a morbidly obese gentleman with mild to moderate reflux on examination and severe stasis dermatitis and discoloration.  Thus there is a mismatch between the degree of physical findings and objective laboratory data.  I believe that this is the case primarily because the patient cannot lie flat and often sleeps with his legs in a dependent position.  Thus he has an ongoing stasis in his legs due to inactivity and dependency.  This in addition to his morbid obesity, that is a girth of 385 pounds that presses on his abdomen 24 hours a day, seven days a week and compresses the vena cava as well as the lymphatic drainage of his legs.  All of these factors taken into account contribute to his discoloration, ulceration and lower extremity swelling.



The solution to this problem is not an easy one.  With his obstructive sleep apnea and abdominal girth the chances of him objectively putting his legs up so they are higher than his belly or heart are nonexistent.  Certainly it is not unreasonable to use a Lymphapress machine to help remove some of the swelling and edema that this patient experiences in his legs, however a Lymphapress is not a maintenance device but is an interventional device.  If we do not have a plan as to what to put on his legs after the Lymphapress is removed in between treatments it will be of no long-term benefit.  I would recommend that he use a Lymphapress machine and intermittent wraps with 6 to 8 inch ACE wraps.  I would always make the tension in the ACE wraps at the level of the ankle and heel greater than the midcalf.  I have given him a prescription for a Lymphapress machine as well as ACE wraps and discussed the relevant components of his care, which are important.  I hope that these interventions will help him with his lower extremity edema and swelling.  It is unlikely that any intervention at the level of his veins will overcome the terrible hydrostatic pressure of his abdomen and total body girth.  If I can provide any additional information regarding Mr. Uribe, please let me know.



Sincerely,






Michael D. Roe, M.D.



MR/martin                    60-38574514.doc



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2123-12-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="33" end="50" text="December 10, 2123" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="57" end="79" text="Irvin S. Joshua Morgan" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="86" end="136" text="Veterans Administration Roseburg Healthcare System" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="137" end="154" text="81 Goldfinch Lane" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="155" end="161" text="Dothan" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="163" end="165" text="VT" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="166" end="171" text="74727" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="197" end="209" text="Walter Uribe" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P9" start="210" end="213" text="HBH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<ID id="P10" start="228" end="237" text="406-70-33" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="257" end="264" text="3/22/68" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="277" end="290" text="Joshua Morgan" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P13" start="312" end="314" text="55" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P14" start="614" end="617" text="TNA" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P15" start="1312" end="1322" text="unemployed" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P16" start="1776" end="1782" text="Dothan" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P17" start="1796" end="1802" text="Galion" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="5922" end="5927" text="Uribe" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="5969" end="5983" text="Michael D. Roe" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="5993" end="5995" text="MR" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P21" start="5996" end="6002" text="martin" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P22" start="6022" end="6033" text="60-38574514" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>