<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2067-03-10








PCC: Respiratory

26 Monica Street

Buena Vista, CT  84376

272-413-0358



FERRARA, LAUREN

48185437

03/10/2067



MAJOR DIAGNOSIS:  Lung mass.



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Lauren is a 75-year-old woman.  She has only a very remote history of smoking, smoking not at all after the age of 30.  In early March, she was undergoing a routine physical.  At that time, she reported she had some mild weight loss.  However, she had been trying to lose weight.  She had no respiratory symptoms of dyspnea or cough.  A chest x-ray was obtained, which revealed a 6 cm left lung mass.  The patient subsequently had a CT scan.  The CT scan revealed a 4 x 6 lung mass in the posterior subsegment of the right upper lobe.  There were some modestly enlarged hilar nodes, but all below 2 cm.  She has some tiny sub 5 mm nodules in both lungs.  The patient is referred by her primary care physician, Dr. Jordon for further evaluation.  The patient has no history of lung .  She has no history of asthma or allergies.  She has not had any history of TB or a positive PPD.  She may have had some mild asbestos exposure when she worked in a publishing company, which had asbestos containing pipes.  She has no history of malignancy.  She has no avocational exposures to dust or danders.



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Includes:

1.  Mild vascular dementia.

2.  Hypertension.

3.  Hyperlipidemia.

4.  Diabetes.

5.  Hypothyroidism.

6.  Peripheral vascular disease.

7.  Anemia.

8.  Renal artery stenosis with mild renal failure.

9.  Carotid artery stenosis.



MEDICATIONS:  Levoxyl 88 mcg a day, Plavix 75 mg a day, Aricept 10 mg a day, furosemide 20 mg a day, nifedipine 90 mg a day, Crestor 20 mg a day, metoprolol 25 mg a day, calcium, Zetia 10 mg a day, vitamin D, Nephrocaps 1 mg a day, fish oil, aspirin 81 mg a day.



ALLERGIES:  Penicillin and estrogens and red dye #5.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  She lives with her husband.  She does not drink.  She has a very remote smoking history in her teens and early 20s.



FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise, negative.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is in no distress.  Her O2 saturation is 95%.  Her blood pressure is 130/70, her pulse is 53.  Head and neck exam:  She is normocephalic and atraumatic.  Her nares are without discharge.  Oropharynx with dentures.  She has no erythema or exudate.  Neck is supple without adenopathy, thyromegaly, or bruits.  Her thorax is kyphotic.  She has normal fremitus and percussion.  Her lungs are clear.  Cardiac exam:  No JVD, S1, S2 without S3, S4, or murmurs.  Abdomen is soft.  Extremities have no clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.  She has residual of vascular surgery in her legs.  She has slightly diminished peripheral pulses.



LABORATORY DATA:  Spirometry is normal.



IMAGING STUDIES:  A chest CT is as noted.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  A 75-year-old with a large right lung mass.  This is likely to be malignant, although a nonmalignant process or inflammatory processes are remotely possible.  At this point, I am going to refer her for a PET CT scan.  Her small nodules in her lung fields bilaterally are all sub 5mm and may not be related to this malignancy.  She does have modestly enlarged hilar nodes.  I am going to refer her to Thoracic Surgery for consideration of a mediastinoscopy and potential resection.  She would likely require cardiac clearance before this would occur.  She can follow up with me after her surgery if this proves to be an inflammatory lung disorder.  Otherwise, she will follow up with Oncology.  If she was deemed not to be an appropriate surgical candidate, either because of metastatic disease or because of comorbidity, she could have this lesion biopsied via a transthoracic needle aspirate.





______________________________

Pamela Falk, M.D.











eScription document:5-33744827 EMSSten Tel



CC: Jaclyn Jordon M.D.

Mondovi Hospital

566 Ferncroft Drive

Union City, CT, 33636

Fax: 

Email: 







DD: 03/10/67

DT: 03/10/67

DV: 03/10/67



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2067-03-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="35" end="38" text="PCC" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P2" start="53" end="69" text="26 Monica Street" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P3" start="71" end="82" text="Buena Vista" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P4" start="84" end="86" text="CT" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P5" start="88" end="93" text="84376" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P6" start="95" end="107" text="272-413-0358" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="111" end="126" text="FERRARA, LAUREN" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P8" start="128" end="136" text="48185437" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="138" end="148" text="03/10/2067" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="213" end="219" text="Lauren" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P11" start="225" end="227" text="75" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="328" end="330" text="30" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="342" end="347" text="March" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="927" end="933" text="Jordon" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P15" start="1159" end="1179" text="a publishing company" TYPE="ORGANIZATION" comment="" />
<AGE id="P16" start="2030" end="2033" text="20s" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P17" start="2883" end="2885" text="75" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="3812" end="3823" text="Pamela Falk" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P19" start="3861" end="3871" text="5-33744827" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="3891" end="3904" text="Jaclyn Jordon" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P21" start="3911" end="3927" text="Mondovi Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P22" start="3929" end="3948" text="566 Ferncroft Drive" TYPE="STREET" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P23" start="3950" end="3960" text="Union City" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P24" start="3962" end="3964" text="CT" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P25" start="3966" end="3971" text="33636" TYPE="ZIP" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="3999" end="4007" text="03/10/67" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P27" start="4013" end="4021" text="03/10/67" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P28" start="4027" end="4035" text="03/10/67" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>