<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2094-09-02







NAME:     Espinal, Sandra

MRN:      4718200



MEDICATIONS:  Per LMR.

Medications

Prilosec (OMEPRAZOLE) 20MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO BID

Clonazepam 0.5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID x 30 day(s) PRN prn anxiety, up to bid

Bromfed-pd BLANK take 1 cap po q 12 hours prn

Prozac (FLUOXETINE Hcl) 20MG, 2 Capsule(s) PO QD

Glucovance (GLYBURIDE/METFORMIN) 2.5-500MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO BID

Cozaar (LOSARTAN) 50MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO QD

Vioxx (ROFECOXIB) 25MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO bid x 15 day(s)

Norflex (ORPHENADRINE Citrate) 100MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO Q12H 







S:   (1)  Patient here complaining of increased neck pain with paresthesias of her

          left arm and tingling of her third and fourth left fingers.  This often

          occurs at the end of the week, when has been at the computer all week

          and then has to take her Vioxx and Norflex for the next two or three

          days, into the weekend.  Patient becoming very frustrated regarding this.

          Did not keep follow-up with Dr. Espinosa, the neurosurgeon she

          initially saw. 



     (2)  Diabetes: Patient had her first eye exam yesterday with Dr. Dunn, who

          actually is an optometrist.  He is referring her to a retinal specialist, due

          to a question of cystoid macular edema, due to diabetic retinopathy and

          some possible borderline intraocular pressures.  The patient is very

          concerned regarding this. Is worried about her heart and kidneys, now

          that she is having problems with her eyes.  Is trying to stick to her diet,

          but is worried. Blood sugars at home have been mostly in the 200's,

          occasionally high 100's. Patient does not bring her record with her. 



O:   Patient refuses to be weighed. BP, RA sitting 128/90. Lungs: Clear to A&P.

     COR: AP 96, NSR. Positive tenderness and spasm to left trapezius muscle.

     Feet: No lesions. Dorsalis pedis pulses 2+ bilaterally.  



A/P: (1)  Chronic neck and shoulder pain with intermittent paresthesias, with

          MRI showing some chronic degenerative changes, but also mild

          impingement of the subarachnoid space, possibly even at the cord at C5-6.

          Lengthy discussion with patient regarding this being chronic problem

          and need to follow up with Dr. Espinosa.  Will refer to P.T., not only

          for therapy, but also to re-evaluate ergonomics of her work site, as this

          may help. Continue all other medications, with ice, heat and home

          exercises.  Consulted with Dr. Moses, who suggested a TENS Unit may

          be helpful.  Will discuss further with patient. 



     (2)  AODM: Now with diabetic retinopathy. Lengthy discussion of 20 to 30

          minutes with patient regarding implications of this, as well as need for

          better diabetic control, especially, as poorly-controlled diabetes is quietly

          harming both her heart and her kidneys, as well as her blood vessels. 

          Patient seems more motivated now to try to adhere to diet and exercise.

          Refer to Dr. Larry Kowalski, a retinal specialist, as soon as possible. Patient

          promises to do her bloodwork for her RFT's, fasting lipids, FBS,

          hemoglobin A1C, as well as urine microalbumin.  Will follow up with

          Dr. Moses and with me afterwards. 



Ursula Delgado, ANP



UD/reece/locke



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2094-09-02" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="44" end="59" text="Espinal, Sandra" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="71" end="78" text="4718200" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="1026" end="1034" text="Espinosa" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="1157" end="1161" text="Dunn" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="2333" end="2341" text="Espinosa" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="2577" end="2582" text="Moses" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="3117" end="3131" text="Larry Kowalski" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="3354" end="3359" text="Moses" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P9" start="3388" end="3402" text="Ursula Delgado" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="3411" end="3413" text="UD" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P11" start="3414" end="3419" text="reece" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="3420" end="3425" text="locke" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>