<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2081-02-10

GI Fellow Consult Note 



Pt: Frantz, Nicole

MRN: 236-07-19

Date of note: 2/10/81 at 12:20pm

Reason for consult: nausea and epigastric pain

Referring MD: Dr. 

ID/CC:  52yoF with DM s/p recent cholecystectomy for nausea here with recurrent nausea/vomiting

HPI:   Pt with DM presenting with 6 weeks of N/V, beginning on 12/26/80 when she had green emesis, then abdominal pain.  Was seen in ED at OSH and sent home.  She continued to vomit, went to another hospital where she stayed for a week, and had a cholecystectomy.  She felt better at home for 4 days after discharge, but had recurrent vomiting, back to ED, admitted again and discharged after a week-long stay.  She now comes to PSH after four episodes of emesis yesterday.

	Pt reports intermittent periumbilical pain, which worsens right before a bout of emesis, then dies down after the emesis.  Pain does not radiate; pt not able to characterize frequency, duration, or quality of the pain.  No obvious relationship between pain and PO intake.

	In between episodes of vomiting, she feels increased amount of secretions in her mouth that she has to spit out.  Denies any dysphagia or odynophagia.  No melena or hematochezia.  Had had constipation, which resolved with laxatives, more recently having 2 BMs/day.

	She does not recall the workup at OSH but thinks she may have had EGD and colonoscopy already, which she reports did not show any abnormality.



ROS:  no fever or night sweats.  No odynophagia or dysphagia.  No rash.  No CP, SOB, LE edema.  Appetite was good and no weight changes before 12/26/80; since then, she is afraid to eat and has lost weight and feels    weak   



PMH			

DM

HTN

S/p cholecystectomy on 1/04/81

No TB or exposure to TB



Meds currently

Zestril

Reglan

Ativan

Colace

ASA



ALL:   Percocet    GI upset.



SHx:	 lives alone  

ETOH:  none

Tobacco:  never

Drugs:  never



FHx:  	 no GI malignancy or IBD



PE	afeb	193/1-9		94		18		98% on RA

General:	middle-aged woman, thin, in some distress in the midst of vomiting green liquid

Skin:	no jaundice; no rash

HEENT:	benign OP

Chest:  	CTA bilaterally anteriorly

Cardiac:  	RRR, nl S1 & S2

Abd:		soft, obese, not distended, mild diffuse tenderness without guarding or rebound, liver edge not palpable, good BS

Rectal:		deferred; pt in midst of vomiting; ED resident did rectal exam yesterday showing nl anal sphincter tone and scant gu- stool

Extremities:	no peripheral edema

Neuro:	awake and alert and appropriate



Labs:

10-Feb-2081 03:24  

Sodium (Stat Lab)                134              L        (135-145)      mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)             3.3              L        (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)              105                       (100-108)      mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)                   26.6                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)                   16                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)            0.9                       (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)               274              H        (70-110)       mg/dl



09-Feb-2081 21:21  

Total Protein                    7.9                       (6.0-8.3)      g/dl

Albumin                          3.7                       (3.3-5.0)      g/dl

Globulin                         4.2              H        (2.6-4.1)      g/dl

Direct Bilirubin                 0.1                       (0-0.4)        mg/dl

Total Bilirubin                  0.4                       (0.0-1.0)      mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase             78                        (30-100)       U/L

Transaminase-SGPT                12                        (7-30)         U/L

Amylase                          103              H        (3-100)        units/L

Lipase                           7.8              H        (1.3-6.0)      U/dl

Transaminase-SGOT                15                        (9-32)         U/L



09-Feb-2081 21:08  

WBC                              5.9                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              41.3                      (36.0-46.0)    %

HGB                              14.3                      (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl

RBC                              5.00                      (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm

PLT                              300                       (150-350)      th/cumm

MCV                              83                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              28.6                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             34.6                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              12.8                      (11.5-14.5)    %



Poly                             56                        (40-70)        %

Lymphs                           38                        (22-44)        %

Monos                            4                         (4-11)         %

EOS                              1                         (0-8)          %

Basos                            1                         (0-3)          %



Abd CT:  The liver, spleen, pancreas, adrenal glands and kidneys

	are unremarkable on this unenhanced CT.

	There is diverticulosis of the sigmoid colon without CT evidence

	of diverticulitis.  There is no evidence of bowel obstruction.

	There is a segment of terminal ileum demonstrates thickened wall.

	No significant surrounding inflammatory change.  There is

	questionable thickening of the gastric and proximal duodenal wall

	which may possibly be due to under distention.  There is no

	evidence of free air.

	There is no retroperitoneal, mesenteric or inguinal

	lymphadenopathy. 

A/P:     52yoF with DM with six weeks of recurrent green emesis and periumbilical pain without abdominal distention or KUB or CT signs of obstruction.  Question of TI thickening and gastric thickening (but may appear that way only due to underdistention).  As per pt, she has had EGD and colonoscopy at OSH already.  Would suggest obtaining records from Fairview-Southdale Hospital first before decision regarding repeat w/u here.  Workup may entail gastric emptying scan to assess for gastroparesis, EGD and colonoscopy to evaluate for malignancy or IBD, brain imaging to r/o CNS process.  Can continue to try Reglan 10mg up to QID.



Will staff with Dr. Otis Aguilera later today.



					_______

Regina Dorsey, M.D.

      



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2081-02-10" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="59" end="73" text="Frantz, Nicole" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="80" end="89" text="236-07-19" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="105" end="112" text="2/10/81" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P4" start="201" end="203" text="52" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="353" end="361" text="12/26/80" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="719" end="722" text="PSH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="1596" end="1604" text="12/26/80" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="1723" end="1730" text="1/04/81" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2525" end="2536" text="10-Feb-2081" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="3119" end="3130" text="09-Feb-2081" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3944" end="3955" text="09-Feb-2081" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P12" start="5682" end="5684" text="52" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P13" start="6027" end="6054" text="Fairview-Southdale Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P14" start="6330" end="6343" text="Otis Aguilera" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P15" start="6374" end="6387" text="Regina Dorsey" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>