<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2091-06-12

Narrative History

   79 yo woman who presents for f/u of: 

   1.  Urinary incontinence:  She is s/p vaginal sling procedure by Dr. Xuereb in April.  She states that she did well for about 2 weeks, but then the incontinence became worse than before.  According to her son, she saw Dr. Xuereb 10 days ago who thought the procedure was a success but that the pt had a UTI.  She started her on a month-long course of nitrofurantoin.

   2.  PAF:  The pt has not noted any cardiac symptoms.

   3.  PMR:  Her shoulder pain and weakness has disappeared since starting the Prednisone.  She has noted some facial puffiness since the medication was begun.  She is being followed in Rheum by Dr. Lisa Inge.

   4.  Mental status:  She underwent neuropsychiatric testing at BMA 3 days ago and the results have been faxed to BH.  

   5.  Social:  She is currently living in Forest Hills, an assisted living facility.  She has her own bedroom and sitting room and can shut her door for privacy.  All meals are provided for her.  She enjoys the room but at times feels "confined."  She had befriended a 90 yo male patient, but recently had a bad experience when he made sexual advances toward her.  She states that she would like to move back into her apartment in Stow.

Problems

      Urinary incontinence   s/p sling procedure in 4/91; s/p 3 prior bladder suspension surgeries 



      Hypertension



      Depression



      Elevated cholesterol



      Diarrhea



      Polymyalgia rheumatica   diagnosed in 1/91 



      S/P rectocele repair



      Paroxysmal atrial fibrillation   controlled with medication 



      Peripheral neuropathy   unclear etiology 



      Hyperlipidemia



      H/O Alcohol abuse



      S/P urosepsis   admission in 9/90 



      chronic diarrhea   colonoscopy attempted in 9/90 but pt not able to tolerate procedure 



      Dementia   Mild-moderate; neuropsychiatric test done in 5/91 

Medications

      FOLIC ACID     1MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      ECOTRIN (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED)     325MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      REMERON (MIRTAZAPINE)     15MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QHS  



      METOPROLOL TARTRATE     50MG  1 Tablet(s) PO TID  



      SOTALOL     80MG  1 Tablet(s) PO BID  



      THIAMINE HCL     100MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      PREDNISONE     12.5MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QAM  



      VIOXX (ROFECOXIB)     12.5MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  PRN . 



      DIGOXIN     0.125MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      FERROUS SULFATE     325MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      MVI (MULTIVITAMINS)   1 CAPSULE      PO QD  



      CALCIUM CARBONATE   VIT D(1TABLET=250MG E...   500 MG     PO TID  



      FOSAMAX (ALENDRONATE)     70MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QWEEK  



      NITROFURANTOIN     100MG  1 Capsule(s) PO QD  

Allergies

      NKDA      

Review of Systems

   No change in appetite.  No F/C, cough, SOB, CP, abd pain, diarrhea, constipation, dysuria, or joint pains.

Physical Exam

   BP: 140/80    Weight: 133 lbs (up 15 lbs since 12/90)	



      General Appearance

         Appears healthy; facial swelling.



      Cor/Cardiac

         RRR; S1S2 with II/VI SEM at LLSB; no rubs or gallops.

Laboratory Data

   Neuropsychiatric testing (summary of results): Dementia of mild to moderate severity; pattern of deficits is consistent with primary neurodegenerative process (i.e., Alzheimer's); will impact her ability to function independently.

Assessment and Plan

   1.  Incontinence:  F/u with Dr. Xuereb after completing course of nitrofurantoin.

   2.  Cardiac:  Stable on metoprolol, sotalol, and digoxin.

   3.  PMR:  Continue low-dose prednisone.  Discussed facial bloating as side effect.  Plan according to Dr. Inge is to taper prednisone slowly over a year.  Will check ESR today.

   4.  Depression:  Much better.  No physical signs/sx of depression right now.  Continue Remeron.

   5.  Dementia:  It was suggested in the neuropsych evaluation that a cognitive enhancing medication may benefit the pt.  Will discuss starting Aricept with pt's cardiologist, Dr. Jankowski, to make sure it will not impact her Afib.

   6.  Hyperlipidemia:  Lipitor was d/c'd at some point over past year.  Will check chol/HDL today since she is not fasting.

   7.  Social:  Discussed results of neuropsych evaluation with patient.  Discussed issues of living alone and how she would need 24 hour supervision.  Pt not sure if this situation would be better than assisted living.  Discussed these issues with pt's son, Villatoro, over the phone after the visit.  Will fax him paperwork for health care proxy.





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2091-06-12" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P1" start="50" end="52" text="79" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="161" end="167" text="Xuereb" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="171" end="176" text="April" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="314" end="320" text="Xuereb" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="716" end="725" text="Lisa Inge" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P6" start="793" end="796" text="BMA" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P7" start="843" end="845" text="BH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P8" start="893" end="905" text="Forest Hills" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P9" start="1120" end="1122" text="90" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="1282" end="1286" text="Stow" TYPE="CITY" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1351" end="1355" text="4/91" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="1536" end="1540" text="1/91" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="1782" end="1786" text="9/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="1841" end="1845" text="9/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="1950" end="1954" text="5/91" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="3011" end="3016" text="12/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="3485" end="3491" text="Xuereb" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P18" start="3707" end="3711" text="Inge" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="4060" end="4069" text="Jankowski" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="4499" end="4508" text="Villatoro" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>