<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2093-04-24

Narrative History	

81 year old woman who presents for an annual exam with her daughter-in-law, Franchesca Justice.  They would like to discuss the following issues:

1.  Shoulder pain:  She continues to have bilateral shoulder pain, but the L shoulder is worse than the right.  She has been taking Prednisone 9 mg a day for a long time but has not f/u with Rheum for about a year.  She did have a cortisone in the L shoulder in the past.  She is able to lift her arms over her head.

2.  Depression:  Her family feels that she is doing much better on the Effexor than the Celexa.  The pt has seen Dr. Ramsey in Psych a few months ago.  

3.  Dementia:  Dr. Ramsey recommended continuing on the Aricept.  Overall, the pt's family feels that her memory is worsening, although some days are better than others.  She has not had any other episodes of halluncination, as was described in an email from her son a couple weeks ago.  The pt states that she is sleeping and eating well, but her family thinks that she sleeps too much.

4.  Eyelid surgery:  She is scheduled to have surgery on her eyelids on May 25.  The drooping of the lids is so bad by the end of the day that she is unable to read.

5.  Incontinence:  She has now had 3 collagen implants for her bladder.  The pt does not think that she is any better, but when Dr. Xuereb tested her a few months ago, she saw some improvement.

6.  Diarrhea:  She has about 2 soft BM's a day, but she also has intermittent diarrhea.  Her daughter-in-law is wondering if the pt might be lactose intolerant.  She is not having any blood in her stool.  She does not have any diarrhea in the middle of the night.  She has never gotten a colonoscopy since the last attempt just prior to her hospitalization 2 years ago.

7.  DM:  The pt states that she does not eat much sugar, but her daughter-in-law thinks that she probably does consume a fair number of sweets.

8.  Hyperlipidemia: She has been on Zocor 20 mg QD but is not following a low fat diet.

9.  Medication compliance:  The pt's family is not sure if she is taking her medications every day.  They pay a private nurse to come lay out the meds in the am, but the pt is often asleep when she comes and will not get up to take the meds at that time.

10.  Onychomycosis:  The pt has a fungal infection in her great toes.  Her daughter-in-law is wondering if there is anything topical to treat this with.  The pt gets regular pedicures.



Problems

Urinary incontinence : s/p sling procedure in 4/91; s/p 3 prior bladder suspension surgeries

Hypertension 

Depression 

Elevated cholesterol 

Diarrhea 

Polymyalgia rheumatica : diagnosed in 1/91

S/P rectocele repair 

Paroxysmal atrial fibrillation : controlled with medication

Peripheral neuropathy : unclear etiology

Hyperlipidemia 

H/O Alcohol abuse 

S/P urosepsis : admission in 9/90

chronic diarrhea : colonoscopy attempted in 9/90 but pt not able to tolerate procedure

Dementia : Mild-moderate; neuropsychiatric test done in 5/91 

Diverticulitis:  Hospitalized in 7/92



Medications

Folic ACID PO QD (1MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s))

Ecotrin (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED) PO QD (325MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s))

Metoprolol TARTRATE PO TID (50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s))

Thiamine HCL PO QD (100MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s))

Digoxin PO QD (0.125MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s))

Ferrous SULFATE PO QD (325MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s))

Mvi (MULTIVITAMINS) 1CAPSULE PO QD 

Calcium CARBONATE VIT D(1TABLET=250MG E... 500MG PO TID 

Nitrofurantoin PO QD (100MG CAPSULE take 1 Capsule(s))

Zocor (SIMVASTATIN) PO QHS (20MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) x 30 days)

Glyburide PO QD (2.5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s))

Prednisone PO QAM (5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s))

Prednisone PO QAM (1MG TABLET take 4 Tablet(s)), total 9 mg/d

Effexor SR (VENLAFAXINE EXTENDED RELEASE) PO QD (37.5MG CAPSULE CR take 1 Capsule(s))

Sotalol PO BID (80MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s))

Aricept (DONEPEZIL HCL) 10MG PO QHS (x 30 days)

Effexor (VENLAFAXINE HCL) PO QD (37.5MG TABLET take 4 Tablet(s)) 



Health maintenance

Cholesterol 05/24/2092 223 

Stool Guaiac 12/21/2091 Done - positive 12/09/91;12/11/91;12/12/91.All slides positive.

UA-Protein 01/18/2093 NEGATIVE 

HBA1C 05/25/2092 7.30 

Urine Culture 01/18/2093 see report in Results CATHETERIZED SPECIMEN

Triglycerides 08/26/2091 330 

Cholesterol-LDL 08/26/2091 148 

Bone Density 06/16/2091 BMD-Hip 

Hct (Hematocrit) 12/07/2092 40.7 

Cholesterol-HDL 05/24/2092 43 

Hgb (Hemoglobin) 12/07/2092 13.7 

Syphilis 09/14/2090 FINAL Result NON-REACTIVE. 



Allergies

NKDA 



Social History	

Lives in Forest Hills, an assisted living facility; never smoking; Etoh- rare- she might have one drink if she goes to her son's house for dinner; exercise- walking.



Family History	

Family History: mother died at 89 of "old age"; father died of unknown causes; no breast or colon ca; brother is s/p MI before age 60; + DM.



Review of Systems	

No change in weight, appetite.  No dizziness, F/C/N/V, cough, SOB, CP, abd pain, constipation, dysuria, joint pain.



Physical Exam	

BP: 122/70		Weight:	132 lbs. (down 8 lbs) 	Height: 5'2"

GENERAL: 	Elderly woman with Cushingoid facies.

SKIN:		NL turgor, no abnormal lesions.

HEENT:	            NL eyes, lids drooping over eyes about 1/2 way; NL oropharynx

NECK:	            No thyromegally, no nodes; carotids 2+ bilat without bruits.

CHEST:	            Clear lungs, NL frame

COR:		NL S1S2, no murmur, rubs, or gallops.

BACK:	            No spinal tenderness.

BREASTS:	Symmetrical, No dominant masses; no axillary masses.

ABD:		NL BS; soft, NO HSM

PELVIC:	            deferred

RECTAL:	            deferred

EXT:		No edema, clubbing, or cyanosis; DP pulses 2+ bilat

NEURO:	            NL MS, NL gait



Assessment and Plan	

1.  PMR:  Discussed the importance of regular f/u with Dr. Inge.  We should aim to get the dose of Prednisone decreased.  Will check ESR today.  Franchesca will make sure appt is scheduled with Dr. Inge.

2.  Depression:  She seems better.  Continue Effexor. 

3.  Dementia:  Will continue Aricept.  Discussed keeping pt stimulated with outings, family visits.  Her excessive sleeping is likely a combination of several factors, including her multiple medications, depression, and possibly the dementia.

4.  Eyelid surgery:  Pre-op exam today.  Will order complete metabolic panel, CBC, and EKG.

5.  Incontinence:  It is not likely that she will be able to have any more procedures at this point.  Some of the incontinence may be secondary to dementia rather than pure stress incontinence.

6.  Diarrhea:  Discussed trying a lactose-free diet for a week to determine if lactose-intolerance may be playing a role.  Will set up a virtual colonoscopy since the pt had such a bad experience with the sedation for her colonoscopy 2 years ago.

7.  DM:  Check glucose and Hgb A1C.

8.  Hyperlipidemia: Check fasting lipids- she will get them drawn at Dameron Hospital.

9.  Medication compliance: Discussed trying to get nurse to come a little later in the day so that pt could be observed while taking her medication.

10.  Onychomycosis:  I do not think oral medication would be a good idea for this patient because the risks of hepatotoxicity outweigh the benefits.  Will refer her to Podiatry for care of the toenails since the pt has a h/o peripheral neuropathy.

11.  Health maint:  Order mammo to be done at DH; TSH.





_____________________________________________

Faith G. Ice, M.D.











_____________________________________________

Faith G Ice, MD







]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2093-04-24" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P1" start="48" end="50" text="81" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="124" end="142" text="Franchesca Justice" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P3" start="630" end="636" text="Ramsey" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="686" end="692" text="Ramsey" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="1128" end="1134" text="May 25" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="1355" end="1361" text="Xuereb" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="2523" end="2527" text="4/91" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="2671" end="2675" text="1/91" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="2869" end="2873" text="9/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="2919" end="2923" text="9/90" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="3019" end="3023" text="5/91" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P12" start="3059" end="3063" text="7/92" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P13" start="4083" end="4093" text="05/24/2092" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="4113" end="4123" text="12/21/2091" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P15" start="4140" end="4148" text="12/09/91" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P16" start="4149" end="4157" text="12/11/91" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P17" start="4158" end="4166" text="12/12/91" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P18" start="4200" end="4210" text="01/18/2093" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P19" start="4228" end="4238" text="05/25/2092" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P20" start="4260" end="4270" text="01/18/2093" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P21" start="4330" end="4340" text="08/26/2091" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P22" start="4363" end="4373" text="08/26/2091" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P23" start="4393" end="4403" text="06/16/2091" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P24" start="4431" end="4441" text="12/07/2092" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P25" start="4465" end="4475" text="05/24/2092" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="4498" end="4508" text="12/07/2092" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P27" start="4525" end="4535" text="09/14/2090" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P28" start="4613" end="4625" text="Forest Hills" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P29" start="4821" end="4823" text="89" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<AGE id="P30" start="4921" end="4923" text="60" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P31" start="5852" end="5856" text="Inge" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P32" start="5938" end="5948" text="Franchesca" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P33" start="5991" end="5995" text="Inge" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P34" start="6940" end="6956" text="Dameron Hospital" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P35" start="7404" end="7406" text="DH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P36" start="7465" end="7477" text="Faith G. Ice" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P37" start="7542" end="7553" text="Faith G Ice" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>