<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2077-08-04

EDVISIT^42817774^AARON, JEAN^08/04/77^VALENTIN, IDA

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Status post fall, right shoulder pain.

I saw the patient with Dr. Andrew Newhouse.  Please see his note for

further details.  I confirm that I have interviewed and examined

the patient, reviewed the resident's documentation, and discussed

the evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 63-year-old female

who presents after mechanical trip and follow at work today and

hit her forehead.  No loss of consciousness, no headache, no

visual changes, no upper or lower extremities, paresthesias or

weakness.  She fell onto her right shoulder, is complaining about

pain at that area.  No focal weakness, no neck pain, no back

pain, no chest pain, shortness of breath, no belly pain.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypertension, diabetes,

hypercholesterolemia, neuropathy, and diverticulitis.

MEDICATIONS:  Currently on Novolog, verapamil, lisinopril,

amitriptyline, and aspirin.

ALLERGIES:  No known allergies

SOCIAL HISTORY:  One pack per day smoker and does not drink.  She

denies IV drug use.  She lives alone.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As per resident's note and my HPI.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is awake, alert, and nontoxic but does

appear uncomfortable.  Afebrile, vital signs are notable for a

blood pressure of 185/79, O2 saturation 99% on room air,

respiratory rate 18, and pulse 89.  HEENT exam:  Normocephalic

and atraumatic.  No facial tenderness.  No cervical spine

tenderness in the midline.  Lungs:  Clear anteriorly.  No TLS

spine tenderness in the midline.  Heart:  Regular rate and

rhythm.  Abdomen:  Soft, nontender, and nondistended.  Her right

shoulder that is held by her side, she has exquisite tenderness,

unable to really move it.  She has intact axillary nerve

sensation, full strength in her hand and fingers.  Alert and

oriented x3.  Normal mood and affect.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient thought she hit her

forehead does not have signs or symptoms suggestive of

intracerebral injuries.  I do not feel she needs imaging though

she has pain in her shoulder.  She is awake and alert and answers

questions appropriately.  She has no cervical spine tenderness in

the midline.  She did have plain films of her right shoulder that

show comminuted fracture of the right humerus involving the

surgical neck, greater tuberosity, anatomic neck with medial

displacement distal fragment.  She also had a chest x-ray that

showed some mild pulmonary vascular congestion.  The patient had

preoperative screening labs that included sodium 138, K 4.2,

chloride 101, bicarbonate 25, BUN 20, creatinine 1.4, glucose 395

and calcium 10.  White count of 27, hematocrit 41, and platelet

count 286,000.  Coags within normal limits. 

The patient will be admitted to the Orthopedics Surgery.  We will

check UA given her white count.  Of note, she did have her

differential still pending.

DIAGNOSIS:  Right shoulder fracture status post mechanical fall.

DISPOSITION:  Admitted to Ortho.

CONDITION:  Stable.  She will also be treated for hyperglycemia,

which is also another diagnosis.

______________________________

VALENTIN, IDA MD

D: 08/04/77

T: 08/04/77

Dictated By: VALENTIN, IDA

eScription document:2-7000249 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2077-08-04" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<ID id="P1" start="36" end="44" text="42817774" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="45" end="56" text="AARON, JEAN" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="57" end="65" text="08/04/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="66" end="79" text="VALENTIN, IDA" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="166" end="181" text="Andrew Newhouse" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="453" end="455" text="63" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="3264" end="3277" text="VALENTIN, IDA" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="3285" end="3293" text="08/04/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P9" start="3298" end="3306" text="08/04/77" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P10" start="3321" end="3334" text="VALENTIN, IDA" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P11" start="3356" end="3365" text="2-7000249" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>