<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2071-11-23



Visit Note



Patient Name: RICO, NATHAN C                     

MRN: 9190908

Dictated Date: 11/23/2071                    

Dictated By: Leroy Kelly

Date of Visit: 11/23/2071



Nathan was seen today in routine followup with Clinic Attending Dr. Kim Mays who concurs with the assessment plan that I will outline below.



HISTORY OF THE PRESENT ILLNESS:  Nathan is a 51-year-old, right-handed man who suffered a large right MCA territory stroke in October 2069.  This occurred in the setting of right internal carotid artery occlusion, and hemicraniectomy was required for management of malignant cerebral edema after the stroke.  He subsequently developed an infection of the abdominal bone flap.  His stroke workup revealed a normal echocardiogram and 24-hour Holter monitor.  A hypercoagulability panel was negative.  Homocysteine was normal.  Serum lipid analysis revealed mild hypertriglyceridemia.  His recovery was complicated by brain abscess, which required surgical drainage and prolonged antibiotic therapy.  Finally an artificial bone flap was replaced in October 2070.  He then developed persistent nausea and vomiting and a pseudomeningocele.  A VP shunt was placed by Dr. Bennett.  Unfortunately, even after shunting there was persistent nausea and vomiting.  This turned out to be a side effect of Fentanyl patch use.  The Fentanyl was subsequently replaced with methadone for chronic left-sided neuropathic pain, and the nausea and vomiting abated.



I last saw Nathan on April 2nd of this year at which point he was doing quite well.  He complained of some hot flashes of unclear etiology.  His depression seemed to be under better control on Celexa. 



Today he reports that he continues to have trouble with neuropathic pain on the left side of his body.  Fortunately he has managed to wean himself off of methadone and this has not caused the pain to get any worse.  He is using a substantial dose of Neurontin, which he thinks is helpful.  He complains that these pains involve his face, arm, and leg on the left side and he wonders whether there might be some relationship between the pain and the shunt, which was placed on the left side of his head.  He also complains of occasional leg spasms at night, which are not particularly bothersome.  His most significant complaint at this time relates to the hot flashes that he mentioned at our last visit.  These often occur several times daily, although they may not occur for several days at a time.  He explains that most of the episodes occur when he is in bed at night.  He first develops a feeling of nausea followed by a cold sensation on one side of his body or the other.  This has been followed by a feeling of heat from the top of his head down to his toes.  There may be a feeling of urinary urgency.  He then experiences a sensation as if he is floating on the bed, and generally this is followed by nausea.  The entire episode lasts only seconds but the nausea may persist for as long as an hour.  He also notes on some mornings he does not feel like getting out of bed.  He continues to experience depressed mood, and he longs to return to a normal state of functioning.  



He has returned to volunteering as a Big Brother.  He is unable to work.  His divorce is now complete and he is really glad about this.  He is living with a friend named Tejeda who takes excellent care of him.  



His left arm remains paralyzed.  He has minimal proximal strength in his leg.  He has a dense visual field deficit on the left side.  



He has one new complaint which is a feeling of numbness and tingling in the 4th and 5th fingers on the right side.  



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY include diabetes, hypertension, and hyperlipidemia.  



CURRENT MEDICATIONS include Celexa 20 mg daily, Neurontin 600 mg q.i.d., Phenergan p.r.n., Avandia, Glucophage, Lopressor, Zestril, Pravachol, insulin, and aspirin 325 mg daily.  



On exam Nathan is well-appearing.  His hair has now grown back.  On mental status exam he is able to relate a cogent history.  He has a number of questions about stroke rehabilitation possibilities including a hyperbaric oxygen program that he learned about in Connecticut.  Eye contact is good.  On cranial nerve exam pupils are round and reactive and extraocular movements are intact.  There is a left visual field deficit.  The face is asymmetric with an upper motor neuron pattern left facial droop.  The tongue protrudes in the midline.  The left arm is completely plegic.  The left leg has greater than anti-gravity proximal strength.  There is left-sided sensory extinction.  Reflexes are brisk on the left and normal on the right.  Nathan is able to ambulate with a cane and a left ankle foot orthosis.  



We spent much of today's visit discussing various issues that concern Nathan.  Regarding the possibility of hyperbaric oxygen therapy for stroke rehabilitation.  I explained that there is no convincing evidence in favor of this approach.  There are some risks to hyperbaric oxygen therapy such as lung injury and the programs are extremely costly.  Therefore I advised Nathan not to pursue that option.



Regarding his frequent hot flashes, which are very bothersome, the etiology of these episodes is quite unclear.  Dr. Mays mentioned the possibility that these episodes represent some sort of diencephalic paroxysmal discharges.  I think it is possible that these are a side effect of Celexa; I believe that they first occurred shortly after starting Celexa.  We decided to stop the Celexa for a 2-week period to see if there is any improvement in the episodes.  If there is, I would consider changing to an antidepressant that works by a different mechanism.  If there is no change in the episodes we can go ahead and add Celexa back.  



I neglected to mention above that there is sensory loss to temperature and pinprick in the right hand involving the 4th and 5th digits and the ulnar aspect of the hand on the palmar surface.  There is no motor dysfunction in the hand.  There is no Tinel's sign over the ulnar nerve at the elbow.  The ulnar nerve in the ulnar groove is not hypermobile.  The symptoms and physical exam are consistent with ulnar entrapment neuropathy, which I suspect is the result of arm flexion during sleep.  I suggested that Nathan buy an elbow pad with a Velcro strap that will help facilitate keeping the arm straight during sleep.  We will keep an eye on this over time.  



No other changes are indicated at the moment.  I intend to see Nathan in followup in about 6 months.





___________________________

Leroy Kelly, M.D.



cc:







TD: 11/26/2071 12:12:15

TR: quijada

Job ID:  568143









]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2071-11-23" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P1" start="58" end="72" text="RICO, NATHAN C" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P2" start="100" end="107" text="9190908" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="124" end="134" text="11/23/2071" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P4" start="169" end="180" text="Leroy Kelly" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P5" start="197" end="207" text="11/23/2071" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P6" start="211" end="217" text="Nathan" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P7" start="279" end="287" text="Kim Mays" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P8" start="388" end="394" text="Nathan" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<AGE id="P9" start="400" end="402" text="51" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P10" start="481" end="493" text="October 2069" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P11" start="1101" end="1113" text="October 2070" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="1220" end="1227" text="Bennett" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P13" start="1513" end="1519" text="Nathan" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<DATE id="P14" start="1523" end="1532" text="April 2nd" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<PROFESSION id="P15" start="3216" end="3245" text="volunteering as a Big Brother" TYPE="PROFESSION" comment="" />
<NAME id="P16" start="3367" end="3373" text="Tejeda" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P17" start="3939" end="3945" text="Nathan" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P18" start="4192" end="4203" text="Connecticut" TYPE="STATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P19" start="4671" end="4677" text="Nathan" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P20" start="4817" end="4823" text="Nathan" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P21" start="5116" end="5122" text="Nathan" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P22" start="5270" end="5274" text="Mays" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<NAME id="P23" start="6303" end="6309" text="Nathan" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P24" start="6520" end="6526" text="Nathan" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<NAME id="P25" start="6592" end="6603" text="Leroy Kelly" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<DATE id="P26" start="6628" end="6638" text="11/26/2071" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P27" start="6653" end="6660" text="quijada" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<ID id="P28" start="6671" end="6677" text="568143" TYPE="IDNUM" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>