<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2062-07-21



Halcyon House Intern Admission Note


PATIENT:  Ostrander, Pamela.  
MR: 1612187 
ADMIT DATE:  07/21/2062
PCP:  Jameson 
CODE STATUS:  Full Code 
PATIENT CONTACT:  


CC:  Fatigue 


HPI:
This is a 59 female with PMH significant for HTN, DM, Mood disorder NOS, Breast lump. Who present to the EW with fatigue and BP in the 200s. According to the patient, she had high blood pressure for years that was well controlled according to her up till Jan, when she lost her insurance and could not fill in her prescriptions. In Jan of this year, the patient stopped taking any BP meds up till she had a visit with her Psych nurse which found her BP to be in the 200s sent her to EW, they controlled her BP and sent her out on Metoprolol 50 BID, and Lisinopril 10 mg QD. After which, the patient had a trip to Peru and ran out of her medication 2 days priory to her return. When she returned about a wk ago the patient presented to EW because of another episode of hypertensive  emergency, for which, she was D/C with a follow up with one of the HGH PCPs. Patient could not get an appointment until later this month, and she was having a feeling of fatigue today, so she called her APS nurse which one more time found her to be in the 200s and sent her to the EW. 


On ROS:  Patient denies any HA, changes in vision, nausia, vomiting, chest pain, palpitation, SOB, Abd pain, syncope, palpitation, recent wt changes, change in her bowel or urinary habits. However she does describe feeling fatigued, episodes of flushing, history of hearing double messages when she communicate with other people.  No feeling of hot or cold. 


Emergency room course:  
In the EW, the BP was 210/109, P: 90, RR:18, SAO2 100%. The patient received 5mg of lopressor IV and and 50mg PO for which her BP had minimal response. She also received 20 mg of IV Labetalol then 200mg PO' after which her blood pressure was down to the 180s, then it started climbing back up to the 200s for which she received another 10 mg IV, the highest reading the patient got was 257/188. The patient was also given a 325 mg ASA, and the first 2 cardiac enzymes were negative. Relative to a previous EKG, the EW EKG showed t-wave inversion in V5 and V6.  


  PMH:
DM no insulin requirement. 
HTN
mood disorder
Breast lump  
MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION
Metforman 1000mg BID
Seroquel  100 mg QHS
Metoprolol 50 mg BID
Lisinopril 10mg QD
Neurontin 500 QHS 


ALLERGIES:  
NKDA


FAMILY HISTORY:
  HTN, DM, CAD 


SOCIAL HISTORY:




PHYSICAL EXAM:
Floor: 
HR: 72             BP: 203/109       Temp: 98.3RR:  18           I&amp;O: in out
Gen:  NAD Coop A&amp;OX
HEENT:  PERRL EOMI. oral dry. No thyromegally.
Neck:  supp NT,  no bruit,  JVD flat, no  nodes
Chest:  CTA-B
Cardiac:  RRR.  Nl  S1/S2 no S3/S4, normal S1.  No  rubs/ murmurs/thrill.  
Abd:   S/NT/ND, no palpable masses, no hepatosplenomegaly, no bruits, no palpable AAA.
Ext:  Pulses +2 symmetrical, palp PT/DT, No  Edema,  + color capr, Nails normal, without clubbing, cyanosis, or deformities.  
Skin:  Nl texture, no lesions or rashes. 
Neuro:  


-       Alert, oriented X3.  Clear speech.  
-       Cranial nerves II-XII intact by gross confrontation.  
-       No abnormal movements seen.
-       Patellar, Achillies, symmetrical. Babinski neg.
-      Intact touch and vibratory sens. Nl Motor strength. ROM intact.




LABS:




            137              107              16        
122
             3.3                28.6              .8                        


                                                                                                          
        Ca:9.3         Mg:1.7         Ph:3.6
                 
                      13.3
       9.7   286      
                       40              
UA:
UA-COLOR                                                                             YELLOW    
UA-APP                                                                               SLIGHT    
UA-GLUC                           Negative                          Negative         NEG       
UA-BILI                                                                              NEG       
UA-KET                            Negative                          Negative         NEG       
UA-SPGR                           1.020                             1.015            1.010     
UA-BLD                            Negative                          Negative         NEG       
UA-PH                             5.5                               6.5              7         
UA-ALB                            Negative                          Negative         NEG       
UA-UROBI                                                                             NEG       
UA-NIT                            Negative                          Negative         NEG       
UA-WBC                            see detail                        see detail       TRACE     
HCAST            Negative                          0-2                                         
UAS-RBC          0-2                               0-2                               0-2       
UAS-WBC          20-50                             5-10                              0-2       
UAS-BACT         Few                               Negative                                    
UAS-MUC                                                                              PRESENT   
UAS-SQHI         Few                               Negative                          FEW       
UAS-AMOR                                                                             FEW       


Cardiac:  Neg X 2


-       Trop T :               
-       CK-MB: 
-       CPK : 


EKG:
80, LVH, LA enlarg, new t-wave inversion in V5/V6 comapred to a wk ago. 


ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN:


59 yo female with hypertensive emergency, fatigue, and hypokalemia, no other symtomes. EKG with new wave inversion in lateral leads and negative cardiac enzymes. 




1-       Hypertensive Emergency : patient received 2 inch nitropaste on floor with no decrease in BP. 10mg IV hydralizine got her down to the 150s-160s. Goal is around 160-170. Will start Nicardipine PO 20mg TID and Labetolol 300mg PO and titrate up to BP goal.   to maintain goal 
2-       Hypkalemia/fatigue/hypertension: worried about secondary casues of HTN, namely hyperaldo state or liddel syndrom. Will check an 8am ambulating PAC to PRA ratio, will also check a spot urine to plasma K. Will check serum Metanephrine for pheo, and 24 hrs urine for cortisol, lytes, VMA, metanephrines to check for cushings and pheochromoctoma.  Will get a MRA to evaluate for renal artery stenosis. 
2-       Mood disorder: no active hallucination, will continue with Seroquel.
3-       DM: insulin sliding scale, QID finger sticks.
4-       UTI: urine with WBC, ? starting Bactrim DS X3 days. 
5-       Prophy:  Fragmin SC. 




Xavier Aaron Lowe M.D.  75059
Name,    Pager   #





]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2062-07-21" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P1" start="30" end="43" text="Halcyon House" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<NAME id="P2" start="78" end="95" text="Ostrander, Pamela" TYPE="PATIENT" comment="" />
<ID id="P3" start="103" end="110" text="1612187" TYPE="MEDICALRECORD" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="125" end="135" text="07/21/2062" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P5" start="142" end="149" text="Jameson" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<AGE id="P6" start="228" end="230" text="59" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P7" start="473" end="476" text="Jan" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P8" start="550" end="553" text="Jan" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P9" start="831" end="835" text="Peru" TYPE="COUNTRY" comment="" />
<LOCATION id="P10" start="1067" end="1070" text="HGH" TYPE="HOSPITAL" comment="" />
<AGE id="P11" start="5792" end="5794" text="59" TYPE="AGE" comment="" />
<NAME id="P12" start="6879" end="6896" text="Xavier Aaron Lowe" TYPE="DOCTOR" comment="" />
<CONTACT id="P13" start="6903" end="6908" text="75059" TYPE="PHONE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>