<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<deIdi2b2>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


Record date: 2067-03-13

History of Present Illness Pt. presents today for f/u of her overnight stay in the EDOU from 2/20 to 2/21/67.
 
She went by ambulance on 2/20 when she noted slurred speech and an unsteady gait.  She says it was like she was a drunk.  She hadn't been drinking and hadn't taken or eaten anything unusual.  She was very scared.  No visual changes or other unusual sensations.  She hadn't been sick in any other way:  no fevers, chills, N/V, or other complaints.
 
She felt a tiny bit better and was able to go to the door and let the EMTs in.  They checked her sugar:  63.  They gave her some sugar gel and her Sx resolved.
 
In the ER, her Sx did not reappear.  Labs were notable for BS of 140 then 255.  (A1C on 12/27/66 was 7.8.)  Her Na+ was low @ 124 &amp; 126, but this is stable for her.    She had a normal MRI/MRA.
 
Since then, she has felt her usual self.  Medications  Ambien Cr (ZOLPIDEM Tartrate Extended-release) 12.5 MG (12.5MG TAB MPHASE Take 1) PO QHS  #30 Tablet(s)Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD Avapro (IRBESARTAN) 300 MG (300MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD  #30 Tablet(s)GLYBURIDE 5 MG (5MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID x 30 days #60 Tablet(s)Labetalol Hcl 300 MG (300MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID x 30 days #180 Tablet(s)Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10 MG (10MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS x 30 days #90 Tablet(s)METFORMIN 850 MG (850MG TABLET Take 1) PO TID x 30 days #90 Tablet(s)Norvasc (AMLODIPINE) 10 MG (10MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID  #60 Tablet(s)PERPHENAZINE 4 MG (4 MG TABLET Take 1) PO as directed x 30 days, take 1 tablet (4 mg) QAM and 3 tablets (12 mg) QHS #120 Tablet(s)Proair Hfa (ALBUTEROL Inhaler Hfa) 2 PUFF (90MCG HFA AER AD ) INH Q6H PRN wheezing  #1 Inhaler(s)Seroquel (QUETIAPINE) 50 MG (50MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS x 30 days, may take 50 mg more at night as needed PRN persistent insomnia #45 Tablet(s)SIMVASTATIN 40 MG (40MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS  #30 Tablet(s)SPIRONOLACTONE 50 MG (50 MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD Tricor (FENOFIBRATE (TRICOR)) 48 MG PO QD  #30 Tablet(s)Unable to obtain this due to cost.Ultravate 0.05% (HALOBETASOL Propionate 0.05%) 1 APPLICATION (0.05% OINT.(GM) ) TOP as directed , APPLY TO AFFECTED AREAS TWICE DAILY X 15 DAYS AND THEN ON WEEKENDS ONLY. #50 Gram(s)Urea 35% Lotion 35% LOTION Take 1 TOP BID x 30 days, please apply it at plantar aspect of both feet twic a day #1 Tube(s)Allergies  LISINOPRIL  - Cough, HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE  - Hyponatremia, Review of Systems Positive and negative as listed elsewhere in this note.Vital Signs  BLOOD PRESSURE 120/70 PULSE 84 WEIGHT 224 lbExam NAD.
Neuro:  Gait, speech and strength are grossly intact.Results We reviewed her lab blood tests and her MRI/MRA.Problems  Diabetes mellitus type 2  I gave her another Rx for lancets.Hypertension  Elevated triglycerides  Needs generic for Tricor.  Mood Disorder, NOS  Hyponatremia  Anemia  Disposition and Plans Plans as above under each individual problem.  Also...
 
1)  Spell.  DDx includes hypoglycemia vs. TIA.  Still not completely clear which.  That said, she's doing well and that is reassuring.  She needs to check her sugars if she has another spell.  For now, we'll follow her closely.  
 
2)  HCM:  Deferred today.
 
Follow-up:  RTC as previously scheduled.



]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<DATE id="P0" start="16" end="26" text="2067-03-13" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P1" start="121" end="125" text="2/20" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P2" start="129" end="136" text="2/21/67" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P3" start="165" end="169" text="2/20" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
<DATE id="P4" start="739" end="747" text="12/27/66" TYPE="DATE" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</deIdi2b2>